Chapter 1
Nightmare

Benjamin tossed and turned in bed, unable to sleep. He went through all of the usual routines to prepare for a night of dreaming about dinosaurs. He counted the number of action figures in his room. One hundred and forty-seven. He studied the skeletons of his favorite dinosaur, the Tyrannosaurus rex. And, he even replayed his dreams from the previous five nights in his head. But, nothing happened.

He stood up from the bed and looked at it accusingly. There must be something wrong with it. Benjamin kicked the mattress on the side as he would kick his computer when it started to make peculiar noises. The bed did not move and the kick did not seem to fix his problem.

From his backpack, he retrieved an empty journal that Mr. Marchetta, his elementary school teacher, had given his class to record their dreams for one week. It was the same type of journal that he was given to record the foods he ate during a week, the birds he saw during a week, and the number of times Jupiter, Benjamin's golden retriever, jumped into the ground floor family swimming pool from the second floor balcony. Six times. Jupiter jumped six times. Benjamin was convinced that Mr. Marchetta had billions of these empty journals in his classroom closets.

He paced back and forth in his bedroom. He turned on his computer and set the volume low enough so that the noise would not wake his parents. He navigated the Internet until he found Jurassic Superheroes episodes, a popular television series in which a group of good dinosaurs destroy Professor Undutois' plans to destroy the world. Professor Undutois was the worst kind of villain, in Benjamin's mind, because he was smart and mean. That combination made Benjamin very uncomfortable. He liked a particular episode in which buildings fell down, dinosaurs tumbled everywhere, and cars exploded. Benjamin's mother hated it. Benjamin, however, loved it. He tapped play and watched the scenes unfold, wishing he could join the dinosaurs in their quest to stop evil.

The dinosaurs were flying in an airplane when they saw a newsflash that Professor Undutois was going to decimate a large metropolis by blasting it with a gigantic blue laser. One of the dinosaurs knew that it would take at least fifteen minutes until Professor Undutois could start his evil plan. They needed to land the plane immediately and find the terrible man's location before it was too late for all of the innocent people living in the millions of apartments clustered together like a concrete beehive.

Benjamin watched the dinosaurs ride their motorcycles between cars and trucks along a crowded highway, their eyes focused on an evil vehicle in the distance. Suddenly, the back door of the trailer opened and Professor Undutois began throwing rocks. They dodged left and right and Benjamin's heart, which normally began racing during this scene, stayed very, very steady. He had seen the dinosaurs destroy Professor Undutois' plans thousands of times and he knew their lines, strategies, and characters as well as he knew himself. As the dinosaurs steered closer to Professor Undutois, Benjamin's eyelids began to close and his memory took over.

The dinosaurs drove next to Professor Undutois' trailer. They forced the evil villain to brake suddenly and turn sharply off the highway into the European streets below. Benjamin and the dinosaurs chased after him, Benjamin leading the way on a green bicycle. He passed old coffee shops with women drinking espresso and dodged pedestrians carrying baguettes and swerved around taxis transporting people on these Parisian streets while keeping his eye on Professor Undutois in the distance. Benjamin knew exactly where his nemesis had stationed his laser; it was positioned at the top of the Eiffel Tower.

Benjamin stopped chasing Professor Undutois and instead started racing toward the large metal structure in the middle of Paris. The Eiffel Tower was only a quarter mile away as darkness suddenly overcame the city, sending Benjamin's heart into a fast pace. Professor Undutois was nearly at the destination and Benjamin thought, for a moment, that he would not be able to stop him from doing harm. As soon as he started to doubt himself, he realized that if he did not stop Professor Undutois, no one would. He took a deep breath and tried to find courage. As thunder and lightning overwhelmed Paris, Benjamin ran to the Eiffel Tower and began to ascend to the top.

But then, Professor Undutois came down from the Eiffel Tower and ran away as fast as he could, his arms flailing as he screamed loudly. Benjamin stood confused because his dreams never ended this way. Professor Undutois was never scared or worried. He was always confident and mean. He was running away from something, Benjamin realized.

When Benjamin looked to the top of the Eiffel Tower, he saw a gigantic figure that bellowed so loudly that Benjamin could feel the growl pulse through his tiny body. It was the scariest creature Benjamin had ever seen.

“Benjamin, it's time to wake up,” Mrs. Buckingham said as she opened Benjamin's door on her way downstairs to the kitchen.

Benjamin woke up and stared at his computer. He knew something was wrong with how he woke up. He pinched himself and rubbed his eyes over and over to make sure that he was indeed awake. He was but he didn't feel awake.

In all of the dreams he ever had, there was never an evil villain other than Professor Undutois. What could be more evil than Professor Undutois, Benjamin wondered. Is there something more evil out there?

“Benjamin!” Mrs. Buckingham yelled from the kitchen.

Benjamin ran downstairs and pondered what had just happened over French toast. Mr. Buckingham held the newspaper with a headline DREAMS HAVE ALL BUT DISAPPEARED IN PENNSYLVANIA. Benjamin saw it and wondered if he had lost the ability to dream. If last night foretold the future, Benjamin would never dream again. On his way to school, he continued to think about the monster. He wondered if there was something in one of the Jurassic Superheroes episodes that he was misremembering. He knew them completely, though, so it was just not possible.

“On Tuesday, I dreamed that I was at dinner with my parents when my brother spilled lasagna. It was going to fall on our dog but I saved her just in time,” one of Benjamin's classmates said in front of everyone. The classroom was sparsely decorated and dimly lit. Each of his classmates was reading from their dream journals and Benjamin was beginning to think that he might be teased if everyone knew that he had just awoken from a nightmare.

“Howard,” Mr. Marchetta read from a list on his desk. “You're next. Please read your dreams to the class.”

Howard Horne, a large child who behaved like a bully, walked to the front of the class with his journal, smirking at Benjamin along the way. He cleared his throat loudly. Benjamin rolled his eyes, wishing Howard would embarrass himself in front of everyone. Instead, Howard started to detail dreams that everyone in the class thought were exciting and thrilling.

“I was a gladiator Wednesday night and there was a dragon that had invaded our school,” Howard said as he clenched the journal with one hand and pointed to his classmates with the other. “The dragon was here to destroy us. It was going to destroy all of us. It blew fire everywhere and the school started to burn. This wasn't so bad but I was not going to let the dragon destroy our houses. And, the baseball field. I ran after it and then I destroyed the dragon using my gladiator shield and gladiator sword.”

The class applauded and Benjamin shrunk into his seat so that he did not draw attention to himself. He wanted to fit in. The last thing he wanted was to be different from everyone else. He could not dream like Howard.

“Benjamin, you're next,” Mr. Marchetta said as Howard Horne walked to his seat.

Benjamin gulped. His dreams were not nearly as courageous and none of the characters in his dreams were people who he knew in real life. They were his friends, he believed, but they were, indeed, dinosaurs.

“Benjamin, come on,” Mr. Marchetta said because Benjamin had not yet moved.

He walked to the front of the class with his journal in his left hand and a worried state in his mind. And just like when he was losing confidence that he might not be able to stop Professor Undutois, he took one big breath to stop his worries.

“The other day I dreamed that I was with a group of dinosaurs in Honolulu. The evil villain Professor Undutois was going to start a volcano that would destroy the entire island. I led the dinosaurs up the volcano and found Professor Undutois and his evil machine. I went up to him and said—”

“That's an episode!” Howard Horne yelled from the back of the class.

“Howard, quiet,” Mr. Marchetta interjected.

“That's not a dream!” Howard said with a laugh. “That's the tenth episode of Jurassic Superheroes and we're too old to be watching that anymore. Jurassic Superheroes is for little kids, Benjamin. You should go down the hall and tell it to the kindergarten students. But they probably won't be impressed because you can't even dream your own dreams! You steal from television shows!”

The entire class started to laugh as Benjamin's face turned red. It was an episode of that popular television series but it also happened to be his dream. He didn't know what to do next so he continued to stare into his journal in hope that time would move much faster than it was. He had lost any confidence that the deep breath had given him. And, he did not know how to get it back. All he knew was that he didn't want to be there.

“Benjamin, you can continue,” Mr. Marchetta said.

“I don't think I should,” Benjamin said nervously.

“OK,” Mr. Marchetta said. “But, that will mean you still have to complete your assignment. You can't disguise television episodes as your dreams. If you don't have a dream, just say that you didn't have a dream. Don't lie about it.”

“I didn't lie,” Benjamin said quietly.

“I bet I've already seen all of your dreams on television,” Howard said over the laughter of all the other kids in the classroom. “I bet I know the endings too!”

Benjamin stared out the window into the parking lot for the remainder of the day. He didn't know why school needed to be so difficult. Why was it so hard to make friends?

For dinner, Mr. Buckingham made waffles topped with fruit because it was his favorite meal and because he had decided that the family did not consume enough waffles. Benjamin did not have any complaints but he was distracted by everything he had gone through that day. He had dreamed a nightmare and then lived through one in the classroom.

“We had to read through our dream journal at school today,” Benjamin began, slowly.

“That's great,” Mrs. Buckingham responded as she set the table. “How did it go?”

“Not good.”

“Why not?” Mr. Buckingham said as he continued to make waffles.

“None of my dreams are creative. I'm not creative. My dreams aren't dreams.”

“Sure they are. You told me all about those dinosaur dreams,” his dad continued. “And, frankly, I don't know how anyone would think that they weren't creative. It takes a lot of creativity to imagine a stegosaurus navigating a sailboat.”

“Well, it's just that they aren't my dreams. They're all from Jurassic Superheroes.”

“Are you watching that episode I told you not to watch?” his mother asked as she handed him a napkin.

“No, but all my dreams star me and I go around with the dinosaurs stopping Professor Undutois.”

“Those are great dreams!” his dad continued while making more waffles.

“I think we have enough waffles,” Mrs. Buckingham whispered.

“Ten more?” he asked quickly. “Did you know that I haven't had a dream in months. I couldn't tell you the last dream I've had. I'd love to have a dream where I am parading around with dinosaurs solving crimes. I feel like most people these days can't dream. There was a time when everyone had dreams and now it's all gone. You should be thrilled to have dreams.”

“But, all the other kids in school have dreams that are much different than mine. I want my dreams to be like their dreams.”

“Different is good. You should be glad you're different. One day, you might regret that.”

“I'm thinking about throwing away the dinosaur posters in my room,” Benjamin said to his parents.

Mr. Buckingham put down the waffle maker and Mrs. Buckingham stopped setting the table. They were surprised with Benjamin. He had not thought about it for very long but he had decided that by getting rid of the dinosaurs in his room, he would begin to have different dreams.

“How about this,” Mr. Buckingham continued slowly. “You keep all the dinosaur stuff in your room for a month. If you don't have a creative dream in a month, we'll redesign your room to something else. Maybe sports? Cars?” Mr. Buckingham paused and looked at Mrs. Buckingham briefly. “Girls?”

Mrs. Buckingham rolled her eyes at Benjamin's dad.

“I think you've had a bad day,” she said. “But the great thing about having a bad day is that the next day is always better. ”

“Who wants some waffles?” Mr. Buckingham asked with four enormous plates of waffles topped with very little fruit.

The television was playing in the family room and an emergency alert appeared at the bottom of a news television show: IN THIS ECONOMY, WE CAN NO LONGER DREAM... Great, Benjamin thought. Nightmares are everywhere.

Chapter 2
Dinosaur

That night, Benjamin dreamed that he was meeting the dinosaurs at a castle to discuss Professor Undutois' plan to destroy another European capital by flooding it. Benjamin had to figure out where his evil nemesis was going to access enough water to execute the plan. He and the dinosaurs looked down from the old city's castle to the river below.

There just isn't enough water there to flood the entire city, Benjamin thought to himself. There was no ocean or lake nearby. If Professor Undutois was going to bring in a vast amount of water, Benjamin would be able to see it from the castle. He rubbed his brow as the stegosaurus, Tyrannosaurus rex, and brontosaurus waited to hear the plan. Benjamin was confused because he could not figure out where the water would come from.

And then, he had his answer. The sky was clear. It was crystal blue. But in the distance, there was an unusually lonely cloud floating in the direction of the city

“Professor Undutois is going to make it rain upon the old city until the city is underwater,” he proclaimed to the seated dinosaurs. “We have to find the machine he built to create rain and stop him before it's too late.”

“What does the machine look like?” the Tyrannosaurus rex asked.

“I'm not exactly sure,” Benjamin said. “But, it has to be large enough to produce big clouds. It had to be near that cloud over there.”

All of the dinosaurs looked in the direction Benjamin was pointing and agreed that his conclusion made perfect sense. They watched another cloud appear from the distance. Then, another. And, another. There was no doubt in Benjamin's mind that Professor Undutois was making rain clouds and that the evil nemesis would continue to do so until the city was underwater.

“Let's get him!” Benjamin shouted to his friends.

They raced through the old city, navigating the roads on bicycles so that they could dodge the trolleys quickly and safely. Benjamin's heart beat faster as he realized that this beautiful city could be lost if he didn't stop Professor Undutois. It was a lot of pressure, he thought, but he would do it with the assistance of his friends.

“I think we should go—” Benjamin started.

“I'm hungry,” the brontosaurus yelled back.

“You're what?”

“I'm hungry.”

“How can you be hungry now? Can't you wait until after we arrest Professor Undutois?”

“No, I'm pretty hungry,” the brontosaurus named Gary added. “I think I need to eat or I'm not going to be able to help.”

“Is anyone else hungry like Gary?” Benjamin asked his friends while standing in the middle of Wenceslas Square. He couldn't believe this. He needed the dinosaurs to help him and all they were concerned about was eating more food.

“I could use a nap,” the Tyrannosaurus rex named Snark said.

“A nap!” Benjamin shouted.

“Well, we've been going pretty fast for quite some time. I'm kind of tired.”

“But we don't have time!”

“It won't be a long nap.”

“How long will it be?”

“Twenty minutes?”

“Twenty minutes!”

“If I start now, I think it could be fifteen.”

Gary came back with a gigantic salad and began eating it on a park bench.

“OK, Snark. Get some sleep,” Benjamin said. “Gerald and I will find a way to get to Professor Undutois so that we don't lose much time.”

“Actually, I kind of have to...” Gerald the stegosaurus paused.

“You have to what?”

“Use the restroom,” Gerald whispered into Benjamin's ear.

“Fine!” Benjamin said as he flung his hands to his side. He gave up. “Go use the bathroom.”

Gerald stumbled away from the group, Snark slept on the ground, and Gary ate on the park bench. Benjamin was sure that he was losing valuable time that should have been spent stopping the terrible man. He turned his head to the sky and noticed that there were more than ten clouds in the sky. It was only a matter of time before the sky was covered with them.

“I don't think I can wait much longer,” Benjamin said to Gary. “I need to go stop Professor Undutois.”

“I'll only be a few more minutes,” Gary said as he chewed on some carrots. “But, I kind of have to use the bathroom as well.”

“I'm going to go,” Benjamin decided as he gained more confidence. “When Snark wakes up and Gerald returns, find me where Professor Undutois is creating the clouds.”

“Sounds good, Ben,” Gary replied while eating broccoli.

Benjamin did not like the idea of abandoning his friends but he also did not like the idea of Professor Undutois flooding the old city. He thought that he would find the villain and when the dinosaurs were ready, they would help him then.

More clouds gathered in the sky, and then Benjamin felt a raindrop. It was the first raindrop he felt. Then, he felt another. And then, another. Professor Undutois launched his plan and Benjamin needed to stop him. If the rain continued at this pace, there could be a flood very soon.

Benjamin found an abandoned bicycle and rode it to the cloud machine. He saw the machine on the top of a small apartment building. But, he could not see Professor Undutois.

Clouds scattered across the sky and the rain began to pour more violently. Benjamin climbed a ladder on the side of the apartment building, careful not to slip on the metal steps. When he reached the rooftop, he saw the machine. But, he also saw that the buttons to control it were missing. Professor Undutois had them, he thought to himself.

“You'll never stop me this time, Benjamin,” Professor Undutois yelled from the rooftop across the street.

“Give me the controls,” Benjamin said sternly.

“In your dreams,” Professor Undutois said.

Benjamin did not believe he could turn off the machine without obtaining the controls that Professor Undutois held. As the rain started to pour more violently, he climbed back down the apartment building and raced across the street. He was about to ascend the staircase when he saw Professor Undutois descending, heading right for Benjamin. Benjamin took a step backwards and prepared himself to tackle the evil villain as soon as he was within reach. This would be Benjamin's most successful victory yet.

Oddly, though, Professor Undutois was screaming. He was screaming so loudly that Benjamin realized the villain was not running toward Benjamin but away from something. Professor Undutois landed on the ground, threw the controls for the cloud machine at Benjamin, and then ran down the street with his arms above his head, panicking more and more.

Benjamin looked in the direction from which Professor Undutois came and saw the top of the staircase was beginning to shake. There was no time to lose, though, because Benjamin needed to stop the clouds. He looked at the controls that Professor Undutois had thrown at him and decided that it would be simple enough to stop the rain. Benjamin lowered his index finger onto the off button when bricks started to fall from the side of the apartment building. Benjamin looked to the roof and saw the most gigantic face of a monster he had ever seen.

It was the same monster.

It screamed at Benjamin more loudly than any noise Benjamin had ever heard previously.

It had teeth like enormous swords.

It emanated fire from its body as if it was a moving volcano.

And, it moved slowly towards Benjamin.

Benjamin did not know what to do in this situation because he had never encountered such a thing before. If he turned off the rain, he thought, the episode would be over and he will have won. His finger clicked the off button on the controls and the clouds stopped appearing and the rain stopped falling and the old city stopped being flooded. But, the monster kept moving toward Benjamin.

It jumped to the street, destroying the cars and trucks that it landed upon. Benjamin realized that this monster was after him. And, Benjamin could not hide his fear. His legs shook. His arms felt numb. His muscles felt immobile. His face felt weak.

And then, he felt a painful thud in the side of his body. He looked to the ground and realized that he was moving, but his legs were still and his body was still. Snark had grabbed him and ran faster than Benjamin had ever seen him run before. The monster gave chase and Snark sprinted more quickly down deserted streets heading for a section of the city that Benjamin had not seen before.

Benjamin panicked and did not enjoy the dream anymore. He felt in danger and he felt that his friends, the dinosaurs, recognized that there was indeed something wrong. Benjamin wanted to leave, so he did.

He woke up.

He rubbed his eyes and stretched his arms and remarked how his heart was racing a little bit more than he was comfortable with.

“It's over,” he thought to himself, disappointed that he did have a successful dream and curious as to why that monster appeared again.

Benjamin threw his legs over the side of the bed and although he was still waking up, he realized that something was not quite right. Whenever he looked to his wall, his eyes were in line with the poster of a stegosaurus. But now, his eyes were well above the poster. In fact, his head was only a foot away from the ceiling. Benjamin looked down and realized that he was almost six feet above the ground. And if he was six feet above the ground, there was something holding his bed six feet in the air.

He jumped to the floor, looked under his bed and screamed. There was a dinosaur that looked exactly like Snark. The dinosaur looked at Benjamin and screamed in return.

Benjamin screamed.

Snark screamed.

Benjamin panicked.

Snark panicked.

Benjamin tried to run away.

Snark tried to run away.

Benjamin wanted to exit the room but Snark was standing in the path to the door. As Benjamin moved to one side, Snark moved to that same side in an awkward dance of two very scared creatures. And then, Snark grabbed Benjamin's shoulders.

The only thought that passed through Benjamin's mind was that he was going to be eaten at that moment. It was inevitable. Snark was probably hungry and Benjamin was food. But if I'm going to be eaten, Benjamin thought, I'm going to run away and hide. And since he couldn't move, he fought the only way he knew how to fight. He yelled as loudly as he could.

“Oh, no! Quiet! Please be quiet!” Snark replied as he dropped Benjamin.

The voice sounded a lot less menacing than Benjamin had expected. It sounded like it belonged to a man older than Benjamin but not as old as his dad. It sounded as if it was from someone who was not a kid but not yet an adult. Benjamin stepped backward slowly to the door so that he could escape.

“I'm going to get in so much trouble for this!” Snark said as he sat heavily upon Benjamin's chest of dinosaur toys, denting the lid quite significantly. Snark waved one of his claws against his face to brush away some dust in his eye. “Come on, Rodney. Pull yourself together. You can do this.” Snark took a deep, long breath. “You can do this!”

“Rodney?” Benjamin asked with curiosity.

Snark turned quickly to Benjamin.

“Listen, Benjamin,” Snark said. “You need to go about your day and when you come back to your room tonight, I'll be gone. Actually, it would be really, really great if you didn't tell anyone that I'm here. Can you do that for me? I mean, I'm really, really trying hard to keep this job and I'm really, really close to losing it. I need you to do a big favor for me and not tell anyone that I was here. Otherwise, I'll lose my job. Is that OK?”

“What's your job?”

“Oh, I keep talking and I get myself into more trouble,” Snark continued as he shook his head. “I can't tell you that, Benjamin. I've said too much. You just have to promise me that you're not going to tell anyone that I'm here.”

“That's kind of hard,” Benjamin responded. “You've destroyed my room and you're making so much noise.”

Snark and Benjamin looked at the room which appeared to have been torn apart by a tornado, the posters and toys strewn across the floor. The bed was almost unusable and there was clothing everywhere. The lamps were knocked over and there were gigantic Tyrannosaurus rex footprints throughout, including the ceiling.

“Benjamin!” Mrs. Buckingham yelled up the stairs. “Stop jumping around up there and come down for breakfast!”

“You need to clean this up,” Benjamin said to Snark.

“I can't clean it up,” the dinosaur responded to Benjamin.

“You made this mess! You clean it up.”

“But, I can't.”

“Why not?”

“I've got these tiny arms. It'll take me weeks to clean up and I need to get back to work.”

“Work? What do you do?”

“I told you I can't tell you.”

“So, you're an accountant too, like my dad?”

“Benjamin, I'm sorry I destroyed your room but I have to go and I need you not to tell anyone that I was here.”

“Fine,” Benjamin said with a little anger at the state of his space. “But, you're going to have to go out through the window.”

“The window!” Snark yelled with surprise.

“If my mom sees a dinosaur was in my room, I'm going to be in even bigger trouble.”

“I'm not going out the window!”

“Why not? Is it the arms again?”

“No, that's not how I can leave.”

“How are you going to leave?”

“I can't tell you.”

“You've destroyed my room and now you're going to run around my home. Do you know what the kids at school are going to say about me when they find out a dinosaur came from my room?”

“I know, I know. I'm going to leave quickly but I can't let you know how I'm going to leave. You just need to step into the hallway for one minute.”

“If you steal any of my toys,” Benjamin began.

“I'm not going to steal any of your toys!”

“Or the posters!”

“I'm not going to steal any of your posters! Just, please, Benjamin, I'm going to get into so much trouble. I'm really late. I need to go!”

“Fine,” Benjamin said as he gave one last frustrated look to Snark. He stepped into the hallway and closed the door, but only until there was a tiny sliver through which he could see what Snark was going to do next.

Benjamin watched Snark walk back and forth with his claws on his head, obviously worried about the state of things. He kept looking at his wrist, upon which Benjamin realized was a watch. He had not noticed it earlier. Maybe Snark really was late for something, Benjamin thought. Curiosity was overwhelming him and he wanted to know where Snark was going next. Dinosaurs did not just walk around the neighborhood.

Snark took one more glance at his watch and rubbed his claws together. He grabbed the side of the bed and stood it up on its side. Benjamin couldn't believe what he was watching. Snark was making more of a mess of his room even after promising that he wouldn't. It would take him months to restore it to a state his mother would find acceptable, Benjamin thought.

And then, a bright light appeared on the floor that had been previously hidden by the bed. It became larger and larger and brighter and brighter. Snark shielded his eyes and Benjamin did the same. And then, Snark jumped into the light in the ground as if it was a swimming pool and disappeared.

Benjamin's mind was overwhelmed with thoughts. Where was Snark going? How long had there been this light under his bed? Where did it go? Who was going to clean up this mess? How mad will his mother be?

He opened the door to his room and stepped to the light, looking at it without falling into it. He couldn't see anything beyond brightness. And then, the circular light started to get smaller and smaller.

More thoughts entered Benjamin's mind as he realized that a door to something was closing. He did not know what was on the other side of the door but he did know that there was a dinosaur that was late for something. And, that dinosaur knew Benjamin's name. And, that dinosaur saved his life. He struggled with what he should do next.

“Benjamin, time for school!” Mrs. Buckingham yelled to him.

“School!” Benjamin echoed to himself.

But, I don't want to go to school today, he thought to himself.

And so, he jumped.

Chapter 3
Lost Child

Benjamin couldn't see anything. He didn't know what was ahead of him, what was behind him, what was beside him, or what was above him. There was darkness everywhere.

He didn't want to move, in case one step to his left led him to a five thousand foot fall off a mountain with rocks and trees and other sharp things. If he took one step forward, he might step onto some old wooden platform that could give way to him falling six thousand feet into an ancient gold mining shaft. If he took one step backwards, he might get his foot tangled into a rope that had been placed to catch large animals like dinosaurs and suddenly he would be pulled seven thousand feet into the air, dangling from some magnificent tree. He leaned a little to the left and then decided that taking a step to the left would be just as bad. If he took a step to the left, as opposed to the right, he might step into the opening of a gigantic volcano eight thousand feet tall, his tiny body flailing and falling into the erupting lava below.

He worried that if he jumped, the land on which he currently stood might suddenly disappear. Benjamin realized that he was worrying too much. He was losing control of his thoughts, as everything he imagined was bad. Benjamin sat on the ground and wished that his mind would wander into the many glorious things that might await him when the darkness faded. But, he couldn't. He didn't like being alone in darkness, he thought.

And then, something touched him. He felt it fly by his back as quickly as a bat or bird. If it was just a bird, that would be fine because Benjamin had seen many birds before. But if it was a bat, Benjamin would be more concerned. He had never seen one before. He would rather see something he knew than something he didn't know.

It touched him again. This time, he felt the creature across his left shoulder. Benjamin cowered down lower to the ground.

And then, it touched him twice, this time on both the left and right shoulders. Benjamin kept still and hoped that he could be invisible in the darkness.

At that point, it continued. More and more, Benjamin felt the annoying bird-bat thing hitting him. Whatever it was could see in the dark, he thought.

Benjamin began to flail his arms in front of him to ward off the flying thing.

“Away! Away, demon bird!” Benjamin yelled at whatever it was that was bothering him.

But then, Benjamin could see in the dark, too. At a distance of about thirty feet away, a tiny candle suddenly lit to reveal that there was no volcano, mountain, mineshaft, or dinosaur traps around him. There was only flat, safe ground so Benjamin jumped to his feet and ran to the light. He examined it and saw that it was on top of a wooden pole.

Without thinking about who turned the light on, he grabbed the torch and slowly illuminated everything around him.

“Ugh. Shadows!” Benjamin said with far less excitement.

Shadows of various sizes were moving at high speeds all around him. They looked like creatures with two, three, four, eight, and eleven limbs.

“Monsters!” Benjamin yelled.

As if it heard him, another light flickered on to his left. Benjamin ran to it and noticed that it, too, was on a wooden stake. He did not see anyone or anything around that could have turned it on. He only saw more shadows.

“Go away, dinosaurs! Snark, help me!” Benjamin yelled.

Dozens of candles suddenly flickered on, as if Snark was listening to his request for help. They revealed a path through the darkness. Without concern for the shadows and bird-bats, Benjamin ran through the path as fast as he could. He passed nearly fifteen candles when the dark environment changed completely. Everywhere, without warning, was light. And for the first time, Benjamin saw where he was.

He was standing at the entrance to a large stadium with tens of thousands of people in the stands cheering and screaming. The audience surrounded a circular ground covered with sandy dirt that felt hot under the blue sky and unforgiving sun. In the middle of this arena stood a gladiator, with a shield the size of his body and a sword twice as long. He pounded the sword into his shield and screamed back at the crowd. The crowd screamed back at the gladiator.

“Today!” the gladiator beckoned. “We will no longer be afraid!”

Benjamin was immediately afraid. The candles that he followed fell to the ground. He was standing in the middle of the gladiator's arena.

The audience of thousands jumped as the gladiator gestured every direction, including a momentary glance directly at Benjamin. Benjamin slowly walked backwards and hid behind a door from which he could observe without being seen.

The gladiator ran around the arena waving a blue, yellow, and orange flag three stories high. The crowd loved every moment of it. Many threw flowers upon the ground. Many waved signs with pictures of the gladiator on them. Others whistled loudly.

As the gladiator returned to the center of the stadium, thunder broke out in the distance. The gladiator looked in the direction of the noise and raised both his shield and sword into the air. The crowd erupted in excitement for reasons Benjamin did not understand.

Thunder clapped again, closer to the arena. The gladiator yelled back and the audience erupted again.

Thunder clapped once more and Benjamin realized it was not thunder at all. It was a monstrous, skinny red dragon breathing fire into the bright blue sky. When it landed on the ground, everything shook like it would during an earthquake.

The heroic gladiator grabbed the dragon by its tail and swung it around and around. He ran to the beast's head and wrapped the dragon's jaw with thick rope, preventing it from doing any harm to anyone. The audience loved every moment of it.

“This is our land!” the gladiator yelled as he directed the dragon to fly away.

Benjamin's eyes were wide and his jaw was low. He did not know where he was but if there were dinosaurs, gladiators, and dragons, he decided that he made the correct decision to skip school that day.

As he leaned forward to try to get a better view of the gladiator flying the dragon around the arena, something brushed his shoulders again. But this time, Benjamin was pulled backwards by something he couldn't see.

Chapter 4
King

“Welcome!” a grandfatherly man with a friendly smile and gentle eyes yelled to Benjamin in a large stately room. “My name is King Bernard Zwirn! You had a very close call there! Who are you? Where are you from? I'm so glad you started walking toward those candles. That gladiator would've squashed you. Or even worse, you would have been eaten by that dragon!”

King Bernard Zwirn held his heavy belly and let out a loud, echoing chuckle. It was such a warm, full laugh that it made Benjamin smile. Benjamin felt relaxed in front of this gentle, grandfatherly man.

“My name is Benjamin Buckingham. Where am I?” Benjamin asked.

“You, Benjamin, are in Castle Ehtahl and I am King Bernard Zwirn.”

The king stretched his arms as wide as he could. Everything around him looked beautiful and grand. There were stately statues and ornate paintings and healthy plants throughout this castle's hall.

“You are the first visitor we've ever had from the outside,” King Bernard Zwirn continued.

“Outside?” Benjamin asked.

“Yes! No one from where you're from has ever been here. We take great pride in our secrecy and our secret location. It's a wonder you found us at all. But now that you're here, I'd like to offer you a key to the castle.”

King Bernard Zwirn turned from Benjamin and ran down the hall like a rhinoceros running through a gorgeous, pristine setting. The pictures shook, the candles bounced, and the windows rattled. King Bernard Zwirn rummaged through dozens of chests at the end of the hall, throwing clothes and boxes and other ancient artifacts behind him as he desperately searched for the key.

“It's in here somewhere!” he yelled to Benjamin as he turned a large trunk upside down and sorted through its contents.

Benjamin knew his mother would not be happy with the manner in which King Bernard Zwirn was searching. The previously beautiful grand hall was becoming a messy large room. There were things everywhere and it would take several days to put everything back together.

“Here,” King Bernard Zwirn said as he passed a small box to Benjamin. “You have a key to my castle.”

The tiny silver box with a gold ribbon looked as extraordinary as anything else around him. Benjamin unwrapped it quickly, tossing the paper to the ground, and opened the lid.

“It's a grasshopper!” Benjamin said.

“A what?”

“A grasshopper.”

“Oh no, Benjamin,” King Bernard Zwirn chuckled again. “Grasshoppers are little insects. Keys open doors and they certainly aren't alive. They're quite different things, keys and grasshoppers!”

“No, look, King Zwirn. It's a grasshopper,” Benjamin said as he offered the box back to King Bernard Zwirn.

King Bernard Zwirn looked inside and saw that there was indeed a grasshopper living in the box.

“The grasshopper ate the key!” King Bernard Zwirn yelled accusingly.

“I don't think a grasshopper can eat at key,” Benjamin responded.

“There was a key in here and now there is a grasshopper. That can only mean that the grasshopper ate the key,” King Bernard Zwirn said as he scolded the grasshopper. “There can be no other explanation!”

“Was the key smaller than the grasshopper?” Benjamin asked.

“It was a huge key. It was much larger than this grasshopper.”

“Then, there's no way the grasshopper can eat the key.”

“How do you know so much about grasshoppers?”

“We have a lot of them in my backyard.”

“You have grasshoppers in Ehtsetra?”

“Ehtsetra?” Benjamin asked with a puzzled face.

King Bernard Zwirn looked at the grasshopper and then leaned in to Benjamin, his face contorted in confusion. He looked around the room quickly, as if he was unsure if anyone was watching him.

“Benjamin, you are a visitor to this castle?”

“I am a visitor.”

“From Ehtsetra?”

“No.”

“No?”

“No.”

“And if you are not from Ehtsetra, where may I ask are you from?”

“Pennsylvania.”

“I see,” King Bernard Zwirn said very, very slowly. He stepped away with incredibly long, drawn out strides. Benjamin could sense that the grasshopper was nervous because it had stopped gnawing on the side of the box. King Bernard Zwirn looked at Benjamin from the corner of his eye and continued to move further and further away. “If you'll excuse me, I have to—.”

And with that, King Bernard Zwirn sprinted away with his arms waving over his head, his feet slipping on the blue carpet. Benjamin never heard an adult scream as loudly as King Bernard Zwirn did. The faces in the paintings appeared to squirm with discomfort over the dreadful noise.

Benjamin sighed. If he was not being nice, he would expect people to run away from him screaming. But given the circumstances, Benjamin did not understand what he was doing wrong. What was so wrong about being from Pennsylvania? And, where was Ehtsetra?

If he doesn't want to be friends with me, he thought to himself, I'll just explore on my own.

There were more paintings of people on the walls than Benjamin could count. There was Sir Laborious Maximus who looked like an Italian painter with an absurdly long mustache. There was Queen Jebra Coolihan whose head was four times larger than the rest of her body. There was a dog named Woolfred Woofery who looked braver than all of the other people in the paintings. And then there was a tiny plaque for Aloysius Trenhaile but there was no painting. Instead, the words we don't talk about it were inscribed in the wall above his name. Benjamin found this intriguing but did not have more time to think about it because King Bernard Zwirn reappeared.

A security guard who was as short as he was wide arrived with King Bernard Zwirn. He looked like a cube with tiny little feet and short red hair.

“Noel, get the monster!”

King Bernard Zwirn yelled. Benjamin realized that the king was referring to him, that he was the monster.

Noel charged at Benjamin as if he was designed for this specific task. Benjamin did not move because he was not a monster and he also did not see Noel as a threat. The square man stood only three feet tall. But that did not deter King Bernard Zwirn's chants of encouragement. The king was convinced that Benjamin was a monster.

“I am not a monster,” Benjamin yelled back.

“That's something a monster would say!” Noel said as he leaped into the air and dove headfirst at Benjamin. Benjamin took one step to his left and Noel hit the carpet like a dice being tossed across the ground.

“We do not welcome your kind here,” King Bernard Zwirn said.

“My kind?” Benjamin asked with confusion.

“Yes, dream makers do not interact with nightmares!” Noel screamed as he dove at Benjamin again, and hit the ground like a square bowling ball bouncing across the floor.

“I'm not a monster or a nightmare!” Benjamin responded. He was agitated because the king would not believe him.

“That's exactly what a nightmare would say,” King Bernard Zwirn said in response. “Come on, Noel. Get him this time. Really concentrate hard. Give it your all.”

“He keeps moving,” Noel said as he gasped for air.

“Then wait until he stops moving,” King Bernard Zwirn said to Noel.

“But what if he moves again?”

“Then, wait some more.”

“I can hear you,” Benjamin said from the opposite side of the room with his hands on his hips.

“Don't listen to us, monster,” King Bernard Zwirn replied.

Benjamin thought hard about how he could escape this situation. If he ran away, he did not know where he would go. He could not confess to being a monster because Noel would inevitably try to hurt him. He decided that the only way to remedy this predicament would be to convince these two men that he was not a monster.

“What do monsters do?” Benjamin asked.

“Monsters cause nightmares. They terrorize people. You should know,” Noel said. “You are a monster!”

“But, you're terrorizing me,” Benjamin replied. “So, you two must be the monsters.”

King Bernard Zwirn stood tall and shifted his head slightly as he looked upon the young child.

“We aren't the monsters,” King Bernard Zwirn said. “We aren't terrorizing you.”

“You are most definitely terrorizing me.”

“You are terrorizing us.”

“I was not! I was admiring these paintings and then that block monster tried to tackle me.”

“That block's name is Noel Jaffin,” Noel responded.

“If monsters are creatures that terrorize other creatures, you are the monsters. I am not,” Benjamin said.

Benjamin watched King Bernard Zwirn's expression change from cold and angry to warm and gentle. He began to breath more easily as he realized that he may have somehow convinced them.

“Tell me, Benjamin,” King Bernard Zwirn said with his hands on his hips. “Where is this Pennsylvania you speak of?”

Chapter 5
Automatons

Benjamin followed King Bernard Zwirn and Noel Jaffin through the ancient castle. He admired the green floor and yellow walls of a new hallway lined with windows on his left and plants on his right. He smelled flowers that reminded him of chocolates his parents would buy him in the spring.

“So, where is Ehtsetra?” Benjamin asked.

“We don't know exactly where they are located. And, we like it that way,” King Bernard Zwirn said with a smile.

“Don't you like them?”

“Oh, no. We really like people from Ehtsetra. We like them a lot. But it's for our mutual protection that we don't know where the other is.”

“Protection?”

“Benjamin,” King Bernard Zwirn said as they walked through another door to a hallway with white ceilings and blue walls with fish tanks on his left and stained glass windows on his right. The tropical fish swam throughout the enormous fish tank as if they were attempting to mirror the colorful glass display on their opposite side. “I need you to answer some questions from my advisors so that we can figure out how we can get you back to Pennsylvania.”

“But, who do you need to be protected from? What is Ehtsetra scared of?”

“Don't worry, Benjamin. You won't ever have to worry about this. You don't want to. I'll get you home before you know it.”

Benjamin walked slowly because he was incredibly curious about what threatened King Bernard Zwirn. And, he didn't want to go back to Pennsylvania. Not now, at least. He did not want to leave without knowing where Snark went. There was more to see here than there was at school, he thought.

“Benjamin?” King Bernard Zwirn said when he realized that Benjamin was not moving forward.

As Benjamin looked at more of the paintings on the wall, he remembered one of the paintings that he saw earlier.

“Why did it say we don't talk about it above Aloysius Trenhaile's name?” Benjamin asked.

“Oh, that's an easy question,” King Bernard Zwirn answered. “Because we do not talk about it.”

“But who is Aloysius?”

“We don't talk about it.”

“At all?”

“At all.”

“Does he live here?”

“We don't talk about it.”

“And people don't like him?”

“We don't talk about it.”

“Or he did something really bad?”

“We don't talk about it.”

“I have to find someone who can talk about it so that I know why we don't talk about it.”

King Bernard Zwirn stopped walking. He closed his eyes just like Benjamin's mother did when Benjamin misbehaved. Noel Jaffin did not make eye contact with King Bernard Zwirn and Benjamin sensed that the stocky man was uncomfortable.

“Benjamin, we do not talk about it!” King Bernard Zwirn snapped. “You cannot talk about something we do not talk about!”

They proceeded to walk forward and Benjamin did not ask any more questions. And although he was even more curious about Aloysius Trenhaile, he did not want to disobey King Bernard Zwirn. Living with curiosity was better than being hated, Benjamin decided. And, he liked King Bernard Zwirn.

As yet another door opened to yet another colorful room, a bright light blinded Benjamin. The circular room looked like the inside of a round monument, the walls made of marble and the ceiling holding a mural with clouds that appeared to move. It was not a large room and Benjamin felt that Noel Jaffin was occupying an unfair amount of it because of his size. There was one more unusual and unique feature. He was surrounded by twelve automatons, machines that looked like people seated at desks as if they were in a meeting.

“The elders of Castle Ehtahl would like to ask you a few questions, Benjamin,” King Bernard Zwirn said as he walked to a cabinet hanging on the wall.

“Are these machines?”

“Benjamin! There are our elders! Don't insult them in front of them. Wait until you leave if you want to insult them.”

“But, they aren't human.”

“No, they're not. They are automatons.”

“The elders of your castle are automatons?”

“No. The elders of my castle are lazy. They've been replaced by automatons because they got bored of asking the same questions over and over.”

King Bernard Zwirn placed a quarter into a slot in the cabinet and then pulled a gigantic lever from the cabinet to the floor. As he did so, sparks burst from each of the automatons and they all made rickety noises as their tin and copper pieces shifted back and forth. They did not look graceful or smooth because their movements were quite jerky and their exteriors rusty in several spots. Some of the automatons did not have complete control over their movements causing their arms, lips, or legs to move in a peculiar ballet of metal and electricity.

“What is your name?” one of the automatons asked in a metallic, crisp voice.

Benjamin turned to face the automaton that had a pen in its crooked fingers.

“Benjamin Buckingham,” Benjamin responded.

“What is your identification number?” another automaton asked from a different direction.

“Override! Outsider questions,” King Bernard Zwirn said quickly. He gave Benjamin a nod of approval because Benjamin obviously did not have an identification number. The automatons shifted back and forth and jerked their limbs in various movements that together looked like they were synchronized.

“Where are you from?” another automaton asked.

“Pennsylvania.”

“Where is Penn Syl Vannia?” another automaton asked with mispronunciation.

“In the United States?”

“OK. We found Pennsylvania,” another automaton answered. “Is your address 18104 Huckleberry Road?”

“Yes,” Benjamin said with surprise. “How did you...”

“Are you nine years old?”

“Yes,” Benjamin replied with even more surprise.

“What is your relationship with evil?” another automaton asked.

“Evil?”

“Yes, evil.”

“I don't know. I'm not evil. Who is evil?”

“We don't talk about it,” yet another automaton commented. “And how did you get here?”

“King Bernard Zwirn took me here,” Benjamin responded.

“Pause!” King Bernard Zwirn said as he raised the lever from the ground to the cabinet, powering down all of the automatons in the process. “We want to know how you came to Ehtahl? How did you wind up in the castle in the first place?”

“Oh, that's easy—”

“Wait for the automatons to return,” King Bernard Zwirn said as he powered the automatons to the jingle and jangle and clanking of metal parts.

Benjamin relayed the story of how he got to where he was today. He mentioned running through an old city in his dream, waking up to find a dinosaur under his bed, following the dinosaur into an unknown land, and seeing a gladiator battle. If machines could look as surprised as King Bernard Zwirn and Noel Jaffin did, these automatons were as shocked by this outcome as anyone else. Benjamin took a deep breath after he finished.

“Why are you really here?” an automaton asked.

“I wanted to see where the dinosaur was going,” Benjamin said quietly.

“Dinosaur?” King Bernard Zwirn asked.

“Yes. The Tyrannosaurus rex from my dream.”

King Bernard Zwirn groaned through his teeth and rolled his eyes.

“Oh, Rodney.”

“Rodney! He kept saying that name.”

“Yes, Rodney Cohen,” King Bernard Zwirn said while shaking his head. “That guy gets us in so much trouble we're not going to be able to do what we do much longer.”

“What do you do?”

“I'll tell you all about it as we leave.”

“Leave?”

“Yes, Benjamin, we need to get you home.”

“But, I don't want to go.”

“It's not really your choice,” King Bernard Zwirn said. “Elders, when can Benjamin go back to Pennsylvania?”

The automatons moved back and forth in a more rigid, uncontrolled fashion. They jerked from side to side and steam started pouring from their heads, sending a screeching sound into the air. Joints started to disconnect and pieces of robots starts to fall all over the ground.

One automaton leaned forward and moved its jaw slowly.

“The departure gateway closes in ten minutes at the train station. The next time the departure gateway opens is in one month.”

“Ten minutes!” King Bernard Zwirn exclaimed. “Benjamin, we have to go!”

“But where am I? What's threatening Castle Ehtahl?”

“We have to run!”

Chapter 6
Leaving

Benjamin and King Bernard Zwirn sprinted down one hallway, then another, and then another until Benjamin lost a sense of which direction he was going. Everything felt disorienting and confusing. The more he saw of this castle, the less he understood it.

“We've got nine minutes to get you to the train station,” King Bernard Zwirn said in between breaths. “The elders said the next time the departure gateway opens is in a couple months. If you don't get through that portal, I don't know what we're going to do with you here.”

“I could keep to myself. I'll just look around and see where all the dinosaurs live.”

“Benjamin, you won't be able to live here because this place is much different than where you're from. This is, how should I say, a little bit like a magical manufacturing city.”

“A magical manufacturing city?”

“Yes, we make something here.”

“Like bikes?”

“Kind of like bikes,” King Bernard Zwirn said as he opened a door to the outside world. “It's a little bit more complicated than that.”

“What do you make?”

“Oh, my,” King Bernard Zwirn said as he glanced at his watch. “We're going to be late. We've got seven minutes.”

Benjamin thought about stopping, so that King Bernard Zwirn had no choice but to let him live in Castle Ehtahl for a while. He knew King Bernard Zwirn would not be able to pull him to the train station. He was a large man but he looked like he had the strength of someone a quarter the size.

“I'll sprint to the train station,” Benjamin said. “I'm a lot faster than you but in exchange, you have to tell me what you make here.”

“Deal!” King Bernard Zwirn said quickly, his brow covered in sweat and his chest heaving back and forth like rough waves in the ocean. “We make dreams.”

“You make dreams?”

“Yes, we make dreams.”

“What do you mean you make dreams?”

King Bernard Zwirn removed a necklace and gave it to Benjamin. On the end, there was a small brass key that looked like it was much older than the king who wore it.

“You have to use this key to get into the train station. You go straight towards that gigantic tower, then make a left and run along the river to a series of blue, yellow, and green buildings. The yellow building is the entrance to the train station and you'll need this key to get inside. On the last platform, you'll see the departure gateway that will send you home.”

“But, I don't understand what you mean—” Benjamin began.

“You have five minutes to run straight for that gigantic tower, then make a left and run along—” King Bernard Zwirn began repeating the directions again.

“No, sorry,” Benjamin replied. “What do you mean you make dreams?”

“We make dreams.”

“You make dreams come true?”

“No, this isn't Hollywood, Benjamin. We make real dreams. When you go to sleep at night and you have a dream, those dreams are manufactured here.”

“Here?”

“Yes, here. And if you stay here, your presence will throw off the balance of peace and we're not going to be able to produce dreams for very much longer.”

“I don't understand. Peace? Who is threatening to hurt you?”

“I don't expect you to know any of this,” King Bernard Zwirn said as he grabbed Benjamin by the shoulders. “You have to leave because if you don't, this castle and the dreams it creates might be destroyed by nightmares. You have to run. The less you know, the better. If you want to have dreams of dinosaurs again, you need to sprint as fast as you can.”

Benjamin wanted to dream of dinosaurs again and immediately turned from King Bernard Zwirn and ran as fast as he could. Run for the gigantic tower, Benjamin thought to himself. It was impossible to miss the tower. As he got closer and closer to it, he noticed it had far more moving parts than he imagined. Each individual piece seemed to move independent of all of the other parts, as if it was the most complex watch ever created. He wanted to inspect the tower further but he also wanted to have more dreams so he ran through crowds to the bank of the river. As he turned left towards the yellow building, he slipped on the ground and the brass key fell from his grasp. Benjamin got to his knees and crawled five feet to it. He reached for the brass key and extended his fingers. But then, a heavy leather boot with rusty metal lining stepped on it. Benjamin tried to push the boot away but it would not budge. He looked up and saw a vile, awful face.

“Hello,” the evil man said with a sly tone. His voice was not human and his eyes were wildly discolored. His arms twitched and every time he exhaled, a puff of smoke left his mouth.

“You're standing on my key,” Benjamin exclaimed. “I have to get to the train station.”

“Why do you have to go so soon?”

“Who are you? Why are you stopping me?”

“I'm dreadfully sorry. Where were my manners?” he said as he ground his boot further and further into the ground. “My name is Russell Fox.”

“How do you know my name?”

“Everyone here knows your name, Benjamin. You're quite the talk of the castle. Even Selma knows your name,” Russell Fox said with a smirk. “We've never had someone from outside the castle come to visit us. It's quite, how should I say, special.”

“Who is Selma?”

“Oh, just some girl.”

“I was just leaving so if you would give me that key, please.”

“But why? Wouldn't you like to stay and learn more about making dreams?”

“King Bernard Zwirn said I have to or else I'll throw off the balance of dreams and nightmares.”

Russell Fox shifted more of his weight onto the brass key.

“He's always saying that, you know?” Russell Fox said with a curious grin. He wore a heavy leather trench coat and a dark hat that seemed too hot for such a warm day. Benjamin tried to push his boot again but Russell Fox resisted further.

“You have to let me go!” Benjamin yelled at him.

“Don't you want to stay?” Russell Fox asked again with an uncomfortably villainous tone.

“Yes, I do,” Benjamin said.

“Then, stay!” Russell Fox yelled. “I give you my permission.”

“But, King Bernard Zwirn said—”

“Oh, King Bernard Zwirn is always saying these things. He wants the castle all to himself and he doesn't want anyone to interfere. I bet he didn't show you any of the castle, did he?”

“Well, no, he didn't. But, he seemed friendly enough and he told me that I needed to get home quickly.”

“Of course he did. He wanted to get you out of the way so that he can make sure he can continue to manufacture dreams here. He doesn't want you to learn how they're made because that'll mean you could make your own dreams elsewhere. I think you should stay, Benjamin,” Russell Fox said.

“I want to leave!” Benjamin yelled. He realized he wanted to leave Russell Fox more than Castle Ehtahl, but both things felt the same at that moment. “I'm going home.”

Benjamin pushed one more time on Russell Fox's foot and the boot jerked away. The brass key looked delicate despite the heavy boot upon it. Benjamin grabbed the key and jumped to his feet.

Yellow building, Benjamin thought to himself. He had to get to the yellow building.

He ran past the blue building and then past the green building. At the yellow building, there was a keyhole in the middle of a large door that appeared to be the size of the brass key that Benjamin held. Benjamin jammed the key inside and was thrilled when he noticed it fit perfectly. He used the full weight of his tiny body to move the door open. Once there was enough room for him to squeeze inside, he found himself in the most beautiful, spacious, and grand train station he had ever seen. There were people drinking coffee from balcony seats looking down on train conductors walking along the platform amid women selling flowers and men shining shoes. There was room for dozens of trains to pull into the station and the roof was high enough that it felt like it was an enclosed stadium. The outside of the yellow building did not foretell at all what Benjamin saw in the inside. He felt as if he had wandered into a time when trains were the most important technology of an era. And among these train tracks, Benjamin saw one last train at gate number sixteen.

He knew where he needed to go. A tall, circular light beamed from the end of the last train track. It was exactly the same color and brightness that he saw in his bedroom earlier. This was his way home. He had to jump through it.

Benjamin knew it was inappropriate to be sprinting as quickly as he was through such a tranquil, beautiful setting but he also felt there was no other option to reaching the train in time. He was ten tracks away when he saw the light start to flicker, nine gates away when an explosion of white nearly blinded him, eight gates away when the departure gateway began to spin in a circle slowly, seven gates away when it started to spin faster, six gates away when the train began to create loud noises, five gates away when the train started to move forward, and four gates away when the train disappeared. The departure gateway closed.

“No!” Benjamin heard a man scream from the entrance of the train station. “What are you doing here?” yelled King Bernard Zwirn. “You were supposed to go through that departure gateway!”

“I tried,” Benjamin said between large breaths. “I ran as fast as I could but it left without me.”

“You should have run faster,” King Bernard Zwirn said with an increasing amount of anxiety. “This isn't good, Benjamin. This isn't good at all.”

“It won't open again?”

“It'll open in one month. We have no reason to have the departure gateway open so frequently.”

“I tried really hard to get to the train station on time,” Benjamin started to say, becoming a little scared and sad about the situation that he now found himself in. “I didn't try to miss it.”

“It happens,” King Bernard Zwirn said. “It's fine. There's nothing we can do about it now.”

“I was going to make it but then Russell Fox stepped on the brass ring and I couldn't get it quick enough and then he delayed me by at least two minutes.”

King Bernard Zwirn stood from the bench and looked even more concerned than he had just been. The dogs next to him ran away and the bird on the clock took flight. The entire station went quiet and still.

“What happened?” King Bernard Zwirn asked very slowly.

“Russell Fox stepped on the brass key,” Benjamin responded very quietly.

“How do you know Russell Fox? He prevented you from getting to the train station in time?”

“He stood on the key.”

“Did he say anything else to you?”

Benjamin thought hard about this question and was worried that he was taking too long to respond. He did not know where he was and did not want to put himself in a situation where he felt in danger. He needed to quickly assess who could be his friends and protectors.

“He said you wanted me to leave,” Benjamin said.

“That's correct. I do want you to leave, for your own protection,” King Bernard Zwirn responded. “Did he say anything else?”

The answer to these complicated questions did not come quick enough for Benjamin. He knew that King Bernard Zwirn knew that Benjamin was stalling.

“He said you did not want anyone else to make dreams,” Benjamin said each word while trying to observe King Bernard Zwirn's response.

“Russell Fox!” King Bernard Zwirn yelled into the air. “Benjamin, for the next month, you are not to talk to that man. You have to understand me. This is for your own protection. Russell Fox is not a good person these days. He was good, at one time, but those days are gone. This is a difficult time for Castle Ehtahl and I don't want you to get wrapped in the middle of it. I need you to obey my orders and I'll get you safely out of this castle in a month.”

Benjamin swallowed hard and with his instincts felt that he had to trust King Bernard Zwirn more than he trusted Russell Fox. King Bernard Zwirn wanted Benjamin to leave and there was no harm in leaving. But, Russell Fox wanted Benjamin to stay and Benjamin did not know if there was harm in staying.

“King Zwirn, can't I take the same departure gateway that Snark used to leave my house?” Benjamin asked quietly.

“Sadly, it's easier to create gateways to come here than it is to create gateways to leave here,” King Bernard Zwirn said.

“So what do I do now?”

“Well, you did say that you wanted to live here.”

“I did! Yes!”

“So, you'll join a class tomorrow morning and our best teacher will look after you.”

“Oh,” Benjamin said sullenly.

King Bernard Zwirn could tell that Benjamin was not excited about what he said.

“What's wrong, Benjamin?” King Bernard Zwirn asked.

“Well,” Benjamin replied slowly. “It's just that I wanted to come here because I didn't want to go to school. And now, you're telling me that I'm going to have to go to school. I was hoping I wouldn't have to go to school at all.”

King Bernard Zwirn chuckled softly and put his arm around Benjamin.

“I see,” King Bernard Zwirn said. “I'm not sure what your school was like, Benjamin, but I promise you that this will be unlike any other school you have attended. Sometimes, really good people show us how to enjoy things that we wouldn't enjoy if there were really nasty people involved. So, if you trust me, I think you'll be surrounded by really good people at this school. Do you trust me?”

Benjamin paused for a moment and compared Mr. Marchetta with King Bernard Zwirn. There was almost no comparison. Benjamin trusted King Bernard Zwirn completely.

“OK, I'll go to the school. I trust you,” Benjamin said with a smile.

Chapter 7
Selma

The lights flickered on and the door at the end of the room opened, revealing a tall, skinny woman who looked much more refreshed than Benjamin felt. It was his teacher, Miss Lindenmeyer. She had light brown hair and blue eyes slightly hidden by yellow glasses. Her hair lay on her shoulders and she wore light colored clothing like whites and off-whites and off off-whites. And as she spoke, Benjamin understood why King Bernard Zwirn said that she was the nicest person in Castle Ehtahl.

“OK, time to wake up,” Miss Lindenmeyer said to all of the boys in the room. She then left, closed the door halfway, and walked to the other end of the hallway. Benjamin could hear the soft pattering of her shoes hitting the wooden floor as she headed for the girls' room.

“OK, time to wake up,” he heard Miss Lindenmeyer say to another group of students.

Benjamin was already awake because he barely slept. It was uncomfortable being in a new place with new people and he did not like that he did not have the privacy of his own bedroom. When he thought about the adventures that he was about to embark upon, he did not imagine that in some cases, the circumstances would be less awesome than his circumstances at home. He had his own bedroom at home, after all. Here, ten other students slept in one room.

The boys stood, yawned, rubbed their eyes, and did the various other body movements that creatures do in the first minutes of the beginning of a new day. Everyone looked similar to his classmates from home. People must not be that different, Benjamin thought to himself.

“Move,” the boy on the bed next to Benjamin said.

“Hi, I'm Benjamin,” Benjamin replied, trying to make his first friend.

“You're on my shirt. Move,” the boy said as Benjamin realized that he was standing on a shirt that the boy wanted to wear.

“Oh, sorry,” Benjamin said as he moved his foot. He had obviously made it dirty and was not thrilled about having unsuccessfully made a new friend.

“Who are you?” the boy asked as he rubbed his eyes.

“My name's Benjamin. What's your name?”

“Ralph,” the boy answered as he stood and walked to the exit. “But, I've never seen you before. You're the Benjamin everyone's talking about?”

“I guess so. I'm new. I was supposed to leave yesterday but I missed it.”

“So, you're in our class now?” Ralph asked with a confused face.

“Yes, I guess so.”

“Weird. So, where are you really from?”

“Boys! Let's go,” Miss Lindenmeyer said as she entered the door again. Benjamin was glad that she interrupted their brief, tense conversation because he was not sure how to answer the question.

As each of the boys walked past Miss Lindenmeyer, she checked their name with a pencil on a paper attached to a clipboard. The boys walked through and Miss Lindenmeyer said hello to each one of them. She saw that Benjamin was still in the room and that he was having a little trouble tying his shoes.

“It's not so bad, once you do it a thousand times,” Miss Lindenmeyer said as she walked towards him. “You must be Benjamin.”

“Hi, I'm Benjamin,” Benjamin said awkwardly. He was still trying his best to make a good first impression with everyone.

“King Bernard Zwirn told me all about you. My name is Miss Lindenmeyer and I'll be your teacher for the next month,” she said so softly and warmly that Benjamin immediately knew that if no one else, he could trust her.

“I didn't mean to miss the gateway,” Benjamin offered, as he did not want to be seen as irresponsible.

“Oh, it's fine,” she said as she escorted Benjamin through the exit. “Our departure schedule is goofy anyways. So, King Bernard Zwirn tells me that you're in the fifth grade. Is that correct?”

“Yes, I'm in fifth grade. My teacher is Mr. Marchetta but he isn't very good.”

“Oh no?” Miss Lindenmeyer said with more curiosity than Benjamin expected. “What don't you like about the way he teaches?”

“He doesn't really pay attention to what the kids do in the classroom. I don't think he can see, to be honest. He looks like he's staring far off into the distance.”

“Well, every teacher has a different teaching style,” Miss Lindenmeyer said as she positioned Benjamin at the end of a line. There were about twenty students his age ahead of him. “I think you're going to find that my teaching style is a little different than other teachers you may have had. You'll be fine and if you have any questions or if you get nervous about anything, let me know and I'll help you.”

Benjamin felt more relieved that his teacher was so much nicer than Mr. Marchetta. Miss Lindenmeyer already knew Benjamin's name and made him feel so calm that he began to think he might actually enjoy going to school here.

The students walked forward in a single line and Benjamin saw that they were all dressed in the same uniform. The boys had similar haircuts and the girls wore their hair in a similar style. The line itself alternated boy and girl, which Benjamin found amusing because his school was not as organized as this school.

As he walked forward, the girl in front of him turned and gave Benjamin a confused look. He expected to receive these types of expressions on the first day. He received peculiar looks all the time at home. These children already knew each other and Benjamin would be the new kid. It was fine, he thought, because he was used to feeling like the odd person left out.

They continued walking forward and the same girl spun around again, this time giving Benjamin a confused expression that bordered on anger. Benjamin did not know how to respond so he smiled cautiously. It was not his best smile. It was not his worst. It was somewhere in between his best and his worst smile. Never before in his life had he concentrated on such things. But realizing that he had a fresh start, he was determined to be liked.

The girl spun around once more and stared at Benjamin and shook her head from side to side. Benjamin smiled again, this time showing more teeth than he wanted.

“Hi,” Benjamin said quietly so as not to cause the entire line of students to turn around. “Are you by chance Selma?”

“Quiet! Who are you?” the girl asked precisely. Her diction was perfect but her manners were abrupt. Benjamin worried that he was interacting with a classroom bully like Howard Horne.

“My name's Benjamin. I'm new.”

“I know you're new. If you weren't new, I wouldn't have asked you who you were.”

“I suppose that's right. Are you Selma?”

“I'll ask the questions.”

“OK. Do you have any more questions?”

“That's another question!”

“OK. I'm not sure what I should be saying right now. Maybe you should say something.”

“We don't say things like that so you must not be from here. Where are you from?”

“I'm from Pennsylvania.”

As soon as the word Pennsylvania left his mouth, all of the students stopped walking. There was a collective, loud gasp of surprise followed by books and backpacks falling to the ground. Several students hid behind other students while the larger of the bunch tried to move the line further and further away from Benjamin. He could feel their nervous, tense reaction as he watched them stare with wide eyes and lowered jaws.

“OK, children,” Miss Lindenmeyer said as she walked to the back of the line. “I guess now is as good a time as any to introduce our new student. This is Benjamin Buckingham from Pennsylvania. That's right. He's not from here. He's going to be with us for the next month as a foreign exchange student. Everyone, please be nice and give a warm hello to Benjamin.”

“Hello, Benjamin,” the class said in unison and in a worried, confused voice.

“He's from Pennsylvania,” Ralph whispered loud enough that Benjamin could hear this.

“Yes, right, so Benjamin isn't from Castle Ehtahl. Benjamin's from Pennsylvania,” Miss Lindenmeyer said.

The class reacted exactly as they had when they heard Benjamin say the word. There were gasps, books dropping, children cowering, and lots of fear.

“And, that's OK. We're going to treat him like he's from Castle Ehtahl. He'll get along fine.”

“But, we can't. He can't know what we do here,” a girl said with concern.

“Selma, it'll be OK. He'll learn enough to make dreaming more interesting but he won't learn too much that he won't enjoy dreaming anymore. A month will be too short a time for anything crazy to happen. Now, let's keep going to the classroom,” Miss Lindenmeyer said as she gently guided each student back into a single line.

Benjamin felt some nervous looks and glances from the other students. He did not think it was going to be easy to become friends with everyone now. No one seemed to like Pennsylvania, he thought, and he didn't quite understand why. But at least, he had finally met Selma. She was interesting. He didn't know why she was so defensive.

When Benjamin entered the classroom, he saw color everywhere. Paper trees lined the back wall with branches that spread to the ceiling to reveal a blue sky with clouds hanging over desks. Flowers and animals lined the other sides, drawn to a detail that Benjamin had not seen before. Each chair was a different color and each desk had multiple color combinations. It was like he had walked upon a painter's color pallet. And at the front of the class was King Bernard Zwirn.

“Hi, everyone!” King Bernard Zwirn said in a warm tone. “Is everyone ready to learn today?”

The class moaned in unison and King Bernard Zwirn chuckled in response.

“Well, I hope you have fun and I also hope everyone's had a chance to meet Benjamin,” he said with a smile. “You're all very lucky to meet someone who lives outside Castle Ehtahl. He's a great kid and I hope you all get to spend a lot of time with him.”

King Bernard Zwirn waved farewell and left the room. Benjamin sat in the back of the classroom, behind Selma Applebaum. He hoped she wasn't the class bully but for the moment, he wasn't sure. She didn't seem to like him very much.

“Today, we're going to continue our lesson on creating dreams for grumpy old men!” Miss Lindenmeyer told the class as she drew two old men on the chalkboard. There were some giggles throughout the classroom. “If you remember our lesson last week, who wants to tell me the three important rules that you have to keep in mind when you create a dream for a grumpy old man? Just imagine a grumpy King Bernard Zwirn going to sleep at night,” Miss Lindenmeyer said to the laughter of the class. It was almost impossible to imagine a grumpy King Bernard Zwirn.

Every student stretched their hand to the sky but Benjamin noticed that Selma was stretching her hand much higher than all of the other students. She was almost standing as she stretched her body further and further. He had never been in a classroom where there had been such eagerness to answer a question.

“Steven, why don't you give me the rules,” Miss Lindenmeyer said to a larger boy who was sitting next to Ralph.

Steven stood from his chair and counted the rules on his finger.

“First, the dream can't be too crazy because the grumpy old man could have a heart attack and that's not good,” he said.

“That's right,” Miss Lindenmeyer said as she wrote crazy dream equals heart attack on the board.

“Second, the dream can't be too happy because the grumpy old man will become even grumpier.”

“Right,” Miss Lindenmeyer said as she wrote too happy equals grumpy.

“And third, the dream can't happen in too many different places or the grumpy old man will get lost.”

“The first two were correct,” Miss Lindenmeyer said. “But, I think you're confusing the third one with one of the rules for creating a dream for people who get turned around easily. Do you know the third rule for grumpy old man dreams?”

Steven shrugged his shoulders. And as soon as his shoulders started to rotate around, Selma's hand shot back into the air again. She wanted to answer the question more than any other student in the room and Benjamin realized that Miss Lindenmeyer was deliberately not calling on her. But since no one else had a hand in the air, there was no one else to answer the question but Selma.

“OK, Selma,” Miss Lindenmeyer said as if she said these words several times every day. “What's the answer?”

“Don't include anything in the dream that made the grumpy old man grumpy in the first place,” Selma said as fast as she raised her hand.

“That's right,” Miss Lindenmeyer said as she wrote grumpy memories equals grumpier old man.

Benjamin was impressed that Selma knew the answer but he did not understand what it meant. Who were these grumpy men, he wondered, and why were these kids talking about the rules for dreams. In his classroom at home, they only talked about their own dreams. It was confusing but he did not want to ask basic questions in front of everyone because he knew he was the only one who didn't know the answer.

“Benjamin, are you able to follow along?” Miss Lindenmeyer asked as if she was reading his mind.

“Kind of,” Benjamin said quietly. “But, how do you make dreams?”

The class laughed and Benjamin immediately regretted asking the question.

“That's a perfectly fine question, Benjamin. The class is laughing because they never thought to ask such a question. They've been watching dreams be made their entire lives. Basically, we make dreams inside studios throughout the castle. People who have a dream, like the grumpy old man, have different rules assigned to them. So, that's why it's important that we learn as much as we can.”

Miss Lindenmeyer turned to the chalkboard and began to clear space to write. Benjamin wasn't completely sure what she meant because it felt so foreign to him. People didn't make dreams. Dreams were something that happened in his head while he was asleep.

“Did you understand that?” Selma asked Benjamin.

“I think so,” Benjamin said with a confused tone. “But, not really.”

“Good,” Selma said. “Because I study the hardest in this classroom and I work harder than everyone else and I'm not about to let someone from Pennsylvania come in and ruin it all for me.”

Benjamin was taken aback by her attitude and did not quite know how to respond. He did not want to agitate her further.

“I'm not here to ruin anything.”

“I bet,” Selma said as she spun around and raised her hand to answer Miss Lindenmeyer's next question.

As Selma walked to the front of the classroom to draw a layout for a dream in which a grandmother parachutes over a length of the Amazon jungle, Benjamin thought about switching seats to be closer to Ralph and Steven. There was an empty seat near them and Benjamin had decided that it was in his best interest to be friends with them rather than Selma.

“And then you have to make sure a fire extinguisher is available for each of the actors because there's a chance that the grandmother could catch on fire,” Selma concluded.

“Well done,” Miss Lindenmeyer said as the rest of the class groaned slightly.

“Selma knows all about fires because her dad broke the dream machine,” Steven said as Ralph laughed.

Selma stared at Steven and Ralph as she slowly made her way back to her seat. Benjamin found it peculiar that in this classroom, Selma didn't fight back against the two boys. She just went back to her seat and sat quietly.

“Not nice, Steven,” Miss Lindenmeyer said. “And remember, your mother has made her fair share of fires as well.”

The rest of the class laughed. Benjamin was a little distracted because the room was starting to get darker and darker. Over the course of a few minutes, the room became so dark that Miss Lindenmeyer had to turn on a light switch near the door. But, it was still early in the afternoon. The sun was still out, Benjamin observed through the window.

His curiosity overwhelmed him and he raised his hand to find an answer.

“Yes, Benjamin?” Miss Lindenmeyer asked.

“What is the dream machine?” Benjamin asked.

“The dream machine is the large building in the center of the castle that broadcasts all of the dreams. We make dreams and then we send those dreams to people sleeping throughout the world through the dream machine. Without it, there are no dreams. And, it broke for reasons we don't quite understand. Since it's broken, not all of our dreams are being received by people who are sleeping. Not everyone wants to dream, Benjamin,” Miss Lindenmeyer said.

“I see,” Benjamin said even though he did not quite understand. “And, why did it suddenly get dark?”

Before Miss Lindenmeyer could answer, there was a loud scream from outside the school. It was loud enough to cause Benjamin to worry that someone was in trouble. But inside the classroom, no one said anything and no one looked out the window. Everyone continued to stay seated as they had before.

“We don't talk about it,” Miss Lindenmeyer said with her lips clenched together.

Chapter 8
Studio

“You've already seen a lot of the castle,” King Bernard Zwirn said as he and Benjamin walked passed the enormous dream machine. “But, I'd like to show you a little more. What's it like living in Pennsylvania, Benjamin?”

“It's fine,” Benjamin said. “I've never lived anywhere else so I suppose it's the best place I've ever lived.”

“I haven't lived anywhere else, either. So, I suppose this is the best place I've ever lived.”

“How long have you been the king?”

“For quite a few years, Benjamin. I'm rather old. I feel young, but I'm old. I've been king for quite some time. And as the years go by, I wonder how long I'll continue to be king.”

“What do you mean? You don't want to be king?”

“Oh, I'd love to be king forever, if I could. But, it's not up to me. There are some people, one of which you met the other day, who do not want me to be king. They want to be king. And one day, that might just happen. But so long as I'm alive, that won't be the case. I care too much about dreams, Benjamin. I think everyone should be able to dream.”

“Can't everyone dream?”

King Bernard Zwirn turned to Benjamin with a smile. Benjamin realized that the question was a little naïve.

“You may find this hard to believe, but not everyone wants to dream. There are some people out there that want nightmares.”

“They want nightmares instead of dreams?”

“Yes, they want nightmares. It wasn't always this way. In the beginning of all of this, there was only one castle and there were only dreams. But now, there are many castles and not all of them make dreams. Some of them make nightmares.”

“Where are these castles? The ones that make nightmares.”

“They're outside the castle walls. And don't worry, Benjamin. We have a security fleet that works day and night to make sure that nightmares do not enter this castle. That, I can assure you. You won't have to worry about nightmares invading our dreams. I only wish we could make dreams forever.”

“Miss Lindenmeyer told me that the dream machine is broken.”

“It is, yes. I'm not exactly sure who did it but I have my suspicions. I think there's a part missing but I have no idea which one. A lot of our dreams have not been sent to sleeping people and I don't know why that is. Have you looked at this thing?” King Bernard Zwirn said as they rested on a bench near the gigantic tower. “I can't begin to tell you how many pieces are in there. My guess would be millions. But who knows? And if there's a piece missing, how can I know where it was supposed to be?”

“But you need to make the dream machine work again. I want to continue dreaming.”

“Of dinosaurs, right?”

“Yes!” Benjamin said enthusiastically. “Do you know about my dreams?”

“Your dreams are some of the most elaborate dreams that we produce. And, I know that you're a fan of Snark.”

“Snark! That's who I followed to get here.”

“I had a feeling. Rodney, I mean Snark, has a way of getting himself into trouble sometimes.”

“But my last dream, King Zwirn. In my last dream, something horrible was chasing after me. I had never dreamed of it before. It wasn't in any of my previous dreams”

King Bernard Zwirn paused and glanced at the ground. He put his hand on Benjamin's back and guided him away from the dream machine.

“I know. And, I'm sorry you had to see that. We do our best to keep nightmares out of the dreams but it's getting harder and harder. Do you want to see where dreams are made?”

“Definitely!” Benjamin said. He wanted to see where all the dinosaurs lived.

“You'll understand a little more in a bit but I need you to wear this vest. It's small but it's going to let everyone know that you're with me. If anyone asks who you are or what you're doing, you just tell them that you're my friend.”

Benjamin accepted the vest from King Bernard Zwirn and stared at it for a moment. No one had ever said something like that to him before. He thought he had friends in the past but was always unsure. King Bernard Zwirn made it clear that he wanted to be Benjamin's friend. And with that, Benjamin felt a wave of happiness overwhelm his body.

Benjamin and King Bernard Zwirn left for an ancient red building immediately next to the dream machine. As they passed people, King Bernard Zwirn said hello to each one and greeted them by their names. Benjamin couldn't believe this man knew so many different names. He seemed like he could have a conversation with anyone. And, everyone seemed to like him.

“This is production building two hundred and eighty eight,” King Bernard Zwirn said as they walked down a brightly lit hallway with hundreds of white doors on both the left and right. The hallway extended so far that Benjamin could not see the door on the other side. It was also so bright that he had to cup his hands around his eyes to see.

“Two hundred and eighty eight?” Benjamin asked. “How many production buildings are there?”

King Bernard Zwirn stopped and looked to the ceiling as if he was counting them in the air.

“I'm not sure,” he said with a chuckle. “They come and go but somewhere around six billion I think. How many people live in Pennsylvania?”

“I'm not sure.”

“You know, it's probably a number I should know but I don't. Let's just say there are a lot. There are a lot of people that live in Pennsylvania, right?”

“Right.”

“So, there are a lot of production studios.”

“What is behind each of these doors?” Benjamin asked as he reached for a handle.

King Bernard Zwirn pulled Benjamin back softly.

“Just a moment,” he said gently. “I need to open the doors for you. Once I open the doors, you'll be able to see the dreams.”

They continued walking down the hallway and by Benjamin's count, King Bernard Zwirn stopped in front of the twenty-ninth door on the right hand side. He placed his hand on the doorknob and then looked at Benjamin with a large smile. It was calming to Benjamin whose heart was racing with anticipation of what was behind this mysterious door.

“This is where dreams are created,” he said as he opened the door and pushed Benjamin inside. King Bernard Zwirn held his fingers to his lips and gestured to Benjamin to remain silent. He immediately understood why he had to wear the orange vest because there were many other people wearing orange vests as well.

Benjamin watched a large speedboat cruising as fast as it could through a river that raged through a metropolis. Buildings towered everywhere. A person sat in the driver's seat with a large smile, the wind throwing his hair back, and the sun bouncing light off his face. There were cameras capturing every angle. Cranes held lights and speakers above the stage. The speedboat roared as it switched gears and rocked back and forth as waves crashed into it. It went underneath bridges and passed sailboats and turned suddenly and headed the other direction. The metropolis looked like a metal forest that the speedboat moved through as quickly as it could. People in orange vests were moving the set as the man in the speedboat stood and then screamed with joy. Benjamin felt the joy the man must have been experiencing as everything here looked like so much fun. He wanted to ride a speedboat through a city.

In the hallway, Benjamin couldn't contain his excitement.

“That was amazing! That looked so cool!” Benjamin shouted as King Bernard Zwirn laughed. “But, how is that someone's dream? Those were actors.”

“When we went through that door, we stepped inside someone's head, for a short moment. Someone out there far away from us is dreaming right now and he is dreaming of driving a speedboat through a city.”

“But, I never saw cameras or lights or speakers or people wearing orange vests in my dreams.”

“You don't see the cameras or lights or speakers or people wearing orange vests because no one dreams in orange. You don't see anything in orange in your dreams.”

“Is that true?”

King Bernard Zwirn grinned a little and ushered Benjamin down the hallway.

“Well, I'm actually not sure, but it's been the case. To be honest, I think most people are so focused on their dreams that they don't notice any of the things happening around the dream. No one notices the lights and cameras and scene changes. We've gotten very good at producing them over the years. I'd like to say that our dreams are getting better and better.”

They walked inside another dream and saw a ski slope higher than any building Benjamin had ever seen. At the very top stood a skier whose smile stretched wider than her face. All around her, people in orange suits carried lighting instruments and speakers as the woman bounced back and forth. Before she jumped down the slope, Benjamin thought that she saw him, that they had exchanged glances for one moment. She then moved down that hill as fast as that speedboat had moved through that river. Snow splattered and sprayed in all directions as she raced between trees, jumped over large rocks, and did flips in the air over sleeping brown bears. Benjamin could hear the calmness of the wind as well as the sound of her skis carving into the snow.

King Bernard Zwirn took Benjamin into another production studio.

Here, Benjamin awed at a propeller airplane dodging cloud after cloud. The old grandmother inside the plane laughed as she maneuvered it from side to side and then into a full loop. Benjamin noticed his smile was widening like the smiles of the people who were experiencing these dreams. In each of these production studios, adventures were being created in the form of a dream very much like his own dreams. Machines and people created everything before him. The clouds, the blue sky, the trees on the ground, the birds flying past the airplane, and the sun in the corner of the room.

“Which one is next?” Benjamin asked with excitement as he jumped from side to side.

“I have to direct some more dreams so we need to go to the control center,” King Bernard Zwirn said.

“There's a control center?”

“Dreaming is actually quite organized.”

They walked from ancient building to ancient building. And as Benjamin passed each door, he listened to the sounds of excitement and happiness being made in a dream studio on the other side. He didn't know how it was possible but he didn't care. He knew that all of the other kids from home would be jealous of what he was experiencing.

Benjamin and King Bernard Zwirn ascended dozens of staircases up a tall, brick tower. The king was in very good shape, Benjamin thought, because the stairs were exhausting. As they climbed higher, Benjamin looked out small windows to see more of the castle. He could see the train station and the river and the dream machine. He could even see the school and dormitory. When Benjamin saw the large walls that guarded the castle, he realized that he was very far away from home. And under normal circumstances, this would have bothered him tremendously. But, he knew King Bernard Zwirn would be able to get him home eventually. He wondered what was on the other side of the walls.

King Bernard Zwirn stepped into a circular room at the top of this tower. Inside, there were many people chatting and yelling orders back and forth. There were television screens everywhere. And underneath these television screens were windows that revealed an amazing view of the castle below. From here, Benjamin could see into all of the dream studios. There were more than he could ever have imagined.

“This is the control tower,” King Bernard Zwirn said as he opened his arms like he did the first day Benjamin met him. “It's almost ten o'clock in Los Angeles so it's just about time for some dreaming.”

Benjamin sat in an empty chair and marveled over all of the people moving about. It looked like they were preparing for a space shuttle launch.

“Ready everyone?” King Bernard Zwirn said to a room full of happy men and women who cheered their king on. “We're going live in five, four, three, two.”

Benjamin would normally have been at home. He would have been the recipient of one of these dreams. But instead, he was observing them.

“One,” King Bernard Zwirn said. And at that moment, everyone was silent.

Chapter 9
Attack

Benjamin never thought about how many people dreamed at the same time. He just hadn't realized how many other dreams happened at the same time as his dreams. He could see into all of the dreams on the screens and in the production studios below.

He also realized that some people have simpler dreams than others. There was a screen in front of him with a man standing on a bridge looking down upon water lilies. There were no explosions or high-speed chases or dangerous situations. It was just water lilies and a bridge. And to the right of this screen, there was a woman looking at an owl, watermelon, pineapple, and coconut on a yellow table. Further along, there was a young child looking at a man carrying a gigantic basket of flowers on his back. Benjamin expected dreams to be adventurous. He did not realize that dreams don't necessarily have to be what he thought were adventurous.

There were car chases.

And base-jumping.

And throwing fire.

And people chasing animals.

And animals chasing people.

And flying. Lots of flying

And dinosaurs.

Snark! Benjamin thought as he saw his friend in screen eighteen thousand, one hundred and four. It was him. It was definitely Snark.

“That's him!” Benjamin yelled to King Bernard Zwirn.

King Bernard Zwirn stood and offered suggestions for making the dreams better. He pointed every which direction and simultaneously seemed to be talking to more people than Benjamin had ever known in his entire life. He spoke commands with such confidence and poise that he did not seem to sweat at all. Benjamin knew that if he was in charge, his heart would race and his mind would be overwhelmed with thoughts. King Bernard Zwirn, however, acted like he had been doing this his entire life.

“Who?” King Bernard Zwirn asked.

“Snark! That's him!” Benjamin said. “That's the dinosaur from my dream, the one who took me here.”

“Expand one eight one zero four, please,” King Bernard Zwirn said warmly.

The small screen expanded to fill nearly a quarter of the entire room. It was definitely him, Benjamin thought. He looked at King Bernard Zwirn who had a look of confusion on his face.

“Why is Rodney Cohen working?” King Bernard asked gently to some people in the room.

Benjamin did not know to whom King Bernard Zwrin was speaking but he could hear the brief sounds of someone responding back to him.

“I told him that he needed to take a break. He was overworked. Benjamin wouldn't be here if he just got more rest. Rodney works too hard,” King Bernard Zwirn said gently to anyone who would listen.

“Who is Rodney?” Benjamin asked softly and curiously.

“Rodney is person who plays the dinosaur in your dreams,” King Bernard Zwirn said. “But do realize that this doesn't change your dream. Your dreams are with dinosaurs. They're merely acted by people and Rodney is one of them. He's a workaholic.”

“Can I meet him?”

“Rodney?”

“Snark?”

“Well, that's the thing, Benjamin. You'd meet Rodney Cohen here but you'd meet Snark in your dreams.”

“I'd still like to meet Rodney.”

“OK, I'll set up a meeting for the two of you.”

King Bernard Zwirn's fingers tapped the desk in front of him. He muttered to himself a couple times and then he let out a short sigh. Benjamin noticed that King Bernard Zwirn's eyes did not move away from Snark.

“I need to check on something in that dream,” he said slowly. “I'll be back in fifteen minutes. You can hang out here and watch the screens until I come back.”

Benjamin didn't know why King Bernard Zwirn was being secretive. It was obvious that he was going to the dream that had Snark in it. But, Benjamin didn't know why. He didn't know if Snark was in trouble for having led Benjamin into Castle Ehtahl. All Benjamin knew was that he had not seen King Bernard Zwirn that serious before.

“Sure,” Benjamin said. “I can wait here. But, can I come along with you?”

“I think you'll have a lot more fun if you stay here,” King Bernard Zwirn said. “Look at all these dreams! And besides, I'll only be gone for a few minutes.”

Although Benjamin did not know exactly what was happening, the dreams were so interesting to him because he could see into the minds of people sleeping throughout the world. There was a person chasing a lion. An older woman was standing in front of a classroom. A young man was riding a motorcycle in a desert. The screen which had been showing Snark flickered and went dark.

“Where did Snark go?” Benjamin asked the people working behind him.

“Over there,” someone said from the back.

“Over where?” Benjamin answered with his hands at his side.

“Near the staircase on the right,” the same voice shouted back among all the other shouts.

Benjamin walked to the staircase, which was just next to the last column of screens. King Bernard Zwirn would be back soon enough, Benjamin thought, and he could not wait to ask him many questions about Snark. He wanted to know everything.

A hand gently rested on Benjamin's left shoulder and he was thrilled to realize that King Bernard Zwirn was back. His first question, he decided, was to ask where Snark and all of the dinosaurs went after the dreams were done. But when Benjamin turned around, he saw quickly that the hand did not belong to King Bernard Zwirn. It belonged to Russell Fox, the man who prevented Benjamin from reaching the train station. And standing behind Russell Fox was a sinister looking man wearing all black and smoking a long pipe.

“Hi, Benjamin,” the man said in a menacing voice.

Benjamin turned to run toward all of the workers but Russell Fox grabbed his shoulder and made a sign with his finger that Benjamin had better be quiet.

“Don't run, Benjamin. I'm here to watch the dreams, with you. Do any of them interest you?”

“Who are you?”

“Quiet, Benjamin. We have to watch the dreams.”

“I want you to leave me alone.”

“I will. I will. But, not right now.”

Benjamin did not want to speak with this man. He wanted King Bernard Zwirn to return as soon as possible. He strained his neck to look for the king but he couldn't find him.

“Benjamin, my name is Thalia Nachamie and I am, how should you say, very interested in you. You see, the king and I have a bit of a disagreement as to how dreams should be made in Castle Ehtahl. It'll be resolved in no time, don't you worry about that. I'll get my way. I always do. But first, I have a question or two for you,” Thalia said. “What kind of child leaves their home to go to someplace unknown? Did you not know what you were getting yourself into? Did you not know what would be on the other side? Tell me, Benjamin, why are you here?”

Benjamin paused and looked back and forth for someone who could help him. No one seemed to be looking in his direction. They were all preoccupied with the dreams on the screens.

“Silent, aren't we?” Russell Fox said. And at that moment, Benjamin watched the man's eyes transition from a dark brown to a bright orange and then back to brown. He breathed slowly and arched his head. Benjamin sensed he was not normal.

“I'd like you to leave me alone,” Benjamin said sternly. He was scared because he was defenseless against two people who made him feel very uncomfortable.

“I'll leave you alone, Benjamin,” Thalia Nachamie said. “But if you don't have a good reason for why you came here, I'm left to assume that you came here for something. And, you're not willing to tell me what that something is.”

“I came here for adventure,” Benjamin said quickly as he tried to wrestle his arm away from Russell Fox.

“Adventure?” Thalia Nachamie echoed with a laugh. “Why of course. You'll find adventure here. But you're after something more, aren't you?”

Benjamin got one hand loose and started to move away but Thalia grabbed his neck with a strength that Benjamin had never felt before.

“Now, now,” Thalia Nachamie said. “I'm just going to warn you once, Benjamin. There is no room for someone like you here. We don't take kindly to people who want to change the way we do things. I know what you're trying to do. I know what you want”

“I'm not trying to change anything! I don't know what you're talking about!” Benjamin yelled.

“Stop being so childish,” Thalia Nachamie said as he released Benjamin to the ground. “But do realize, I have my eye on you and I don't take kindly to people who aren't honest with me. You had better stay out of my business, Benjamin.”

Thalia Nachamie and Russell Fox stared angrily at Benjamin as they walked into the hallway and disappeared. Benjamin could still feel the tight grip from Thalia Nachamie. He didn't know what they were talking about. Why did they think he was trying to change something? Why were they so suspicious of him?

“Benjamin,” King Bernard Zwirn said as he reentered the room. “Are you OK?”

“Russell Fox was here and he—” Benjamin started to say. But as he began to speak, a loud noise erupted from one of the screens and several employees stood and pointed in the direction. King Bernard Zwirn jumped up and began issuing new commands.

“Isolate it!” he yelled. “Isolate eight five zero!”

“It's spreading,” a worker yelled.

“Shut it down,” the king responded.

“Are you sure?” someone yelled back.

“Yes, shut it down,” King Bernard Zwirn said quickly.

Benjamin looked at screen eight five zero. There was chaos. A man was hitting everyone in the scene and causing violence everywhere. He was acting ruthless and without concern for anyone's safety. And then, a gigantic monster entered the studio and began wrecking havoc upon everything.

“Something is wrong,” King Bernard Zwirn whispered to himself but in a voice loud enough for Benjamin to hear. “We've never seen a nightmare as strong as a nightmare like that.”

“Nightmare?” Benjamin asked.

“That was a nightmare,” King Bernard Zwirn said when he realized Benjamin was listening. “And, I fear it was the strongest nightmare I've ever seen. I'll keep you safe, Benjamin. Don't worry. I won't let those nightmares get you.”

Chapter 10
Kidnapping

“Psst,” Benjamin heard a nearby voice. “You awake?”

The voice belonged to none other than Ralph Eden, who Benjamin had become accustomed to knowing as the other boy in the dormitory who did not sleep at night. Ralph frequently used his flashlight to read books that were prohibited on school grounds. The only books the students were allowed to read during their personal time were books that had been written with incredible creativity and imagination. Books that downplayed excitement and fun were prohibited. They were the equivalent of poisoning the brain, King Bernard Zwirn told them. They belonged to the nightmares.

“Yes,” Benjamin said without moving. “I'm usually awake.”

“Why don't you sleep?” Ralph asked.

“I don't know how to sleep here,” Benjamin replied. As the words left his mouth, he realized this was true. When he was home, he could easily prepare himself to sleep by imagining his favorite dreams. But here, he was forgetting them and was unable to prepare himself to sleep. He couldn't save the world from Professor Undutois.

“It takes a while to get used to not being able to dream,” Ralph said.

“Not being able to dream?” Benjamin rolled to his side and stared into further darkness. “You can't dream?”

“I could months ago but I haven't had a dream since the dream machine stopped working. My dreams were amazing. I was conquering land after land and building bigger and bigger castles.”

“What happened? When did you stop dreaming?” Benjamin asked.

“I didn't choose to stop dreaming. When our dream machine broke and we learned we only had a limited supply of dreams left, everyone in the castle had to give up their dreams.”

“You gave up dreaming?”

“Yep. And, that's why you can't dream either,” Ralph said. “There's no more dreaming here. No more dreams until the machine is fixed. King Zwirn has been searching for whoever broke it for months. He still can't find the nightmare responsible for ruining everything.”

“So, why don't you just fix the machine?”

Ralph laughed and Steven Wazen on the other side of the dormitory shushed to tell him to be quiet. Steven could sleep as well as all the other students in the room.

“We can't just fix the machine,” Ralph said. “If we could fix it, don't you think we would have fixed it?”

“Yes, I guess. I would hope that would be the case.”

“Right. We can't fix it because it's broken and there's a piece missing.”

Benjamin knew the appropriate question to ask next but decided to let silence handle the conversation because he did not want to be seen as dumb.

“So, your next question,” Ralph continued. “Must be why don't we just make another piece.”

“Yes,” Benjamin answered.

“And the answer to that question is that the dream machine has over one hundred thousand pieces. We do not know which piece is missing, at least that's what the parents in town tell us.”

“You don't believe them?”

“It's not that I don't believe them. But, if this machine has been here for centuries, surely someone must have written down all of the pieces.”

“Maybe there is a blueprint for how to make another one,” Benjamin suggested without really knowing what he was saying.

“There is,” Ralph replied quickly. “But, Aloysius has it.”

“Aloysius!” Benjamin said loudly. Steven Wazen on the other end of the room shushed more loudly than he had earlier. Benjamin lowered his voice and in tandem, tried to lower his enthusiasm for learning more. “Who is Aloysius?”

“We don't talk about it,” Ralph said between his teeth.

“Everyone keeps saying that,” Benjamin said. “But, I don't understand why.”

“If you knew why, you would understand why we don't talk about it.”

Benjamin rolled onto his back and continued to stare into the darkness. He thought about Aloysius Trenhaile over and over and over. Without any details to create him in his mind, he tried to imagine what a person would look like that everyone else would not want to talk about. The only person that came to mind was Howard Horne. And, Benjamin decided, not thinking about anything was much better than thinking about Howard Horne.

Footsteps slowly made their way closer and closer to Benjamin's bed until a figure stood at the end.

“You guys have to be quiet,” Steven Wazen said with disgust. “Just because you can't sleep, doesn't mean we can't.”

“Sorry,” Benjamin said quickly. “We'll be quiet.”

“Were you dreaming?” Ralph asked with a smirk.

“I was dreaming of dreaming,” Steven replied with a laugh.

As Steven returned to his bunk, Benjamin closed his eyes and decided that although he was happy not being at school, he wanted to be able to dream. He decided he would ask King Bernard Zwirn how he could help fix the dream machine in the morning. Maybe, Benjamin thought, he learned something from his father making repairs to their house.

The lights in the dormitory flickered on and off until they stayed on. Benjamin looked at the large clock on the wall and noticed that it was four o'clock in the morning. It was two and a half hours earlier than they normally woke up. The lights never turned on before it was time to start the day.

All of the boys sat on their beds and looked at the clock with even more worry than Benjamin had. They glanced at each other and every one of them had an identical curl in the brow, mirroring each other's confusion.

“Have to wake up!” a brash voice yelled at the end of the dormitory. “Have to wake up now!”

Benjamin saw Noel Jaffin standing in the doorway with heavy armor covering his body. He looked like a heavy, metal cube. And although the sight of a metal cube person was rather funny, Benjamin was a little unnerved that everyone else was unnerved. Noel Jaffin did not wake up the boys. That was Miss Lindenmeyer's responsibility. And when Miss Lindenmeyer woke up the boys, she did not appear dressed in armor. Noel Jaffin was not prepared for a day of learning. He was prepared for battle.

“Wake up! Wake up! Wake up!” he said as he pounded his short legs back and forth into the ground.

Slowly, boy by boy arose and changed.

“Hurry!” Noel Jaffin yelled to the young children. “This is not a drill!”

“A drill?” Benjamin said aloud.

“We were told a day like this might happen,” Ralph said with a tiny feeling of exhaustion. “I guess today is that day.”

“What might happen?” Benjamin said. “What's going on?”

“Just follow orders,” Ralph replied. “And, you probably will be fine.”

The boys lined up and Noel Jaffin checked their names on a sheet of paper on a clipboard as they passed him. Noel Jaffin had to stretch his neck backwards in order to see which child was which. As usual, Benjamin was last.

“I've decided that I'd like to help King Bernard Zwirn,” Benjamin said as if Noel could somehow make this a reality.

“You're not going to help King Bernard Zwirn,” Noel Jaffin said quickly.

“But, I'd like to speak with King Bernard Zwirn about the dream machine,” Benjamin continued.

“You're not going to talk to King Bernard Zwirn about the dream machine,” Noel Jaffin said angrily.

“OK, when can I talk with him?” Benjamin asked.

“He's gone.”

Benjamin stopped. All of the boys in the line stopped. It was worse news that any of them had thought they would hear.

“What do you mean, gone?” Steven asked forcefully.

“I mean that King Bernard Zwirn has been kidnapped. I am here to take you to your class. No more questions. Silence while we walk,” Noel Jaffin said as he marched to the front of the line.

They marched at a slower pace from hallway to hallway in complete silence. But despite not being able to hear the thoughts of the other children, Benjamin could feel that something had gone so wrong that these otherwise happy and energetic children had suddenly become scared and concerned.

As they made their way past the classroom, Noel Jaffin led them to another hallway decorated with paintings on all walls, ceilings, and even the floor. Benjamin stepped carefully from painting to painting of old men and women who lived in this castle before. And oddly, each expression on their face looked direr than the expressions he had noticed on their faces earlier.

Noel reached a painting of a woman wrapped in a red flag on a white horse against a background of tan rocks that matched tan clouds. She pointed to the top left hand corner of the canvas. And that was where Noel Jaffin punched his fist through the canvas and pulled on a hidden lever, revealing an old circular staircase leading down below.

Each of the boys filed one after the other while Noel Jaffin, again, checked their names against a piece of paper on a clipboard. Benjamin, again, was the last to depart but he decided this time that it was not in his best interest to ask Noel any other questions. Instead, he wondered how many other secret passageways existed in this castle. And, he wondered how many other secrets there were in general.

As he stepped down each curved stair, he descended several floors below the ground. It was dark, lit only by candles on the walls, mounted against cold rocks that were moist from whatever rainwater had fallen below. After having turned six or seven times, Benjamin found himself at the opening of a massive, cavernous room that looked like it could hold thousands of people. There were people everywhere.

In front of him, Miss Lindenmeyer stood with the girls from the class. As Miss Lindenmeyer welcomed the boys to join the girls, Selma Applebaum took a step forward. Benjamin knew, before she said anything, that she was the angriest of everyone in the room.

“This is all Benjamin's fault!” she screamed.

Chapter 11
Flying Machine

Benjamin felt his body freeze. His face had no color and his arms felt like cement. He had just been blamed for King Bernard Zwirn's disappearance. But worse than having been blamed, Benjamin couldn't believe something happened to King Bernard Zwirn.

“If Benjamin wasn't here,” Selma Applebaum said sternly. “This would never have happened!”

Miss Lindenmeyer restrained Selma and pushed her to the back of the room. Benjamin did not know where to look.

“What did I do? Did something happen because I came here?” Benjamin muttered quietly to Miss Lindenmeyer.

“It's not your fault, Benjamin,” Miss Lindenmeyer said as she cautiously pushed Benjamin towards the rest of the class. “You didn't understand what coming here meant. You didn't do anything wrong.”

“Did King Bernard Zwirn disappear because of me?”

“Of course not, Benjamin. This has nothing to do with you,” Miss Lindenmeyer said calmly.

Benjamin looked around at the other students but none of them wanted to make eye contact. It was as if all of the kids around him thought that Benjamin would disappear if they did not see him.

“Where is he?” Benjamin asked Miss Lindenmeyer.

“I don't know, Benjamin,” Miss Lindenmeyer said. “You're going to be here for a little bit longer than I thought.”

Benjamin began to panic. He felt like King Bernard Zwirn was a friend. And, that friend held the key to get him home. Benjamin wasn't eager to get home. But at that moment, he didn't know how it would be possible to leave without the king.

As Benjamin stared off in the distance, Miss Lindenmeyer held her class as she had before. It was difficult for him to pay attention because there were people walking around and talking about what may happen next. The distractions were endless and Benjamin began to fear the worst.

“Today, we're going to play with flight machines. We normally wouldn't but this space just so happens to have one of the tallest ceilings around, which makes it incredibly safe. No one is going to be flying to the moon,” Miss Lindenmeyer said.

The students were happy about the idea of using flight machines. Benjamin did not know what they were but he was intrigued when Noel Jaffin wheeled a long rack of odd shaped devices to Miss Lindenmeyer. They looked like a combination of a motorcycle engine and a chair, each of them painted orange.

“Thanks, Noel,” Miss Lindenmeyer said. “Now students, grab a flight machine. Make sure you get your correct size.”

Benjamin watched all of the students pick their flight machines and when it was his turn to pick his, there was only one engine left. He was not sure if it was his size or not. So, he took it and hid behind the other students.

“Oh, Benjamin,” Miss Lindenmeyer began to say with some caution.

“Benjamin shouldn't be allowed to use the flight machines,” Selma said sternly to Miss Lindenmeyer, without addressing Benjamin himself.

He took a step toward the rack to return the device.

“It's fine,” Miss Lindenmeyer said quickly and abruptly. “Benjamin, watch Selma sit on her flight machine.”

Selma was quite upset that she had suddenly been partnered with Benjamin. And Benjamin was quite concerned that his safety was being entrusted to someone who hated him. It was not a great partnership by any means.

Benjamin watched Selma quickly settle into her flight machine and turn the ignition switch on. It made a louder noise than Benjamin expected. It sounded like a mechanical hummingbird would hum.

“Selma, we're going to fly one at a time,” Miss Lindenmeyer said. “Because we don't want any more mid-air collisions, right Ryan?”

Miss Lindenmeyer had the students line up in front of her. One by one, she inspected the flying machines to make sure that they were working properly. She did not want a disaster. Benjamin watched her inspect the machines like a mechanic had inspected his parents' cars at home. Then when Miss Lindenmeyer was finally satisfied that everything appeared to be in order, she went to the first student and nodded with approval.

Steven Wazen flew into the air and his flying machine's engine churned a fine, soft buzz. It was not like the sound of a motorcycle or the sound of a locomotive. It was like the sound of a microwave and a kettle of boiling water. Benjamin watched Steven turn the flying machine to the left and then to the right and then to the left again. He flew fast, then slow, and then fast again. It looked almost graceful, Benjamin thought, as student after student flew into the air and around the room.

To Benjamin, the entire ordeal, so far, was both exhilarating and frightening. This was actually some of the adventure that he was hoping to find. He wanted experiences that were different than his experiences at home and certainly, there were not many flying apparatuses at home. And yet when each student successfully landed, he became more and more scared as he realized it would next be his turn.

“OK, Benjamin,” Miss Lindenmeyer said with the same confidence and enthusiasm she had said to all of the other students. “Let me show you how this works.”

Miss Lindenmeyer sat on the flying machine, pressed an ignition button, and then slowly ascended into the air.

“Once you get this high,” Miss Lindenmeyer shouted as she began to turn around in the air. “You lean forward to go forward. You lean backward to go backward. Left to go left and right to go right. It's actually quite easy.”

“Is it magic?” Benjamin asked.

“No!” Selma shouted from behind him. “This isn't magic. This is science. That's an engine. It's not some fantasy.”

“Selma's right,” Miss Lindenmeyer said as she landed and then promptly adjusted her hair. “It's just science. We have a lot of machines here that you probably don't have in Pennsylvania. They help us create more vivid dreams.”

Benjamin wanted to stall a little longer. He was not feeling as confident as the other students felt about flying one of these machines. Even if he was able to get the flying machine into the air, he would then be defenseless to all of the people on the ground that hated him. Certainly, someone would throw a rock or some fruit, he thought.

“I don't think this is a good idea, Miss Lindenmeyer,” Selma protested as she flew into the air and coasted along the walls of the room.

“It'll be fine, Benjamin,” Miss Lindenmeyer reassured him. “The machine does most of the work for you. Now, just have a seat. And, I have a remote that's going to control your flight.”

She nudged Benjamin into position, tied his seatbelt tight, and then fastened his helmet. As soon as he looked like someone who would soon take flight, Miss Lindenmeyer hit the ignition button without warning Benjamin ahead of time. He felt a sudden jerk of the engine and a sudden beat of his heart. The machine raised Benjamin further and further into the air where Benjamin had a view of the sheer size of the room. Although he still felt more comfortable on the ground, flying was more fun than he expected.

As Miss Lindenmeyer advised, he moved forward as he leaned forward. He moved backwards as he leaned backwards. The machine sensed his movements and handled everything for him.

He even grew enough confidence that he relaxed his tight grip on the handlebars and looked to the students below. Selma Applebaum, along with the rest of the class, had their arms crossed in front of them.

“OK, Benjamin,” Miss Lindenmeyer yelled. “I'm going to turn off the machine from my remote control. You'll descend in a second.”

Miss Lindenmeyer inspected the remote and clicked a few times until the engine of the flying machine stopped. Benjamin waited to get back to the ground, entrusting his teacher to his safety. His teacher, though, looked at Benjamin with confusion and then looked back at her remote with more confusion.

“It's off,” Miss Lindenmeyer said. “You should be descending.”

Benjamin looked to the rest of the class who all looked confused. He was ascending further and further into the air.

Miss Lindenmeyer became more worried. She ran for a closet on the near side of the room. Benjamin looked to see where she was going and the flying machine turned with him. He pointed the engine down and it started to go down. Maybe, he thought, the remote did not work in this dark hall.

He watched his teacher return with a long rope. She turned one end of it into a lasso. The other students uncrossed their arms and now had their hands on their hips. Benjamin did not know what to make of their expressions other than something peculiar had happened.

“Catch the rope when I toss it to you,” Miss Lindenmeyer yelled.

She threw the lasso up in the air and Benjamin grabbed it when it was near. She pulled and pulled and pulled with all her strength and Benjamin descended to the ground. As soon as he placed his right foot on the ground, the flying machine jerked and fell suddenly to the floor.

Benjamin saw that Miss Lindenmeyer was exhausted. And the students, they were perplexed.

“OK, everyone,” Miss Lindenmeyer said as she continued along with her class. “Let's get lunch.”

Everyone filed in a single line and started to march onward. As Benjamin passed Miss Lindenmeyer, she placed a hand on his chest so that he stopped walking forward. She looked from side to side as if she did not want anyone else to hear what she was about to say. Benjamin leaned forward so that he could hear her whispers.

“You can't leave my side or view,” Miss Lindenmeyer whispered. “You're in a lot of danger.”

Chapter 12
Evil

Over the next week, everyone in class treated Benjamin differently. He noticed that Ryan Eden and Steven Wazen watched him as if they were hawks staring at a little mouse. Selma Applebaum refused to make eye contact with Benjamin. But, it was impossible to ignore a student who was able to fly a machine when it was not powered on.

“That hasn't been done before,” said one student. “How did you do it?”

“I don't know,” Benjamin said. “I just kept sitting.”

“Can you do that with other machines?” another student asked.

“I don't know,” Benjamin responded again. “I don't know what other machines exist.”

“Are you related to King Bernard Zwirn?” another student asked.

“No, I don't think so,” Benjamin answered.

“That would be amazing if you were,” another student stated. “Imagine we have in our class a student who is a relative of the man who made all of the dream machines.”

“King Bernard Zwirn made all of these machines?” Benjamin asked.

“His dad did,” Selma said as she continued to look forward at the chalkboard while all of the other students continued to look at Benjamin. “But, he's gone. Only his sons are alive.”

“Who are his sons?”

“We don't talk about it,” everyone said in exhausted unison.

“What's life like in Pennsylvania?” another student asked.

“It's fun,” Benjamin said. “It's not too different than living here I suppose.”

“Are there people everywhere?”

“Yes.”

“And lots of food?”

“Yes.”

“And people can do whatever they want.”

“For the most part.”

“And everyone has dreams?”

“Well, not recently. There haven't been dreams lately at all. My dad hasn't had a dream in months,” Benjamin said.

“Students,” Miss Lindenmeyer said as she entered the classroom wearing a raincoat. “We have to go to the general assembly area for an announcement. So I need you to line up in a single file and head outside. Raincoats on!”

Student after student put on their coats and filed from the classroom outside into the unforgiving rain. There were people exiting every building, all headed in the same direction toward the gigantic dream machine. Benjamin wondered what all of these people did each day. He did not know what every person in Pennsylvania did and he imagined students felt the same way about Castle Ehtahl. There were tens of thousands of people of various ages and sizes and colors gathered in one big plaza. The dream machine hovered over them like a tree that had spiraled upward without casting a single branch.

Benjamin followed Steven Wazen and noticed that Miss Lindenmeyer, who led the group of students, frequently turned around to make sure that she could see him. When they reached a spot in the plaza with enough space for the class, Miss Lindenmeyer positioned everyone in rows and then stood next to Benjamin.

“You are not to leave my side,” Miss Lindenmeyer said.

“What is happening?” Benjamin asked.

“I'm not exactly sure,” Miss Lindenmeyer responded. “But, it's probably related to King Bernard Zwirn's disappearance.”

“Does this happen often?”

“No,” Selma replied. “King Bernard Zwirn liked talking to small groups of people rather than everyone at once.”

“So, who is going to speak now?” Benjamin asked.

Selma shrugged her shoulders as if she did not care. At the front of the plaza before the tens of thousands of people, there was a newly constructed green and blue stone building that towered as high as the dream machine. The building reminded Benjamin of cathedrals he had seen pictures of before. But, this building was much wider and much more detailed than any cathedral he had ever seen. At the very top, there was a balcony with a red flag hanging over the entrance.

As rain poured down, projection screens were hastily opened throughout the plaza. Cameras turned on and focused themselves on the balcony. Lights flickered and flashed from all directions as soundchecks began to test the limits of the speaker system. A hush came over the crowd as Castle Ehtahl's anthem began to play. It was a song that reminded Benjamin of jazz songs his dad would play on the radio while working on the family car. The rhythm was quick and the song was inspiring, even though Benjamin knew none of the words.

When the song ended, the lights dimmed and a roar spread across the crowd from the back to the front. Even Benjamin got caught up in the excitement of what was to come. He noticed, however, that Miss Lindenmeyer was not energized at all. Her eyes were glancing from left to right in a fast enough manner that suggested that she was looking for someone. Benjamin realized she was nervous and that made him nervous. He trusted Miss Lindenmeyer more than he trusted the crowd. And without King Bernard Zwirn, Benjamin looked to Miss Lindenmeyer for help.

On the balcony, two guards who looked to be about the same size as Noel Jaffin removed the red flag. The crowd erupted in anticipation like Benjamin had seen at music concerts on television. Benjamin expected, for reasons he could not explain, to see something magical happen. Maybe, he thought, King Bernard Zwirn would return.

A man did enter but it was not King Bernard Zwirn. It was Thalia Nachamie. And behind him, Russell Fox stood at attention.

The crowd erupted in excitement and cheers and Benjamin was more confused. He did not see any reason to cheer for either of these people. Russell Fox and Thalia Nachamie were evil.

“My fellow Ehtahlians,” Russell Fox projected into a microphone. “I present to you the interim king, Thalia Nachamie.”

The crowd screamed and cheered. Miss Lindenmeyer did not flinch and Benjamin noticed that Selma Applebaum did not flinch as well. The other students in the class cheered as loud or louder than the people around them. And at that moment, Benjamin began to realize that everyone may have been cheering only because everyone was cheering and not because of the men who stood on the balcony.

Thalia Nachamie glanced from side to side with his long face and his crooked nose. His dark black hair blended into his black clothes he wore and the black hat on his head. He looked like a large crow that wore pieces of leather rather than feathers.

“Ladies and gentleman,” Thalia Nachamie's voice boomed across the plaza as the rain continued to pour down. “A great tragedy has come to our castle. Our very own Bernard Zwirn has been kidnapped. We do not know where he was taken and we do not know who has taken him. But, we will find him. And until we do, we will continue to do what we do best.”

Cheers erupted throughout the crowd and Benjamin's face turned pale as he heard confirmation of all the rumors of the past week. King Bernard Zwirn was kidnapped. It was, he thought, one of the worst possible answers to where the king may have been.

“We set a search party to look for Bernard Zwirn. We don't have many clues so if anyone knows what has happened, please contact me directly and I'll make sure to tell you whether your clue is valid or not. As you all know, if Bernard Zwirn is not found in another week, we will have to move on without him. We cannot wait around endlessly for his return. We don't have time. Our dream machine is running low.”

Thunder cracked in the distance and the rain became fiercer. Miss Lindenmeyer placed a hand over Benjamin as her eyes continued to move back and forth. But then, her eyes stopped. Benjamin saw that she was looking to the left but he could not see what she had found.

“If anyone has any questions at this time, please ask them now,” Thalia Nachamie projected to the audience.

“Is there a chance anyone else could be kidnapped?” Russell Fox asked into a microphone behind Thalia Nachamie.

“That's a great question,” Thalia Nachamie continued. “And there is a severe chance that every one of you could be kidnapped. So, it is important that you continue to do your jobs well and that you do not wander outside of this castle. If we cannot fix the dream machine, we will have to use another proposed solution. This proposed solution, as I told you last year, will make sure that you can make dreams and not be kidnapped.”

“Will the dream machine be fixed?” Russell Fox asked into the microphone again. Benjamin could see that Russell Fox was reading from a tiny sheet of paper.

“That is again a great question,” Thalia Nachamie began. “We are missing a piece to the dream machine and we do not know what this piece is or where this piece is. It's possible that the dream machine has suffered damage beyond repair. But, we do not have any way of knowing whether we can fix it without having this piece returned to us. If you know the evil, villainous person who has stolen it, you must tell us immediately. We will not stand for evil in our castle.”

“What will we do if we run out of resources to make dreams?” Russell Fox asked again, in the same tone and awkward reading style as the previous two questions.

“Another great question,” Thalia Nachamie started. “We will not run out of resources to make dreams. If the dream machine fails, I will make sure we have the resources to make more dreams. You can count on that. I think that's it for questions. Have a great day everyone.”

Thunder crashed and Benjamin was surprised that Thalia Nachamie ended his question and answer session because there were over a hundred hands raised throughout the plaza. Selma had her hand raised too and took it back down with disgust. Miss Lindenmeyer was still looking to her left and Benjamin noticed that she was trying to talk to someone by mouthing words and reading lips. He still could not see who she was speaking with.

As the crowd started to depart in various directions, Miss Lindenmeyer ushered the students back to the school where she was met by another teacher Benjamin had not seen before. Benjamin started to walk into the school but then Miss Lindenmeyer grabbed his hand. He saw that Selma was watching everything that was about to transpire.

“Quickly, Benjamin,” Miss Lindenmeyer said. “Come with me.”

Miss Lindenmeyer and Benjamin ran back into the crowd, which made Benjamin quite nervous. He did not know who to believe and who to trust other than Miss Lindenmeyer. Any of these faces looking upon him could belong to the person who kidnapped King Bernard Zwirn. They zigged and zagged between one dark clothed body and another, getting wet from the rain along the way.

Benjamin stopped. In the distance, he saw him.

It was Snark. It was Rodney Cohen.

“Miss Lindenmeyer!” Benjamin yelled. “That's the dinosaur that led me here!”

Miss Lindenmeyer looked in the direction that Benjamin pointed. Rodney looked confused and concerned.

“Rodney,” Miss Lindenmeyer said with a long sigh. “We have to run, Benjamin. I'm going to introduce you to Rodney Cohen now.”

She grabbed his hand as a person would who was pulling an unwilling partner. Benjamin looked back over his right shoulder and watched Rodney walk toward them. His heart beat faster as he realized he would finally meet his favorite dinosaur. He didn't know what to say. He had waited for this moment his entire life. And, it was finally here.

“Hey, there, um, Benjamin. Sorry, I, uh, kind of, you know, got you here, when, um, you know, the King's missing and all,” Rodney Cohen said exceptionally awkwardly. He kept rummaging through his hair like he knew he did something wrong. It was not, Benjamin thought, the welcome he had dreamed of.

First of all, Rodney Cohen was a person and he wasn't wearing the Snark costume. And Benjamin realized that he didn't like Rodney Cohen as much as he liked Snark. Snark was confident and powerful and inspiring and adventurous. Rodney Cohen was awkward and goofy. Benjamin was speechless.

“I know seeing me, you know, um, without the, uh, costume, er, the, uh, you know, I mean, what I'm trying to say is, that, well, I'd rather, you know, greet you as Snark, not, uh, well, not, um, not me,” Rodney Cohen said as he shifted his weight back and forth.

Benjamin stared at Rodney Cohen and let out a long sigh.

“Yes, I kind of wish you were Snark right now,” Benjamin said.

Benjamin looked at Rodney Cohen as if he was a stranger. And, Miss Lindenmeyer appeared to recognize this because she interrupted the quite awkward conversation.

“Rodney, there's something you need to know about Benjamin,” Miss Lindenmeyer said while making sure no one around her listened.

“Oh, really? What is it?” Rodney said curiously.

“We can't talk here,” Miss Lindenmeyer said as she glanced from side to side at the thousands of people walking among them. “Let's go to the school.”

Benjamin wondered what was so special about him. He also wondered how someone so lanky and awkward like Rodney Cohen could be so confident and powerful as Snark. How was it that one person could be two different things? It seemed impossible to Benjamin. No one could be both.

“Benjamin can fly on a flying machine without power,” Miss Lindenmeyer whispered to Rodney Cohen as they walked forward.

Rodney quickly glanced at Benjamin and his confused face turned into excitement. He gave Benjamin a huge thumbs up and tried to give him a high-five before Miss Lindenmeyer pushed down his hand.

“Not now, Rodney! I was teaching the class to fly on the flying machines,” Miss Lindenmeyer continued. “Benjamin went up as well and I controlled his flying machine from a remote control. When I turned it off and had Benjamin come back to the ground, he continued to fly around.”

“Maybe the remote control was busted,” Rodney said.

“It wasn't. I tested it again that evening.”

“Maybe there were strong winds. I know I get in lots of trouble in strong winds. I can get stuck up there for hours even.”

“We were indoors.”

“Maybe he had a remote control of his own.”

“Rodney, please. He didn't have a remote control of his own. I'm only telling you this, not because I want to, but because you brought Benjamin here and you're going to have to help me protect him. If Thalia Nachamie learns of this, Benjamin is going to be in incredible danger. Thalia Nachamie will either capture him or kill him.”

Rodney examined Benjamin as they continued to walk. Benjamin was confused why this guy was going to help protect him. He looked like he was much older than Benjamin and not many more years older in maturity. But, Benjamin couldn't forget that Snark saved him during the nightmare he had. Maybe, Benjamin thought, Rodney could help him after all.

“Sweet!” Rodney Cohen yelled. “I'll hide the little man.”

“Good,” Miss Lindenmeyer said. “Do you know where King Bernard Zwirn is? By chance, did you have anything to do with it?”

“No!” Rodney said as he waved his hands back and forth. “I love King Bernard Zwirn. I wouldn't do such a thing. I want him back. Unfortunately, it seems Aloysius Trenhaile doesn't like him.”

“Aloysius?” Benjamin asked.

“Oh sorry little dude, we don't talk about it” Rodney replied. “But, um, yeah Aloysius kidnapped him.”

Chapter 13
Dreams

Ryan Eden and Steven Wazen waited for Benjamin to wake up in the dormitory before they began firing questions at him. They had been waiting for about thirty minutes, watching Benjamin sleep. Little did they know, however, that Benjamin was doing his best to sleep as long as he could. He realized that being awake was only causing him trouble and that sleeping would allow him to pass time more quickly. Ryan and Steven grew tired of waiting any further. They grabbed Benjamin's bed and began rocking it from side to side.

Benjamin could not sleep through what was essentially a simulation of an awful boat ride. His eyes flew open and his body shifted forward as he signaled that he had had enough. But Ryan Eden and Steven Wazen had not noticed because they became more occupied with shaking the bed than waking up Benjamin.

“What are you guys doing?” Benjamin asked as he rubbed his eyes.

“You have to wake up,” Ryan Eden said.

“I don't have to wake up,” Benjamin replied. “There's no school today.”

“Well, you were going to have to wake up at some point,” Steven Wazen added with a snicker. “And besides, we've got some questions we want answers to.”

“Everyone has questions for me,” Benjamin said as he found clothing to change into. “I don't want to answer any more questions.”

Benjamin walked across the dormitory as Steven Wazen and Ryan Eden followed like two snakes stalking a prey. Benjamin felt unease about their presence because they obviously had questions that he did not want to answer. And even though he could not stand up to Russell Fox or Thalia Nachamie, he also knew he could not stand up to Steven Wazen or Ryan Eden.

“Just one question, then,” Steven Wazen continued, unconcerned with Benjamin's request for silence. “Why is it that you want to be friends with dinosaurs?”

Benjamin paused because that question was more unexpected than all of the questions that raced through his mind. But he wondered what Steven Wazen was getting at because Ryan Eden laughed uncontrollably behind him. He could answer this question, he decided, because he was not scared of what he would say.

“We go on adventures together,” Benjamin said. “They are my friends.”

“But, they're in your dreams,” Steven Wazen said. “They aren't real.”

“I know they're in my dreams,” Benjamin replied. “And, I know they aren't real. But that doesn't stop me from dreaming.”

“Right,” Steven Wazen said quickly. “We all know the story of how you got here. But you don't realize that you didn't see a dinosaur. You saw Rodney Cohen.”

“I know Rodney,” Benjamin said quickly. “Miss Lindenmeyer introduced me and Rodney's been showing me what dreams he acts in.”

“Oh, Benjamin. You don't know how much trouble you're in. Do you? You can't be that dumb?”

Benjamin paused for a moment because he knew from his experience dealing with Howard Horne that there was no good answer to that question. If he responded that he was not dumb, he would not further his own cause. But if he responded that he knew the danger he was in, he would be lying. He wanted to know why he was in danger. He didn't understand but Steven Wazen was certainly not going to explain it to him. And so, Benjamin turned around in hopes that the question and the two boys would disappear.

“Gentleman,” Noel Jaffin said as he entered the dormitory wearing less armor than before. Noel cleared his throat several times as if there was something lodged between his pumpkin body and his bowling ball head. “Benjamin, follow me.”

“Where are you taking him?” Ryan Eden asked as he walked to Noel Jaffin.

“That's none of your business, Ryan,” Noel said despite being nearly a foot shorter than the boy. “Benjamin, you are to follow me at once. Let's go.”

“You're always escorting him. You're never escorting any of the other kids. It's not fair.”

Noel shook his head in annoyance at Ryan Eden. Benjamin smiled inwardly as he passed the two boys and although he was not thrilled to see Noel Jaffin, he was thrilled to leave the dormitory. Whenever Noel Jaffin appeared, Benjamin knew that something had happened that was not very good. It was as if Noel Jaffin's arrival was a message alone that trouble was near.

“Where are we going?” Benjamin asked Noel Jaffin.

“We,” Noel Jaffin stated as he tried to lengthen his walking distance to match that of Benjamin's, “are not going anywhere. I am going home to watch the Naidefur games.”

“The what?” Benjamin asked.

“No time to explain. You are going to meet Miss Lindenmeyer and Rodney Cohen.”

“But, there's no school today,” Benjamin protested.

“You are a smart one,” Noel Jaffin said sarcastically. “But danger doesn't rest on the weekends and you've got a date with a lovely woman and, um, well, a dude.”

“Fine, fine,” Benjamin said because he did not want to hear any more.

Noel Jaffin escorted Benjamin through a series of buildings and hallways that Benjamin had become more accustomed to seeing. He knew that the guard was taking him to a production studio.

“Noel, how do nightmares get in here?” Benjamin asked.

“Oh I don't know,” Noel Jaffin grumbled through his mustache. “I suppose they come in here a lot like you came in here.”

Benjamin thought about that answer for a second because only at that moment did he realize why he was confused earlier as a nightmare. If nightmares entered the way he entered, of course everyone would assume that he was one. It made sense.

Noel reached his arm above his head and turned a doorknob. It was studio two thousand and two.

“In you go,” Noel Jaffin said as he began to shuffle Benjamin forward.

“Wait, Noel,” Benjamin said. “Aren't you going in too?”

“Over here!” Miss Lindenmeyer yelled from the far side of the production studio. “Come over here.”

“And, away we go,” Rodney Cohen shouted as he turned on a flying machine and soared into the air. “I never get tired of this!”

He moved every which direction as Miss Lindenmeyer used another machine to create clouds. Miss Lindenmeyer then turned on a fan, which blew the clouds in the air so that Rodney could fly between them. Miss Lindenmeyer and Rodney were both laughing and Benjamin thought that it did look like fun.

“Is this all fake?” Benjamin asked them.

“What?” Miss Lindenmeyer asked. “What do you mean?”

“Is this all fake? Are dreams not real?”

“Well, Benjamin, I think you're in a state where you can answer that question as best as I can. What do you think?”

“I don't know anymore,” Benjamin said distantly. “Well, that's not true. I'm pretty sure this is all fake.”

“So, if it's all fake, why don't you just go home?”

“I don't know how! King Bernard Zwirn has the key.”

“It can't be all fake, right? We dream for a reason. We don't dream fake dreams. The dreams are real.”

Benjamin thought that perhaps Miss Lindenmeyer had a point. If it was all fake, then dreaming would be pointless. And, he liked dreaming.

Rodney landed the flying machine next to Benjamin and then promptly brushed off the dust from his jacket. Even though he looked nothing like Snark, there were some characteristics that Benjamin saw in both of these creatures. Rodney was actually adventurous.

“It's been decades since I've used any of these old machines,” Rodney said. “I've been using newer models lately. It's fun to go back into time and try an old one again. These things have character, you know? They, um, don't work as well as the, uh, new ones. But they still work!”

“Benjamin,” Miss Lindenmeyer began. “We asked Noel to bring you here because we want to show you how to use more of these devices. Rodney wants to see if you can fly again.”

“You want me to fly?” Benjamin asked with concern. “I promise you that I don't know how to fly.”

“Sure,” Rodney said. “And, I can't either. Fly, that is. But perhaps under the right circumstances, you might be able to do something else.”

“With one of these machines?”

“Yes, with one of these machines. You don't have to start with the flying engine. You could try any of them.”

“This one,” Miss Lindenmeyer said, “is made for surfing a gigantic wave. You won't get wet at all but you'll be able to surf with ease.”

The machine looked like a metal basket sewn together with copper, steel, and iron. Orange lights lined the outside and blinked in a fluid dance. It looked mechanical yet organic and heavy yet light. Like all the other machines that sat next to it, it looked like someone had spent years piecing each individual component together.

“Hop on!” Rodney said with youthful enthusiasm.

“I don't know,” Benjamin said. “I'm not sure I'm ready to use these machines.”

“Oh, nonsense,” Miss Lindenmeyer said. “Once you start it up, you don't have to do anything. You just enjoy the ride.”

Benjamin looked at the machine and wondered if it would hurt him or guide him. Rodney nudged Benjamin from behind but Benjamin did not move. Miss Lindenmeyer budged him and he still held his ground. He did not want to get involved with these machines. He didn't want to sit on something that looked like a torture device.

But when both Rodney and Miss Lindenmeyer pushed Benjamin together, he fell forward into the arms of metal and lights. The machine enveloped him like a mechanical kangaroo would hold its baby. Without asking Benjamin, Rodney pushed hard on the ignition switch and Benjamin moved to an area of the production studio where the floor was beginning to separate down the middle. As the divide grew larger, waves of water passed across the floor. It was not, however, ideal for a boy who was pretty much scared of everything.

The machine touched down on the water and Benjamin could not believe what was happening. He was surfing, albeit with a lot of help. But, he was actually surfing. This was something he did not imagine was possible. And more than that, he was having fun.

He surfed for what felt like hours and then Miss Lindenmeyer told him to turn the machine off. It guided him back to Rodney and Miss Lindenmeyer who had their hands crossed and their smiles strewn from ear to ear. They looked as happy as Benjamin looked.

“Can I try another?” Benjamin asked with curiosity.

“Sure!” Rodney said. “That one will let you float in the air.”

Benjamin ran to the machine that looked like a large mechanical crow with thousands of pieces. He turned it on and then started to float throughout the room. Miss Lindenmeyer sent clouds into the air and Benjamin felt like he was experiencing something much more enjoyable than dreams. He felt like he was experiencing something magical.

“What is he doing up there!” Selma Applebaum yelled from the entrance of the production studio.

She stamped her feet as she walked to Miss Lindenmeyer. Behind her, Ryan Eden and Steven Wazen marched with their arms folded and their eyes squinted. Benjamin fell from the sky upon seeing them and landed on a soft padding.

“What are you three doing here?” Miss Lindenmeyer asked.

“I want to know why he is allowed to use these machines and I am not,” Selma protested.

“Selma, this is none of your business,” Rodney said. “You need to leave immediately.”

“We told you Benjamin was being trained to be the top student in the class,” Ryan Eden said from behind Selma.

“They don't want you to be the best anymore,” Steven Wazen said to Selma Applebaum.

Benjamin did not know what to say because he did not know if that was Miss Lindenmeyer's intentions. He saw Rodney roll his eyes and then walk back to the machines. Selma must have seen him roll his eyes as well.

“Oh stop it, Rodney,” Selma said.

Benjamin looked at her and wondered how she knew Rodney. It was impossible to know everyone in the castle.

“You always get so jealous,” Rodney said. “If dad was still around, you wouldn't barge in like that. What's your problem with Benjamin?”

Selma didn't say anything. Tears swelled in her eyes. She turned around quickly and ran from the production studio. Ryan Eden and Steven Wazen did not waste any time and chased after her. Rodney and Miss Lindenmeyer simply sighed and gave expressions of disappointment.

“You're Selma's brother?” Benjamin asked.

“Not by choice!” Rodney replied.

“Is it a choice?” Benjamin questioned.

“Well, uh, no, but, um, I'm a lot older than she is and we don't always get along. She gets so jealous. She just wants to be the best and hates when someone else might be better than her,” Rodney explained.

“She's jealous of me?”

“Yep! Listen, Benjamin,” Rodney said as he crouched down. “I'm really sorry about you learning about Snark and the dinosaurs. It was never my intention that you see me this way. I mean, look at me. I don't look courageous, confident, or brave. That's Snark. Snark is courageous, confident, and brave. I'm lanky, awkward, and different. So, I apologize and I need to help you out. It's probably the only thing I'll be able to do. And I'm not sure I can help you out other than to tell you that if you're to save yourself, you've got to dream. Actually, to save all of us, you've got to dream. Benjamin, you've got a gift.”

“A gift?”

“Yes, a gift.”

“But anyone can use these machines,” Benjamin said as he looked at the thousands of machines spread across the floor.

“That's correct,” Rodney said. “But, you are the only person we know who is able to use these machines while they are turned off.”

“But, I turned them on before I used them.”

“Nope,” Rodney said. “Every one of them was turned off. You can somehow fly on your own, surf on your own, and do whatever on your own. I don't know how you can do it. But, man, Benjamin, if someone finds you, you're going to be in so much trouble.”

“Who? Who is going to find me?”

“The person who broke the dream machine.”

Chapter 14
Hope

Benjamin feared for his safety. He walked around aimlessly thinking about what he could do. He needed to find out who was trying to hurt him. He needed to figure out what happened to King Bernard Zwirn. He needed to know why Rodney Cohen and Miss Lindenmeyer believed he had a gift. And, he needed to know why Selma was so jealous of him.

“Why are you walking back and forth like that?” Benjamin heard the familiar voice of Selma shouting from down the hallway. He was so lost in his thoughts that he completely ignored her voice. There was too much to think about. “I said, where are you going?” she shouted again.

Selma walked to Benjamin and stood in his path. But, Benjamin didn't stop. He continued to pace back and forth. It was like there was nothing else around him.

“Are you deaf?” she said. “I asked why you are walking back and forth.”

“I'm trying to figure out what to do,” Benjamin declared. He turned and continued to walk past her.

Selma followed his pacing and laughed lightly to herself as she did so.

“And what exactly are you trying to figure out?” she asked.

“I haven't figured it out,” Benjamin said honestly. “I need to know who is trying to get me.”

Selma laughed again.

“I need to know where King Bernard Zwirn is.”

Selma nodded her head with approval.

“I need to know why I have a gift.”

Selma let out a disgusted expression of disapproval. At that moment, Benjamin stopped.

“And, I need to know why you're jealous of me.”

Selma stopped walking after him and she let out a loud gasp. He noticed that she was not happy with his observation.

“I am not jealous of you.”

“You definitely are.”

“I am most certainly not!”

Benjamin could see that Selma was becoming uncomfortable. She laughed like she was trying to conceal her discomfort. Benjamin tried to change the subject.

“In any case, it's just one of many things I have to figure out.”

Selma would not let him change the subject so easily.

“Wait a second! I am not jealous of you, Benjamin.”

“OK,” Benjamin said as he walked past her.

“Why would you think I would be jealous of you?”

“Like I said, I don't know. I've got to figure that out.”

“But there's nothing to figure out. I'm not jealous of you!”

“You might be right.”

“I am definitely right.”

“But what if you're wrong?”

“How can I be wrong? I just told you I'm not jealous of you!”

“You could be lying to me.”

“This is a ridiculous conversation. I am not jealous of anyone!”

“You're probably right. But, I still need to know why you were upset that I was using the machines.”

“There's nothing to figure out! There's nothing there, Benjamin.”

“I mean, it's not the top thing on my list. I've got to figure out who might want to hurt me. That's definitely the top thing on my list.”

“So you wouldn't care if I was jealous of you then?”

“But, you aren't. You said so.”

“Right, but if I was?”

“Well, I still would rather know who is trying to kill me before I figured out why you're so jealous.”

“I'm not jealous!”

“So, we're on the same page.”

Selma stumped on the ground and let out a loud, long sigh. She flung her arms in the air, spun around in place, and then marched away from Benjamin. Benjamin watched her walk down the hallway. At the very end, she turned to look at him and let out another loud, long sigh of frustration. Benjamin didn't understand why she acted the way she did.

After Benjamin was done pacing for the day, he went outside to try to find Rodney Cohen. He needed to ask Rodney if the dinosaurs could help him find King Bernard Zwirn. As he walked around the castle, people brushed by him from every direction as they walked about their day. Some walked to the production studios, some walked to the market, and some walked to the restaurants and bakeries that had opened only an hour earlier. It was a little chillier than usual that morning but it had been colder in general since King Bernard Zwirn's disappearance.

He marched forward to the gate on the other side of the town that led to somewhere else. He walked past the school, past the dream machine, and past the train station. And as he passed the train station, he closed his eyes as he realized that the building looked no different than any of the other production studios. As he wondered why the train station looked similar to all of the other production studios, a hand grabbed his shoulder.

“So,” Ryan Wazen said without pausing for a second. “Could you fly?”

“Could I fly?” Benjamin asked. He was confused why Ryan Wazen was being a little more aggressive than usual. “No, I couldn't fly,” he lied. “Flying is impossible.”

“Of course,” Ryan said. “Flying is impossible but that doesn't answer my question.”

“It's a silly question.”

“No, it's not. Could you fly?”

“Of course I couldn't fly,” Benjamin lied for the second time. “No one can fly.”

“People can fly but if you can't, I guess that's a shame. Miss Lindenmeyer was wrong about that kind of stuff before. Don't take it too hard, kid.”

“What do you mean by before?”

“About kids that she thinks can fly. They usually can't. Some of them could, I was told. But, we never saw them again.”

“Where do they go?”

“Wouldn't you like to know,” Ryan said as he started to walk backwards from Benjamin. “You don't have to worry about it because you can't fly. Don't ask questions you don't want to know the answer to. That's what my dad always told me.”

Ryan ran off and Benjamin tried to follow him but he was too fast. Benjamin did not have a good feeling about Ryan. There was something that he didn't know about him. Ryan had a secret, Benjamin thought.

Benjamin stared at the castle walls for a period of time and wondered what was on the other side. He wondered if there were answers to where King Bernard Zwirn was outside the walls. He walked to a gate, deciding that he needed more information. Guarding the gate were two men who looked identical to Noel Jaffin. They both had the same box-shaped figure and short stature. Benjamin thought that if they did not let him pass, he might be able to quite easily topple them over.

“Stop!” the guards yelled in unison. “You shall not pass!”

“What?” Benjamin asked.

“If you pass—”

“I heard what you said,” Benjamin responded. “I didn't quite expect you to say that. I'm leaving, Noel, so I would appreciate if you would open the gate.”

“Who is Noel?” asked one of the guards as he stamped his wooden pole into the ground.

“Are you Noel?” the other guard asked the previous one.

“I'm not Noel. I'm Joel. Are you Noel?” Joel asked the other guard.

“I'm not Noel. I'm Cole. Haven't we met?” Cole asked Joel.

“I guess not.”

“We stand here every day and we've never introduced ourselves.”

“It's nice to meet you,” Joel said to Cole.

“Same!” Cole said he shook Joel's hand.

“But you shall not pass unless you are gas!” Joel and Cole yelled at Benjamin in unison.

“I don't think you realize what you're saying,” Benjamin said as he tried not to giggle.

“The only way you're getting through us is if you're gas,” Joel said sternly.

“Yes, I know but you're saying—” Benjamin began.

“You shall only pass if you're gas,” Cole repeated.

“OK, I need to leave,” Benjamin said.

“No!” they yelled back in unison. “No one leaves!”

Benjamin thought about this statement for a moment. Did he mean anything to anyone in the castle? Was he someone? Or, was he no one? He wasn't sure.

“I am no one. Can I leave?”

Cole and Joel looked at each other with a puzzled expression. They looked as if they were pondering something their brains were not capable of understanding.

“Well, this is interesting,” Cole said to Joel.

“Interesting indeed,” Joel said to Cole.

“Could this be the no one that is allowed to leave?”

“It's quite possible that if no one is allowed to leave and this child before us is no one, he could leave.”

“That seems right to me as well but how do we know that he is no one?”

“He just said he was no one.”

“Ah, right. But would no one lie?”

“Good point, Joel! No one tells the truth all the time.”

“So then, no one is a liar.”

“This child is no one the liar.”

“No one, you shall not pass!” they yelled in unison.

“Is there another gate?” Benjamin asked. He did not want to have to deal with Joel and Cole any longer. He was getting a headache.

“Of course, there are four more,” Cole said as he stamped his wooden pole back into the ground.

“There are four more!” Joel said with surprise.

“I really think we need a better onboarding process,” Cole said. “I don't know who guards those gates.”

“Me neither!”

Benjamin walked along the walls at a quick speed to find another gate. He did not want to have to deal with Joel or Cole if he could find another exit.

“Good luck, no one,” Cole cried out after Benjamin.

Benjamin walked between the castle walls and the back of small houses and production studios. It was a narrow alley that felt neglected compared to the rest of the clean town. It was muddy and there were bits of garbage tossed throughout. It made sense, he thought, because no one walked along this path. As Benjamin walked further, he wondered if the only people who would traverse this disgusting, claustrophobic path were the guards who tended the gate.

He had been walking for a good period of time and did not yet see another gate. The curved walls of the castle made him think the he might walk a full circle to see Joel and Cole again.

His left foot stepped into wet mud and sunk into the ground. He quickly moved his right foot to a rock and tried to pull his other foot forward. It was gross and Benjamin knew that he would have to throw his shoes away after this was all done. It made a loud squishy noise like the sound he made when he tried to vacuum the water out of the bathtub when he was six.

It started to make him laugh.

And, he would have continued to laugh except that he heard another familiar voice.

“But, what if I don't want to,” Benjamin heard Ryan Eden say. “I'm not as good as the others.”

“It doesn't matter if you're stronger or better than the others,” Benjamin heard Thalia Nachamie say. “You are my son and you will follow in my footsteps. No other person or child is going to get in your or my way. Do you understand?”

Benjamin crouched as low as he could to the mud as he realized the noise was coming from the house immediately to his left.

“I understand, father. I'll follow in your footsteps.”

“I've already paved the path for you. Selma has been taken care of. She'll be seeing King Bernard Zwirn, shortly. You won't be seeing him again and there is no chance that he'll get in our way,” Thalia Nachamie said.

Benjamin's heart sank as he wondered what had happened to Selma. He had just seen her. He no longer wanted to leave the castle. He needed to find her.

“What about Selma?” Ryan Eden asked his father.

“You won't have to worry about Selma,” Thalia Nachamie said. “Soon, I'll be king. And then, you'll be king. This is a glorious time for us.”

“It is, father,” Ryan Eden said.

“Now, run along,” Thalia Nachamie said. “I need to have a meeting with our leader.”

“Is he ready to invade?” Ryan Eden said.

“Yes,” Thalia Nachamie said. “All of our plans are working perfectly.”

An invasion? Benjamin started to panic. He kept his little body as close to the wet, sticky mud as possible so that he could avoid being seen. His hands felt clammy. His breathing became heavy. He need to find Selma. Ryan Eden shut the door as he left the room and Benjamin wanted to run away. But if he did so, Thalia Nachamie would see him. He needed a distraction so that he could escape and get help. He needed to tell Selma that an invasion was coming.

But suddenly, the sky turned as black as night. Tornado winds blew Benjamin against a wall. Dust and dirt filled the air as something massive smashed to the ground. Benjamin couldn't see and for a moment, he couldn't hear. The explosion was so loud that his ears rang for minutes. The moment reminded him of what he saw from the classroom window when day turned into night. Something evil had arrived.

“Thalia!” a loud voice echoed from within the room where Thalia Nachamie and Ryan Eden had been talking. “Have you executed my orders?”

“Yes, Aloysius,” Thalia Nachamie said. “I'm ready for your invasion.”

“Great,” the menacing voice said. “Do not let me down this time. Do you understand me?”

“Yes, master,” Thalia Nachamie said. “I won't let you down.”

“Have you taken care of the children?”

“Don't worry,” Thalia Nachamie said. “It's all taken care of.”

“If you mess this up, Thalia, you won't be given another chance.”

“I understand, master. Thank you for giving me another chance. I'll make sure you control the castle this time.”

Another explosion made Benjamin's ears ring and dust flew back into the air. Within seconds, daylight had been restored. Aloysius had left. Benjamin sat with his back against the wall and slowed his breathing to try to stay calm. It was hard. He never felt so scared in his life. He listened to Thalia Nachamie slam a door shut. And without waiting another moment, Benjamin sprinted along his escape route. The castle walls moved so quickly that he wondered if he could run this fast forever. He wanted to find help. He wanted to find safety. He wanted to be as far away from Thalia Nachamie as possible. But as he ran faster, he then ran straight through someone. The collision felt like the collision he had when he was younger and accidentally ran into the basketball pole at home.

“Benjamin! I'm so glad I found you. I thought you were lost,” Noel Jaffin yelled at Benjamin.

“Noel, is that you?”

“Benjamin! What is wrong with you?”

Noel had been knocked over like a beanbag chair thrown down a staircase.

“Noel, is that really you?”

“Yes, Benjamin. It is I, Noel. Who else would it be?” Noel said. “Now, would you mind telling me why you ran me over?”

“Noel, Selma! Where is she?”

Noel's expression changed and he looked from side to side quickly. He lowered his tone.

“We can't talk about that here, Benjamin,” Noel said. “She's missing.”

“Missing!” Benjamin yelled.

“It's not good,” Noel said as he lowered his head.

Benjamin's heart sank.

“How? Where?” Benjamin yelled.

“Quiet! Quiet!” Noel whispered. “Yes, you're in a lot of danger. It's good I ran into you. I wish you didn't run into me. But, I need you to wait here. I parked my car on the other side of the market. I'll be right here in five minutes. Do not move a muscle, OK?”

Benjamin nodded as he looked at the hundreds of people moving throughout the marketplace. Noel disappeared into the crowd and Benjamin decided that he could trust the guard. He couldn't leave just yet, he thought. He needed to make sure he was going to be safe.

As Benjamin waited, he scanned the people in the marketplace and recognized a face. Benjamin retreated into the shadow so that he could not be seen. It was Russell Fox.

Russell Fox was walking very suspiciously. He was wearing a long dark jacket and had both his hands in his pocket as he moved from market shop to market shop. Benjamin watched him very carefully because he knew Russell Fox was trouble. As Russell Fox turned in place, Benjamin got a glimpse of something metal that Russell Fox held in his right hand. And then, the evil man walked to a stand covered in oranges and stood there for a few minutes. Something was very wrong, Benjamin thought. Russell Fox then stuck his right hand in the middle of the oranges and walked away quickly, in the opposite direction of Benjamin. And as he walked away, Benjamin noticed the metal piece was no longer in his pocket.

As soon as Russell Fox faded into the crowded, Benjamin moved quickly through the crowd to the gigantic stack of oranges. He put his hand into the oranges as the shopkeeper stared at him with an annoyed expression. Benjamin tried to be calm about it. He tried to find the place where Russell Fox placed his hand.

Then, he felt something metal.

He grabbed it and waited for the shopkeeper to be distracted by another customer. Benjamin removed it quickly and put it in his pocket.

He knew exactly what it was.

Chapter 15
Blamed

“Noel!” Benjamin yelled as Noel Jaffin drove a vehicle only slightly larger than his body to Benjamin. His car looked like a square, metal box in which Noel occupied just about the entire space. Once he parked, he leveraged all of his weight to get out of the vehicle like an elephant trying to squeeze itself out of a refrigerator.

“What is it, Benjamin?” a sweaty Noel answered as he brushed the dust from his pants.

“Noel, I found something that could help me and help Castle Ehtahl and probably get King Bernard Zwirn and Selma back,” Benjamin said as he gripped the missing piece in his pocket. He didn't know what it could do. But, he thought the dream machine would transform the castle and drive away the nightmares once again.

“Right. Right. I've heard this before. Let's just get you to the police station so we can figure out what to do with you next.”

“You don't understand. This could answer all of our problems. The mystery of the missing piece of the dream machine is over,” Benjamin said as he opened his hand to reveal the missing object.

Noel did not look convinced. He crossed his arms and tightened his lips, ultimately ending his bored performance with a heavy sigh. He picked the piece from Benjamin's hand and inspected it from every angle.

“This is scrap,” he said as he tossed it over his shoulder.

Benjamin ran after it and caught it before it hit the ground. If the missing piece broke, then the dream machine certainly would not work.

“Noel, this is the missing piece. We can put it in the dream machine and it'll start working again.”

“How are you so sure? This is scrap metal. This doesn't mean anything.”

“Can't we at least try?”

“Try what?” Steven Wazen said from behind Benjamin.

Benjamin did not know how long Steven Wazen had been standing behind him or how much he had heard. At that moment, Benjamin wanted to focus only on getting this metal component into the dream machine. He was worried that Steven Wazen might distract from this goal.

“Nothing, Steven,” Noel Jaffin said in response. “Just another person among hundreds of thousands thinking they are special enough to have found the missing piece of the dream machine.”

“He thinks he's found the missing piece to the dream machine?” Steven Wazen asked as he stood immediately next to Benjamin. He had a skeptical expression that made Benjamin's stomach clench. “How long have you had it?”

“How long have I have it?” Benjamin asked with a startle. “I've only just found it. I found it in the market. We have to see if it fits because this could answer all of our problems.”

“Can I see it?” Steven Wazen asked.

Benjamin paused. He did not want to give it to anyone else after having watched Noel Jaffin carelessly toss it over his shoulder.

“Come on,” Steven Wazen continued. “Let me see it.”

Benjamin stared into Steven Wazen's eyes and then glanced at the ground. Before he could hide the piece, Noel Jaffin let out a loud groan and yanked it from Benjamin's hands.

“I don't understand kids these days,” Noel Jaffin said to himself as he gave Steven Wazen the component. “Here. Here is the scrap metal.”

Steven Wazen inspected it in exactly the same way Noel Jaffin had just examined it. But unlike Noel Jaffin, Steven Wazen's expression became more and more intrigued and curious. It was as if he was understanding something that Benjamin could not see.

“It's scrap metal,” Steven Wazen said quickly.

“I knew it,” Noel Jaffin said. “Now, Benjamin, let's get a move on.”

“Can I have it back?” Benjamin asked Steven Wazen who still held the metal piece.

“I'll dispose of it for you,” Steven Wazen said as he put it in his pocket and quickly ran away.

“There,” Noel Jaffin said. “That was really nice of him to offer to get rid of it for you.”

Benjamin was upset. He wanted to run after Steven Wazen but the boy had already become hidden by the crowd in the marketplace.

“Noel, that was the missing piece!” Benjamin said in complete disbelief. “He took the missing piece for the dream machine!”

“It's scrap metal, Benjamin. You're not the first person to claim to have found the missing piece. You're actually the seventeenth person who claims to have found one today. Or, eighteenth. I'm not sure. The sooner we get you to the station, the sooner we'll know what number you are,” Noel Jaffin said as he ushered Benjamin to the small car. “Now, we're going to both fit inside here. You get in first.”

Benjamin looked at Noel Jaffin with disapproval. There was no room for anyone else in this car once Noel Jaffin was inside it.

It was the most uncomfortable car ride that Benjamin had ever experienced, his face squashed between the window and Noel Jaffin's hot, squishy belly. His legs were on top of each other and he couldn't move his arms. When they arrived in the station's parking lot, Benjamin felt like his body had been damaged in every place. It was excruciating and upon seeing Rodney Cohen at the station, embarrassing.

“What are you doing here?” Benjamin asked Rodney as he tried to straighten himself out.

“I was arrested,” Rodney said with a laugh.

“Really?” Benjamin asked.

“No,” he said. “I'm looking for my sister.”

“Noel told me she's missing.”

“She is,” Rodney replied. “Noel asked me to stop in the station to talk to some of the other guards.”

“Do you know where she is? ”

“No,” he said. “But, I have a good idea who is responsible for this.”

“Who?”

“For your own safety, you should hide. Thalia Nachamie might try to kick you out of the castle or have you kidnapped like Selma's been kidnapped.”

“What's outside the castle? Selma was kidnapped?” Benjamin exclaimed.

“I think so. Benjamin, she likes you a lot. It may not seem that way but she can't stop talking about you. If you hear from her, please let me know that she's fine. And whatever you do, don't leave the castle. It's not safe out there.”

“Benjamin,” Noel Jaffin called from his office on the other end of the station. “Get in here.”

“See you later, Benjamin,” Rodney said as he left the station.

“Rodney, wait! I forgot to tell you—” he started to say but it was too late. He should have mentioned what he found.

Benjamin walked along the blue carpet lined with yellow desks and cubicles until he reached Noel Jaffin's office. The room was, sadly, only slightly larger than Noel Jaffin himself. Benjamin paused at the door, let out a large sigh, and then squeezed his way between a small space between the desk and a wall. There was only a little bit more room than there was in the car. Benjamin and Noel Jaffin sat face to face, only inches away from touching.

It was uncomfortable.

“Benjamin, we've got to find a way to hide you for a bit,” Noel Jaffin said.

Benjamin wanted to end this conversation as fast as possible so that he could leave the office.

“Sure, OK. Let's do it,” Benjamin said quickly.

“Alright, so I'll just arrest you and we'll put you in a jail cell for the time being. No one is going to bother you there.”

“Wait. Arrest me?”

“Yep, I'll arrest you for assault or something. I'll tell people you hit me. Ouch!” Noel Jaffin said with a hearty chuckle. Benjamin could feel the heat of the laugh on his face. It was disgusting.

“Can't you just put me in a jail cell?” Benjamin asked. He couldn't believe he asked the question because he did not want to be in a jail cell at all. There must be a better option, he thought.

“No, no, no,” Noel Jaffin said while shaking his head. With each turn of his neck, Noel Jaffin almost hit Benjamin with his nose. “We can't put innocent people in the jail cells.”

“But, I am innocent.”

“Yes, but that's why I said I would tell people who you assaulted me.”

“But, I haven't assaulted you.”

“That's true. OK, hit me.”

“What?”

“Hit me,” Noel Jaffin said as he squinted his eyes and lifted his shoulders in preparation of Benjamin hitting him.

“I'm not going to hit you!”

“Hit me!”

“No!”

“Do it!”

“No!”

“Punch me in the face!”

Benjamin wanted to punch Noel Jaffin in the face. But, he knew he couldn't do it. If he went to jail for a crime that he did in fact commit, he would be in even more trouble than he was now.

“No, I won't!”

“Fine,” Noel Jaffin said as he opened his eyes and relaxed his body. “I'll just tell people you punched me in the face.”

“But, I didn't. Can't you put me somewhere other than a jail cell?”

“There is no other place in this castle that is as safe and secure as our jail cells. No one will bother you there. The only other place is the zoo but I don't think you'll like it there.”

“There's a zoo?” Benjamin asked with curiosity.

“Yes, it's over—” Noel Jaffin began to say until a woman twice Noel Jaffin's size entered the doorway.

Benjamin swallowed hard. There was no more space in this office. He would be crushed if she wanted to sit inside the room as well.

“Noel, may I have a word with you?” the enormous square woman said.

“Yes, boss, sure,” Noel Jaffin said to her. “Stay here, Benjamin.”

Noel Jaffin squeezed his way out of the office, crushing Benjamin between the desk and the wall. His body had not endured so much torture as it had from this large man in such small environments. Benjamin breathed heavily in an attempt to get his body back in order. The office walls had pictures and books that had been squashed like flies against white paint. A plant looked like it was flattened against the window and Noel Jaffin's chair looked like it had been through several battles. It was losing the war against Noel Jaffin's weight.

“Benjamin,” Noel Jaffin said as he reentered the doorway. “We have to go for a castle meeting.”

“OK, I'll be here,” Benjamin said.

“No, you're coming along.”

“Are you sure that's a good idea?”

“No, but I need to keep an eye on you.”

They walked to the plaza and as they approached, Benjamin saw the entire castle's population standing and sitting around while some workers scrambled to erect screens and speakers. Noel Jaffin did not have the same expression of worry that Miss Lindenmeyer had the last time Benjamin was here. Instead, he kept looking at his watch while shuffling a candy bar in his other hand.

“What is this for?” Benjamin asked.

“I don't know exactly,” Noel Jaffin replied. “But, it better not get in the way of lunch.”

“When is lunch?”

“When isn't it lunch?” Noel Jaffin said with a hearty laugh. “Twenty minutes. Lunch is in twenty minutes.”

Benjamin looked around the audience for someone he knew but like last time, did not see anyone. There was no Miss Lindenmeyer. No Rodney Cohen. No Selma Applebaum. And, no Steven Wazen or Ryan Eden.

Rather, there were strangers everywhere. And in unison, those strangers stood and jumped with excitement. A roar of cheers waved across the people as Benjamin looked to the balcony to see who was going to appear.

It was Thalia Nachamie. Benjamin expected him. Who else would it be?

But then, two more people stepped onto the balcony. Benjamin did not expect to see them. His heart slowed with a little worry.

It was Ryan Eden.

And behind Ryan Eden, it was Steven Wazen.

“What are they doing up there?” Benjamin muttered to himself.

“Quiet,” Noel Jaffin said as he nudged Benjamin. “We're going to find out if they've found King Bernard Zwirn.”

“What do you mean? They wouldn't find King Bernard Zwirn. They're the reason King Bernard Zwirn is missing!”

“Quiet! Quiet!”

Thalia Nachamie hit his hand against the microphone three times, causing all of the speakers around the audience to pop in response. He leaned forward and with his long, crane-like nose hooking over the microphone began to speak.

“We have not found our beloved King Bernard Zwirn,” Thalia Nachamie said to the cries of the audience below. “But, our efforts are not in vain. We are continuing to search for him. We search in the night. We search in the day. We are searching all the time. And so, it is with my deep regret that I must inform all of you that the time has come to move on. We cannot keep searching for King Bernard Zwirn forever. It is with great courage that I tell you today that I must be made interim regent. It is not by my choosing, of course. It is to make sure that dreams are available to all that go to sleep at night. You see, without a king, this castle does not have a leader. And without a leader, there are no dreams. And, I must be that leader. Today, I present myself, King Thalia Nachamie, the leader of Castle Ehtahl.”

As Thalia Nachamie stopped talking, the crowd remained silent for a few seconds until Russell Fox began to clap. When Russell Fox clapped, people around him started to clap. And then, people around those people started to clap. And this persisted until the entire audience was clapping for Thalia Nachamie, their new king.

“My followers, I want to let you know that even though I am now King, that does not mean that we will stop looking for Bernard Zwirn. In fact, it is quite important that we continue searching for our friend. But good people, there is one person among all of you who is hindering our progress. There is one person among all of you who does not want us to find Bernard Zwirn. There is one person who is trying to steal from us.”

Gasps and whispers spread throughout the audience. Even Benjamin wondered what Thalia Nachamie was alluding to. If anyone was in the way of searching for King Bernard Zwirn, Benjamin thought, it was Thalia Nachamie.

“Only this morning, I was made aware of this.”

Thalia Nachamie turned around and Ryan Eden handed his father the missing piece of the dream machine that Benjamin had only hours earlier given away.

“That's the piece,” Benjamin told Noel Jaffin.

“The what?” Noel asked as he looked at his watch again.

“That's the missing piece of the dream machine that you said was scrap metal.”

“It was scrap metal.”

“It wasn't!”

“It looked like any scrap metal I've ever seen.”

Noel Jaffin looked forward, squinting his eyes to see what Thalia Nachamie was holding.

“There is someone in this audience who had the missing piece of the dream machine all along,” Thalia Nachamie's voice echoed through the plaza. “This person did not want us to have it. This person kept it from all of us. This person kept it from you. He wanted to keep it for himself. He wanted to make sure the dream machine never worked.”

“That was Russell Fox,” Benjamin whispered to Noel Jaffin. “That's who I saw put it in the market stand.”

“Shh, quiet down,” Noel Jaffin said to Benjamin. “I may have to make an arrest.”

“Someone in our castle is preventing us from making dreams. Someone has been putting us through turmoil all along. Someone wants to stop us from dreaming.”

The audience stirred.

“But my followers, I am proud to say that we have identified the person. And, we are going to exile him from our castle. He is no longer welcomed here and we will not have him among us any more.”

Cheers and applause echoed throughout the plaza. Benjamin strained his neck to see where Russell Fox was, but he was not standing in the same location as he was before. Benjamin looked everywhere to find the thief.

“That person will be punished! We will get back our dreams!”

The crowd screamed loudly.

“He will be removed! We will be stronger than ever!”

The crowd raised their fists in the air.

“He is no longer welcome here!” Thalia Nachamie raised his fist into the air as he finished each sentence. “We are going to be more powerful than ever!”

The crowd cheered. Benjamin swallowed hard.

“Benjamin Buckingham, I banish you from Castle Ehtahl!”

Chapter 16
Banished

Benjamin felt a wave of worry surge through his body like a breeze blowing through a wind tunnel. He could not leave, he thought to himself, because he did not know where he would go. He knew where he was and that, he believed, was better than not knowing where he could be. Without anyone he trusted around him, he felt isolated, alone, and vulnerable. He felt feelings he knew from school, feelings that did not make him happy, feelings from which he wanted to flee.

“Are you OK?” Noel Jaffin said.

“I'm OK,” Benjamin answered.

“You're pale white.”

“Well, I suppose I am.”

“Like white white.”

“I get it.”

“It's just that I've never seen someone so white and be OK. Are you sure you're OK? You look like you've seen a ghost.”

Benjamin thought about all of the ghosts he had battled in his dreams with his dinosaur friends. He was never fearful of the ghosts. He never turned pale white or white white or confused or worried or scared. With his friends, he had all the confidence he needed to stand up to evil. But without any friends, he had nothing.

“I'm going outside,” Benjamin stuttered.

“Yup.”

“Yup?”

“Oh, yeah, no, sorry, I mean,” Noel said. “You'll probably be fine.”

“I'll probably be fine?”

“Well, what do you want me to say?”

“I don't know! Lie to me!”

“It'll probably be a wonderful experience.”

“A wonderful experience? Are you insane?”

“It might be!”

“Or it might not!”

“Well, if you have those expectations—”

“Noel, can't you help me?”

“I don't know what to do Benjamin. I can find Miss Lindenmeyer but you're about to be banished. There's really no time! I could—”

He couldn't finish his sentence because Thalia Nachamie began to shout above everyone once again. He moved his head from side to side like a bird perched on top of a tree, staring at everyone below him like they were mice in a farm field. And all Benjamin could do was try to hide behind the other mice.

“Benjamin Buckingham,” Thalia Nachamie walked to the castle doors. “You are hereby banished from this castle and you are never to return.”

Thalia Nachamie emphasized what he said by thrusting his clenched fist forward and spitting after every word. Benjamin felt like he was being verbally and physically attacked. He could not imagine how he could escape.

“Do you understand me?” Thalia Nachamie stared deep inside Benjamin's eyes.

Benjamin nodded meekly. He wanted it to stop. He wanted to wake up in his bed and for all of this to end peacefully. He wanted to be rescued. He wanted Snark.

“You shall never return!”

“OK.”

“You shall not be welcome back.”

“OK.”

“You shall live forever with nightmares.”

“Nightmares?”

“Leave! Now!”

Thalia Nachamie turned to the guards standing behind him. Joel and Cole turned a steel wheel as quickly as their short bodies could turn something much larger than they. The wheel was nearly double their size and as one of the guards pulled, another was lifted up into the air.

Joel and Cole opened the door nearly halfway when Thalia Nachamie motioned for them to stop. The guards were dripping in sweat and breathing like dogs that had chased tennis balls for hours. Thalia Nachamie had decided that there was enough room for Benjamin to exit.

Then, all of the people in the plaza turned their heads and stared at Benjamin like sunflowers looking toward the sun. He had never had such attention in his life as he had at that moment. He was the most popular person in the castle and he felt like he was the least liked.

“Be gone with you!” Thalia Nachamie yelled as he pushed Benjamin through the door. “Don't ever come back!”

Behind him, the guards trampled on top of each other to close the door. Benjamin listened to the straining metal as it whined in pain. When it was finally closed, it let out a short thud.

And then, Benjamin heard applause and cheering that sounded as loud as the noises he heard when that dragon was captured. The plaza of people erupted in happiness and excitement at the expense of Benjamin's feelings. This hurt his heart. He did not want to be hated. No one wanted to be hated. But Benjamin especially did not want to be hated.

Maybe Noel was right, he thought. But as he looked at the area outside the castle, he did not know where to go. It was not as bright and lovely and beautiful as he had hoped. Instead, it was a desert as empty as a school in the middle of summer.

There wasn't a living plant as far as Benjamin could see. There was no water and no sign of any animals. There was just dirt and cracks and the sound of the sun baking the earth.

Benjamin was left to himself and his thoughts.

“Incoming!” Benjamin heard a familiar male voice yell from behind the walls.

Benjamin turned and watched something in the sky heading in his direction. When it hit the ground, he saw it was a backpack. He ran over to it and opened it up to find bottles of water. What would he do with so many arrows, he thought.

“Again!” Benjamin heard the same male voice yell.

In the sky, another object headed straight for Benjamin. He ducked away as quickly as he could. This object, he realized, was a book entitled A Guide To Plants Outside The Castle Not That You'll Ever Need This Because Everyone Stays In The Castle But If You Do Here's A Book For That, I Guess.

Benjamin chuckled.

And with that, he was on his own. He turned and walked into the desert as alone as a person could be. He took five steps and readied himself for whatever awaited him.

“Thanks, Noel,” he whispered.

Chapter 17
Squirrel

Benjamin reached into the backpack for some water. The desert was unforgiving and not a place for relaxation. He returned the water bottle and upon doing so, realized that there was a piece of paper at the bottom of the bag. He took it out and saw that it was a crudely drawn map. In large letters in the lower right hand corner was the name Selma.

The castle was in the center. To the north of the castle was a forest. To the south were the words don't go here! and to the east were the words you'll die here! and to the west were the words worse than the other two!

Benjamin decided that he would walk to the forest but he didn't see a forest anywhere. He didn't know which direction he was walking any longer.

As Benjamin pondered where to go, he heard a faint noise behind him. He squinted his eyes but could not see what was making the commotion. It sounded like an air conditioner getting louder and louder and louder. Benjamin squinted more and noticed a trail of dust being sent into the air by something moving quickly along the land.

It was coming right at him.

Benjamin picked up the backpack and ran as fast as he could away from it.

The humming noise was getting louder and the trail of dust was getting closer. Benjamin ran faster but he could not run fast enough. The sound was beginning to take the shape of a siren like a police car racing down a highway. Something was going to run him over. Benjamin crouched to the ground and braced himself for impact.

“North! North! North!” yelled a squirrel as tall as Benjamin's waist. “North! North! North! North!”

Benjamin opened his left eye and saw the squirrel sprint off as dust and dirt flew into the air. He had never seen a squirrel move as fast as that squirrel had moved. He had never seen a squirrel that gigantic before. He also had never heard a squirrel speak.

“Wait! Wait!” Benjamin yelled to it.

“North! North! North! North!” the squirrel kept yelling in the distance.

Benjamin ran in the same direction but could not maintain the same speed as the squirrel. It was as if the squirrel had an engine that could make it run ten times faster than it could naturally run. At least, Benjamin thought, he now knew where north was. He walked forward and hummed to himself along the way. He thought about how happy he was to not be in school and he thought about what Jupiter might be doing. And after a few hours of deep thinking, Benjamin saw the forest on the horizon.

The forest seemed to be as wide as Benjamin could see. And on the edge of the desert, about a hundred feet from the start of the forest, was a wooden stand with a large sign at the top that read Information Desk. There was nothing else out here. He approached the stand and saw that there were maps, brochures, and even coupons for a variety of discounts.

On top of the counter was a silver bell with a note that read: ring for assistance. Benjamin certainly needed assistance. So, he rang the bell.

The leaves of the forest swayed as if a wide wind had swept across the land. The trunks of the trees moved back and forth while the foliage on the ground moved into the air.

“Why hello there!” Benjamin heard a voice but he could not see the speaker.

“Hello?” Benjamin asked.

“Hello there! How are you?” the voice said again. It was loud enough to be a person but Benjamin could not see who was speaking.

“Hello? How are you? Where are you?” Benjamin asked as he strained his head to look around and around.

“I'm right here! How are you?”

“I'm good. How are you? Right where?”

“Here!”

“Where is here?”

“Here? This is the forest!”

“No, where are you? Right now, where are you?”

“Oh, I'm on the information desk. Welcome to the information desk! The information desk in the forest! I don't get many visitors but that does not mean I am not well trained in the art of customer service.”

Benjamin looked at the desk and saw the smallest green caterpillar he had ever seen. It was so small that it was hardly visible. It was standing on its end and speaking to him through a loudspeaker.

“You're a caterpillar!” Benjamin said in surprise.

“You're a human!” the caterpillar responded in mock surprise.

“You're the smallest caterpillar I've ever seen!”

“You're the most observant person I've ever seen!”

“And you can talk?” Benjamin asked.

“And you can talk?” the caterpillar responded again.

“Well, I've never heard a caterpillar talk before.”

“Trust me, son. You're going to see some things you've never seen before out here.”

“Out here? I'm sure of that.”

“Yes, outside the castles.”

“How many more castles are there?”

“Oh, my. You can't be from here. You've got so many questions. Where are you from if you don't mind my asking?”

“Pennsylvania,” Benjamin said quickly. The caterpillar's green face turned white and the leaves stopped swaying and the tree trunks stopped shaking. Everything had come to a standstill. “Why does everyone react this way when I say I'm from Pennsylvania.”

“Sh! Sh!” the caterpillar yelled as it held its finger to its lips. “Don't be so loud!”

“But—”

“Listen just because you're from Pennsylvania doesn't mean you have to tell people you're from Pennsylvania.”

“But—”

“OK, so you're from Pennsylvania. What in the universe of dreams are you doing here?” the caterpillar had its hands on its hips and was tapping its right feet on the ground.

“I am trying to leave. I'm trying to go back to Pennsylvania.”

“Sh! Sh!” the caterpillar hushed Benjamin. “OK, OK. That makes sense. Why do you want to leave?”

“Well, I don't want to leave. And, I can't really. You see a king was kidnapped along with my friend, Selma. And, I need to find them. If I find them, I'll get to go home. So, I want to go home but I need to find the king to do so.”

“Yeesh, this is getting complicated. How did you ever get here in the first place?”

Benjamin began to open his mouth to explain.

“You know what?” the caterpillar quickly responded. “It's probably best if I don't know about it. What is your name?”

“My name is Benjamin.”

“Benjamin, it's a pleasure to meet you. My name is Myrna Delacourte. Now let me see here,” Myrna said as she rummaged through the brochures and informational papers properly organized in the information stand. “Forest. Forest. Forest. Going north. Things not to eat. Things to eat. Things best left untouched. Sorry, Benjamin. I don't have any information guides for getting to Pennsylvania.”

“I don't need a guide for getting to Pennsylvania. I need a guide to leave here for Aloysius Trenhaile's castle.”

Everything around Benjamin went silent. Myrna Delacourte's eyes were as large as the rest of her body. She dropped the brochures. It seemed, Benjamin thought, that people outside Castle Ehtahl spoke of Aloysius Trenhaile exactly as people inside the castle did.

“Well,” Myrna responded with shock. “I hope you never say that name again. I don't think you want to go there. Here. Here. Here. Let me show you some wonderful brochures about the forest. This may not be the cleanest or the coolest or the hippest or the healthiest place but it is not the worst, either! What is that you have there? There! In your hand? What is that?”

“Oh, it's a map.”

“Let me see it.”

“I'm sure your maps are better.”

“Well, I love seeing other cartographers' works!”

Myrna put on a pair of glasses and made disapproving facial expressions at the map.

“Well,” Myrna said as she folded the map and returned it to Benjamin. “This is certainly drawn by someone who has been out here before. It doesn't have all of the details but it certainly has enough information to get you here, to me. You're lucky to have found this place to begin with. How did you know which way was north?”

“A squirrel ran by screaming north! North!”

“Oh, that noisy squirrel!” Myrna said between her teeth. “He's so loud.”

“How is it that you and a squirrel can talk?”

“How is it that you can talk?”

“Someone taught me to speak, I suppose. My parents taught me.”

“Well, some people taught us to speak, too.”

“That's amazing! Who?”

“So long as you don't say where you're from or where you're going again, I'll explain a little bit. Were you in a castle?”

“Yes, Castle Ehtahl!”

“Right, OK. So, there are these castles that make dreams. Castles for daydreams and castles for night dreams. But, there are also castles that make nightmares and really, really bad dreams. Castle walls that make dreams keep the nightmares outside and keep the dreams inside. You are in between castles. This is where things or people go when they aren't wanted.”

“Not wanted?”

“I'm going to presume that you did something that's led you to be kicked out of Castle Ehtahl. Otherwise, they would have sent you back to,” Myrna looked side-to-side and then whispered. “Pennsylvania. Perhaps, you're currently unwanted as well?”

“Well, I didn't do anything but I was accused of doing something.”

“OK, same thing. You're out here like the rest of us. All of us have either done something or been accused of doing something and now no one wants us. Or, sometimes, people just don't like us. It's hard being alone but we make do. So, we live out here.”

“What did you do, Myrna?”

Myrna stared Benjamin in the eyes, standing approximately three inches tall.

“I killed a guy,” Myrna said sternly. “No, I'm kidding! I have to have fun out here. I don't get to see that many people. No, no, I ate an apple and apparently it was someone's very special apple and they were all like 'you ate our apple!' and I was like 'it was delicious' and now, here I am. It's not a bad life. I've got all these informational brochures ready to give to people who journey through.”

Myrna Delacourte let out a long sigh as her chin rested on her hand. She looked longingly into the distance before she stopped when she noticed Benjamin was paying attention to her. Benjamin could see that Myrna did not want to be where she was. She was not as happy handing out informational brochures as she said she was. He knew she wanted to be back in whatever castle that had kicked her out.

“So the space in between castles, that's the space for things in transition. We're not wanted by anyone. And, we haven't found anyone else who wants us yet.”

“Maybe you could apologize?” Benjamin offered.

“Apologize for eating the apple? Oh, Benjamin, if only it was that easy. I'm fine here. It's not so bad. I do miss my family but that's another thing and let's get you on your way.”

“Your fam—”

“So, the easiest way out of here is straight through that forest. After that, you're going to have to get back into a castle so that they can get you out of here. Since you're from,” Myrna leaned over and whispered, “Pennsylvania, that means you're going to have to find the person who welcomed you here in the first place.”

“That's King Bernard Zwirn.”

“OK, so you have to find King Bernard Zwirn and then he'll send you home.”

“That's the king who is in Al—”

“OK! OK! Say no more!”

Myrna Delacourte stacked several maps and brochures together and handed them to Benjamin.

“Would you like a coupon book for the shopping outlets on the west side of the forest? Actually, I'm just going to include it and that way you have it. Better have it and not need it, right?”

“So, I need to go straight through the forest.”

“Yes, go straight through the forest and then hang a left. You'll see signs and follow the maps. One more thing about the forest, though. You need to be aware that the trees grow and move so you need to grow and move with them. Don't get caught on your heels.”

Benjamin waved goodbye to Myrna Delacourte and wondered how long Myrna had been alone by herself. He wondered how many times she dreamed of being with her family again. Benjamin paused, looked to the sky, and turned to leave the forest.

“Myrna,” Benjamin said as he walked back the booth. “You said you don't get many visitors and so I was wondering if you could maybe close down the information booth for a little bit. Would you like to accompany me in my journey?”

“Not be alone?”

“You won't be alone!”

“I'll bring more maps!”

Chapter 18
Forest

Benjamin had been walking with Myrna on his shoulder for the better part of the afternoon before he realized that he could not yet see an exit to the forest. It seemed to him like they might be walking in circles. Or worse, it seemed like the forest actually went on forever. Myrna's nose was pointed deep into the map she held before her.

“I think we're lost,” she said.

“How can we be lost? I thought you sold maps for this place,” Benjamin replied softly as he looked from side to side.

“I do sell maps for this place. That is true.”

“So shouldn't you know where we are?”

“Well, it's not like I've ever used the maps. I merely sell them to people who use them. I haven't used them myself.”

“You don't know if the maps are right?”

Myrna stopped as Benjamin continued. She looked as far into the sky as she could.

“They might not be correct! There could be people lost everywhere!”

“I'm sure they aren't currently lost.”

“My maps are incorrect! They're misguiding people!”

“How many people have you given maps to?”

“Well, actually, you're the first person to stop by the information desk.”

“So, I guess I'm in good hands.”

Benjamin was surrounded by trees hundreds of times taller than he, with large branches that blocked a clear view of the sky. Brown leaves rustled on the ground as green leaves combed the air above. The trees were extraordinary. Benjamin stood small and insignificant compared to their size. They climbed thousands of feet into the air like wooden skyscrapers. He needed to find the exit before the sun set, he thought, because he was not sure what was in the forest at night. And now with his companion, Myrna, Benjamin felt a bit of responsibility for making sure he kept her safe. Being just a caterpillar, Benjamin thought, she couldn't defend herself.

The forest was the first of many things on the map that Myrna was reading. After the forest, there was a waterfall. Then, there was a river. Then, there was a prairie. Then, there was a mountain range. Then, a volcano. And finally, there was another castle that had information on how to get to Aloysius Trenhaile's castle.

“So why did King Bernard Zwirn end up in a nightmare's castle?” Myrna asked.

“He was kidnapped,” Benjamin said. “One of my classmates was kidnapped, too.”

“Who?”

“Selma,” Benjamin said slowly.

“I see,” Myrna said slowly and with a short giggle. “Do you like Selma?”

“She's not really that friendly to me.”

“But, you're going to go rescue her?”

“Well, of course I'm going to rescue her.”

Myrna stopped for a moment and looked deep into Benjamin's eyes.

“You don't have to lie to me, Benjamin. You could have just told me that we're going to go save your girlfriend!” Myrna said with excitement.

Benjamin stopped walking and looked at Myrna with his hands at his side.

“Let's be clear. She's not my girlfriend. She doesn't like me at all. She thinks I'm the reason King Bernard Zwirn was kidnapped.”

“I see,” Myrna said as she thought deeply for a moment. “Do you like her?”

“Myrna, I've already answered that.”

“I'm exhausted,” Myrna said as she wiped the sweat from her brow. “All this walking in search of your girlfriend is making me exhausted.”

“Do you want to rest?” Benjamin asked as he shook his head. “We have been walking for quite a bit.”

“Would love to!” Myrna said as she plopped herself down on a leaf. “I'm also a tad hungry. Are you hungry?”

“I'm a little hungry.”

“I'm a lot hungry.”

“What do caterpillars eat?”

“Grass, mostly. Sometimes mint. And if we're very lucky, we get a tomato leaf. Oh my, you haven't lived until you've eaten a tomato leaf wrapped in mint with a blade of grass tying it together,” Myrna said as she licked her lips.

“So you want some grass?” Benjamin offered, as he walked to a patch of green leaves.

“No, I'm not hungry for grass. Oh! How about some berries!” Myrna said as she pointed to a cluster of red fruit near a tree on the other side of Benjamin.

Benjamin waited for Myrna to go retrieve the berries but Myrna was acting as lazy as a caterpillar could be. She pretended to move half a step forward and then fell back to resting on her side.

“It's so far!”

The berries were about ten steps away from Benjamin and he didn't understand how Myrna could be so lazy. He could walk there in five seconds. It would take three seconds to pick the berries. And then it would take five seconds to walk back.

“It would take thirteen seconds to walk there,” Benjamin said. “You can do it.”

“Nope, not true.”

“What do you mean?”

“It'll take you thirteen seconds to walk over there. It'll take me nearly ten or eleven hours to get there! You've forgotten I'm a caterpillar. I'd starve before I got there!”

Benjamin looked at his little friend and realized that he had been thinking about himself and had not considered that Myrna could not do what he could do. He did not think about getting the berries from her perspective. It was so simple, to him, and it would be so hard for her. And so, he walked to the berries, retrieved some, and returned them to Myrna with a smile in thirteen seconds. He held them in his hand for a few moments.

“What are you waiting for?” Myrna asked impatiently. “Let me have them.”

“How do you know they're safe to eat?” he replied.

“I've eaten them many times before and I'm still alive!”

“I don't know if they're safe for me,” he said. He turned to his backpack and retrieved A Guide To Plants Outside The Castle Not That You'll Ever Need This Because Everyone Stays In The Castle But If You Do Here's A Book For That, I Guess. He turned page after page until he found a picture of a berry that was identical to what he had in his hand. Underneath the picture, it read not recommended for human consumption.

“Oh, I shouldn't eat these,” Benjamin said.

“Really?” Myrna asked as she chewed more and more of the berries.

“It says here that they cause humans to fall into a deep sleep.”

“That's a shame! They're so delicious.”

“Well, I'll let you enjoy them then.”

“Would you mind if we took some along with us? They're so delicious I think I'd like to have some tomorrow.”

“Sure, Myrna. I'm sorry about not thinking about how long it would take you to retrieve berries.”

“It's OK. You're not the first to think I can do what everyone else can do. Most people can't even see me.”

“Well, you are tiny.”

“I've got a ferocious voice, Benjamin. Don't forget it!”

Benjamin laughed as Myrna held her fists to her face in a mock boxer's pose. He gathered more berries and upon seeing how red his hands had become, he tried to wipe them clean against the trunk of a tree. Myrna noticed what Benjamin was doing and mumbled something to Benjamin but her words weren't clear because of all of the berries in her mouth. As Benjamin continued to wipe his hands against the tree, it started to shake back and forth in such a way that none of the berries stuck to its trunk. Benjamin thought this was curious and so he grabbed some more berries and tried to smash them into the tree again. Myrna swallowed all of the berries at once, her face covered in red juice and her belly rounder than a tennis ball.

“Uh, I wouldn't do that,” she said.

“Do what?”

“I wouldn't put berries on the tree.”

“Why not? It's fun. The tree shakes them off! Watch this.”

And before Myrna could say another word, Benjamin gathered as many berries he could and ran to the tree with the widest trunk in all of the forest. He held the red fruit above his head and then swung his arms into the tree. The berries smashed into the trunk and then flew back into Benjamin's face just as fast as he had thrown them into the tree.

“What is your problem!” a voice rang throughout the forest.

Benjamin looked around. He didn't know who asked that question but it sounded like a woman who was not too far away from him. It was a voice much deeper than Myrna's and it echoed throughout the forest.

“Now you've done it,” Myrna said with a bored face. She picked up another berry and began to eat it.

“You can't take a hint!” the voice yelled again. “Do you think it's fun to have some little creature run up to you and smash berries into your side? Don't you know berries stain?”

“I know berries stain,” Benjamin said as he moved his head back and forth to try to find the source of the voice. He walked backwards to Myrna. “Myrna, where is that voice coming from?”

“If I knew, I'd include it in my informational brochures!” she said with mock jest before devouring another berry.

“You were throwing berries into my side on purpose!” the voice yelled again.

“Who are you? Where are you?” Benjamin asked.

“You've got some nerve. I thought you'd get the gist if I shook them away; but for some reason, you had to run back with more berries. More berries! Why would you think I would want berries on my side?”

“I was just trying to clean my hands.”

“And you think throwing berries into my side without asking my permission is the answer to your problem?”

“I thought it would solve my problem, yes.”

“Solving that problem created another problem! They stain! Why would I want them on my side?”

“He tried to put them on me too,” an older manly voice echoed from another side of the forest.

“He did what?” the woman's voice yelled.

“He smashed berries into my side as well,” the man's voice said.

“Well, this is just a berry massacre, isn't it?” the woman said. “This little boy has been trying to smash berries into the side of all of us.”

“Me too,” a young girl's voice said.

“The children!” the female's voice said. “You've even tried to smash berries into the children!”

“Oh, Benjamin! Not the kids!” Myrna said as she grabbed Benjamin's collar and stared directly into his eyes.

“I shook at least a dozen times and there are still some berries on me,” the elderly man said. “It's going to take at least a few washings until I'm able to get this stain out.”

“This is just an awful day,” said the woman. “There are berry stains everywhere. Don't you know how difficult it is to get berry stains off?”

“I have no idea,” Benjamin said honestly.

“Ask your mother,” the woman said. “They're impossible. Downright impossible.”

“They're impossible, Benjamin. Not possible,” Myrna said as she continued munching on berries.

“Look at me,” said the young girl. “I'm pretty much an embarrassment at this point.”

Benjamin realized that the trees were talking but he couldn't understand where the voices were coming from. He wasn't sure if the trees themselves were talking to him or if Myrna was playing a joke. He didn't think it was an impossibility. Myrna was a very smart caterpillar with a quirky sense of humor.

“Who are you all?” he said.

“Oh, now he wants introductions,” the elderly man's voice said.

“Little boy comes into the forest and makes a mess of everything and now he wants to know our names,” the female voice said.

“Kids these days are so rude. They've got no manners and think they can throw berries wherever they want.”

“Amen to that!” Myrna said.

“You're preaching to the choir, Earl.”

“So, his name is Earl,” Benjamin said quickly, referring to the elderly voice.

“Oh shoot, I'm sorry Earl,” said the female's voice while the young girl giggled in the background.

“Ah, you've done it again,” said Earl. “You were never good at keeping secrets, Bertha.”

“Bertha?” Benjamin asked.

“So now you're going to make fun of my name?” Bertha asked sarcastically.

“Well, no, I was just confirming that your name is Bertha.”

“Yes, it's Bertha. That's Earl. I'm Bertha. And, that's Gertrude. You know all our names so now you know who to send money to for our cleaning bill.”

“I'm Benjamin. I'm sorry I stained your trunks.”

“Benjamin, eh?” said Earl. “I would have thought you looked a bit more like a Robin.”

“Robin, yes,” said Bertha. “I've seen many robins before and you do look a lot like them.”

“We were just stopping to eat some berries. We've been walking through the forest for some time now and we're just trying to find our way out.”

“Hi, everyone. I'm Myrna,” Myrna said.

“Myrna? The Myrna who sells the maps of the forest?” Earl asked.

“Yes that's me,” Myrna replied.

“We've got a celebrity in our midst. Those maps are wonderful,” Earl said in a very calm manner.

“They are gorgeous!” Gertrude said. “I love the way you drew us!”

“Ah, thanks everyone!” Myrna said as she tossed a berry at the now bored Benjamin.

“We've been watching you two for a while now,” Bertha said. “And I hate to break it to you but you've been walking around longer than hours. It's been a couple days.”

“Days?” Benjamin said in surprise. “But, the sun hasn't set yet.”

“It doesn't set over this forest. It just keeps circling and circling and circling.”

“Oh did I forget to tell you that?” Myrna asked.

“Oh my gosh, Myrna. That's exactly how I felt. I felt like I was walking around in circles.”

“You were.”

“How would we have known this?”

“Don't you have one of Myrna's maps?”

“We do!” Myrna said. “But, I only create them. I've never used one before.”

“That's totally understandable,” the three trees said in unison.

“How in the world is that understandable?” Benjamin asked as he shook his head.

“Makes sense to me!” Myrna repeated.

“How would we have known where we were going to go?” Benjamin asked.

“You could have just asked,” said Earl.

“Well,” Benjamin said. “I didn't think I'd get an answer if I asked a question into a forest.”

“That's true,” Bertha said. “There's that group in the middle of the forest that's rather rude. They probably wouldn't have told you. You should have put berries on them.”

“They are the worst!” Myrna said quickly as she bit into another berry.

“Where am I now?” Benjamin asked.

“You're in the north east. Can't you tell by our sophistication?”

Benjamin couldn't tell. He did not know what a sophisticated tree looked like.

“Alright, fine,” Bertha said. “But, you're going to have to believe us. We're very, very sophisticated.”

“Can you help us leave the forest?” Benjamin asked the towering natural wonders around him.

“That depends on where you'd like to go,” Earl said.

“We came from the dessert.”

“You came through the desert?” Gertrude asked. “No one survives the desert. That's one of the most dangerous places outside of all the castles.”

Benjamin felt a little proud of himself because he did, indeed, survive. It wasn't so bad, he thought. He could do it again if he needed to. And with Myrna's assistance, he could easily manage the desert.

“If you need to exit opposite the desert, you're going to need to head for the canyon. The canyon will take you to a river and then Myrna's map may be able to guide you the rest of the way,” Earl said.

“Great,” Benjamin said and then paused for a moment. “But, which way is the canyon.”

“I'm pointing to it,” Earl said.

Benjamin looked up at the nearest tree and saw a trunk soaring into the sky with hundreds of branches pointing every possible direction. He was a little embarrassed because he did not know what Earl meant. Myrna shrugged her shoulders because she had no idea which one of the branches was pointing in the right direction.

“I'm sorry but I can't—”

“Can't you see, Benjamin?” Bertha asked with concern. “Earl is pointing in the direction of the canyon.”

“It's right there, Benjamin,” Earl said.

“I can see but it's just that there's so many—”

“He can't see,” Gertrude said.

“I can see,” Benjamin responded. “But your branches are going in so—”

“There!” Earl said.

“Right there!” Bertha echoed.

“There?” Myrna asked from Benjamin's shoulder.

“There!” Gertrude said.

Benjamin looked into the sky and decided he could only know which direction to go if he started to walk. He took three steps forward in one direction.

“No!” Earl yelled.

Then, he stopped and took three steps to his left.

“No!” Bertha yelled.

Then, he stopped and took three steps backwards.

“Ah, almost but!” Earl yelled.

Before Earl or Bertha could say anything more, Benjamin turned a little bit to the right and started to walk.

“That's it!” Gertrude said. “I guess he can see.”

“So if I walk straight, we'll walk to the canyon?” Benjamin asked the trees.

“You won't be able to miss it,” Bertha said.

“And if you need directions in the future,” Earl continued. “Just ask someone. It's incredibly rude to smash red berries into our sides. Bye, Myrna!”

“Bye, everyone,” Myrna waved as she sat on Benjamin's shoulders while he walked forward.

“I guess you don't need maps if you can talk to trees,” Benjamin said to Myrna.

“Who in their right mind would talk to trees when you can use a map!” Myrna yelled as she whipped out another map that read Map To Dangerous Areas Of The Kingdom.

Chapter 19
Favor

By his own calculation, Benjamin estimated that he had taken three thousand, four hundred, and seventy-two steps before he reached the edge of the forest. Myrna was saved any steps by continuing to sit on Benjamin's shoulder. And as far as he could tell, these steps were in a straight line. But, he knew that it was also unlikely that he completed a perfect line. He was beginning to learn that despite his best efforts to complete a goal, there were many obstacles along the way. In the forest, these obstacles were trees. But in his quest to make friends, his obstacles were other people around him. People like Russell Fox and Thalia Nachamie were the bad trees that blocked his departure. But as Benjamin exited the forest and Myrna blocked the sun from scalding her eyes, he gained a small amount of confidence that he could navigate his way. He could do this, he thought to himself.

“Well, I don't know about you but I'm exhausted,” Myrna said as she lay on her back on Benjamin's shoulder.

“You haven't moved at all! How can you be exhausted?” Benjamin asked as he looked around at the canyon below them.

“Mental exhaustion, Benjamin! You have no idea. I've been thinking so much the entire time we were in that forest,” she responded as she closed her eyes.

“What were you thinking about?”

“Oh, you know. The typical things like how many brochures I should print next. Are my maps accurate? Turns out they aren't! I didn't realize. I thought a lot about that. And, of course, I thought a lot about boys.”

“Boys?” Benjamin stopped walking and stared at Myrna.

“Yes, boys! You can't tell me you're not currently thinking about Selma,” Myrna said as she stood on her feet.

“No, I don't think about Selma!” Benjamin objected.

“Oh! Tell me, Benjamin. Tell me you do,” Myrna said as she nudged herself closer to Benjamin's face and placed her chin on her hands.

“I don't!” Benjamin said as he sat on the edge of the canyon.

“Is she cute?”

“No.”

“Is she sweet?”

“No.”

“Is she single?”

“No.”

“Then, frankly, Benjamin, I don't know why you're interested in her.”

“There is no her. Selma and I are not a couple.”

“You don't want to be with her?”

“I'm confused. You've confused me. I have to go save her. And, I have to save King Bernard Zwirn.”

“Oh my gosh you're in love!” Myrna said as she twirled in a circle and then fell onto Benjamin's shoulder.

“I am not in love.”

“Sh! Sh!” Myrna said as she put her finger to Benjamin's mouth. “This is great, Benjamin. The world needs more love.”

“I'm not in love.”

“If you're not in love, then why don't you just save King Bernard Zwirn? You don't have to save Selma.”

“I can't not rescue her.”

“Well, sure you could!”

“That wouldn't be nice.”

“There's a fine line between being in love with someone and being nice to someone, Benjamin.”

“I don't think that's true.”

“So explain this to me, Benjamin. If you think you're not going to save your girlfriend, why are you here talking to a caterpillar staring off into a gigantic canyon?”

“I don't see how those two things are related.”

“Wrong!”

“Why, then?”

“Because, Benjamin, you are in love. And, you have an imagination. And in order for someone to be in love, they must have an imagination, I say.”

“You're so confusing, Myrna. I don't know what love is. But, I know what an imagination is. But what good is an imagination? It doesn't make me good at sports or school or making friends.”

“I think you're using it incorrectly!”

“Incorrectly?”

“Yes! Incorrectly!”

“How should I be using it then?”

“Hm,” Myrna said as she tapped her fingers on her knee. “I don't know but you have to figure that out. You have to figure out how to use your imagination so that you stop worrying about how you measure up to everyone else. You have to figure out why you're here. I, for one, know why I'm here.”

“Why are you here?”

“To take a nap,” Myrna said as she curled up on Benjamin's shoulder and shut her eyes.

She fell asleep faster than any creature Benjamin had seen fall asleep. He felt a sense of calmness having Myrna lay on his shoulder because he felt that she trusted him. It was a compliment that Benjamin thought deeply about as he stared into the canyon and wondered why he was here. What good is an imagination? How was he using it incorrectly? How could he use his imagination in general? He never thought about such things. He never thought about his imagination.

Hours passed as Benjamin kept searching his brain for an answer to Myrna's question. He was feeling mentally exhausted as he explored every nook and cranny of his mind. And just as he thought he found something that could lead him to the answer, he heard a familiar sound in the distance.

“South! South! South! South! South! South!” the huge squirrel yelled as it ran by. “South! South! South! South!”

Benjamin watched the little creature run by his side and out of sight while leaving a small dust trail in his path. Myrna stayed asleep through it all. Benjamin still could not believe a squirrel could run that fast for so long. It must be possessed, Benjamin thought, as he stared off in the distance and wondered what could frighten someone so much to make him run so fast. And when he thought about it more, he realized that he was not too dissimilar to the squirrel that ran away because Benjamin, too, had run away from something. But, it hadn't been so loud and certainly, it hadn't been so noisy. As Benjamin sat with a newfound understanding of himself in hand, he heard the sound of the squirrel as it made yet another pass by Benjamin.

“North! North! North! North! North! North!” the squirrel yelled as it ran the opposite direction. “North! North! North! North!”

It must be hard to be like the squirrel, constantly running away from something and, presumably, not knowing where to go. And Benjamin would have continued to think about how he and the little woodland creature were alike except that the squirrel was beginning to pass more frequently and with more proximity than Benjamin felt comfortable. In fact, the squirrel was beginning to run directly at Benjamin as if it didn't know that an obstacle was in its way.

“South! South! South! South!” the squirrel yelled in the distance.

The little animal was about a thousand feet away and ran along the edge of the canyon at Benjamin. Why would a squirrel want to run directly at him, Benjamin thought. Surely, it sees that something is in its way.

“South! South! South! South!” the squirrel screamed.

Benjamin shifted to his left and then to his right. There was nowhere to move. If he moved to his left or backwards, he would fall off the side of the canyon. Trees blocked his path to the right. This squirrel was aimed right at him.

“South! South!” the squirrel screamed as its eyes widened and slobber flew from its lips.

With only fifty feet left, the squirrel had picked up a speed the equivalent of a motorcycle moving down an empty highway on a calm Saturday morning. There was no stopping it, Benjamin thought. There was going to be a collision.

“I can't move!” Benjamin yelled. Myrna awoke to see the situation that had unfolded while she was dreaming. “Stop, squirrel! Stop!”

“South! South!” it yelled with a noise that felt more like a bark than a warning.

“Brace yourself!” Myrna yelled.

Benjamin braced himself for a collision with a animal moving at a speed faster than anything he had seen. Either he or the squirrel would be squashed in a moment.

“SOUTH!”

As the squirrel neared, it only increased in speed. Benjamin crouched to the ground and thought that if he tried to catch the squirrel, he could reduce the impact and prevent either one of them from falling into the abyss below. The squirrel jumped into the air at Benjamin, its eyes closed and its mouth open wide. Benjamin jumped into the air at the squirrel, his eyes closed and his mouth tightly shut. Myrna covered her eyes with her hands and prepared herself for impact. The bodies collided in midair like two hands clapping together. All three of them fell to the ground and each of them grabbed something that prevented them from falling into the canyon. The three shocked creatures stared at the sky.

“South,” the squirrel said faintly.

“Not south,” Myrna said through her teeth.

“Ouch,” said Benjamin as he rolled back and forth in mild pain. He wasn't really hurt so much as confused. Neither animal moved for a minute as they all pondered what had happened.

“My head hurts,” the squirrel whispered as it stood up and adjusted the goggles it had been wearing to keep dirt out of its eyes.

“You ran right into me,” Benjamin said as he rubbed his belly. “Your head should hurt.”

“I didn't even see you.”

“I was standing right in front of you the entire time. How didn't you see me?”

“Are you one of those blind squirrels?” Myrna asked with curiosity.

“I run with my eyes closed.”

“Not a smart squirrel,” Myrna said as she climbed onto Benjamin's shoulder again.

“You run with your eyes closed? How do you know where you're going?” Benjamin asked.

“I yell the direction I want to go. If I want to go north, I yell north! If I want to go south, I yell south. East? East! West? West! Northeast? Northeast!”

The squirrel yelled the words in a low tone that Benjamin thought could only be from an older man. His little body heaved up and down as he let out a long cough like someone with a breathing problem. After he gathered himself back together, he cleared his throat and wiped the dirt from his goggles with his white tail. Benjamin watched him put the goggles back on his face and move gray eyebrows up and down in satisfaction. It never crossed Benjamin's mind that the squirrel moving so quickly across the land could be as old as the creature standing before him.

“You're the biggest, craziest squirrel I've ever seen,” Myrna said as she shook her head slowly from side to side.

“You're the rudest little caterpillar I've ever met,” the squirrel responded with one eye open and the other closed. “Why are you so tiny?”

“For probably the same reasons that you're so gigantic,” Myrna said.

Benjamin felt that there was an unusual tension between Myrna and the squirrel. He somehow thought that the two of them had something in common. But, he didn't know what it was just yet.

“Yelling the direction isn't going to help when you run into something. I can't yell north and then expect to be running north,” Benjamin explained.

“Have you tried it?” the squirrel said so quickly that Benjamin realized it was not even a question.

“Well, no, but—”

“How would you know if you haven't tried it?”

“I'm not going to—”

“Why not?”

“First of all, we're standing on the edge of a canyon. I'm already nervous as it is. If I closed my eyes and ran anywhere, I'd probably fall right into the abyss.”

“Bah! I've been running around for years now. I've learned a thing or two. First thing I learned is that yes, you do run into things. Second thing I learned is that I can run a lot faster if I run with my eyes closed. And, third thing I learned is that I haven't yet run into any canyons!”

“If you'll forgive me, dear squirrel,” Myrna started to say sarcastically. “If you did run into a canyon, we probably wouldn't be talking to you right now.”

“Exactly!”

“Where are you running to?” Benjamin asked.

“Well, that's a better question than asking about the weather,” the squirrel said as it propped its elbow on its knee and tilted its head to the sky. It tapped the ground several times with its tail and then smacked its lips. “I supposed you can ask where we all are running? Or, are we running? Are we running to something or are we running from something.” The squirrel got to his feet and pressed its finger against its forehead. It stopped and shifted its head back quickly. “Or, we're running from and to something! But what does it mean to run at all? I don't get to think about these questions very often. I suppose I'm always running. You know what they say about the flowers?”

“They're delicious!” Myrna said with a wide smile and her finger pointing to the air as if she had correctly answered the question.

“No, silly caterpillar, that's—,” the squirrel said.

“My name is Myrna!” Myrna interrupted him.

“My manners! Nice to meet you, Myrna. My name is Barnaby,” Barnaby the squirrel said.

“And, my name is Benjamin,” Benjamin said as he extended his hand to Barnaby because Benjamin thought it was the polite thing to do. Barnaby took it and examined it on all sides.

“You are awfully young,” Barnaby said. “And, it's nice to meet you as well, Benjamin.”

“Nice to meet you, too,” Benjamin said as he realized he was chatting with both a caterpillar and a squirrel.

“So, I was going to say something. Oh yes! I remember now. I was going to say that when you're running all the time, you never have time to think about why you're running. And if you're never running and always thinking about running, you're not going to get anywhere. So maybe, just maybe, the best way to be is to think while you're running? No. That doesn't work very well for me at all. I can't even think about where I'm going while I'm running. Maybe the best way to run is to stop every now and then to understand why you're running. Why am I running?”

“Yes! Why are you running?” Benjamin said as he and Myrna waited patiently for Barnaby to respond.

“Bears,” he said as a matter of fact.

“Bears?” Myrna asked with a confused expression.

“Oh, yes. There were bears back there! Can you imagine running around and having a great time and then all of a sudden you open your eyes to see a dozen bears staring at you! They'll eat you alive, really. Scary things. That'll give you another reason to close your eyes. If I can't see the bears, I won't be scared of them.”

“You could avoid them if you saw them.”

“I suppose you're right. If I saw the bears, I could avoid them.”

“So you were running away from bears?” Myrna said as if she were talking with the most boring person she had ever met.

“Well, I'm running away from a lot of issues,” Barnaby said as he nudged Benjamin's sneaker with his elbow. “But yes, mostly bears. And, my fear of failure but we don't need to talk about that. How did you get so smart?”

“I don't think I'm very smart,” Benjamin said.

“Well, you certainly ask interesting questions. I've been running back and forth away from bears for years and no one has asked me these types of questions.”

“I suppose I'm curious.”

“Curiosity is a great thing!” Barnaby said quickly. “Don't ever lose that. Curiosity can get you very far.”

“I'll remember that,” Benjamin said.

“So anyways, where are you two headed?” Barnaby asked.

Myrna climbed down from Benjamin's shoulder to the ground with great excitement and anticipation. Benjamin noticed that it was the fastest he had seen her move. She stood immediately before Barnaby and pressed her hands together in front of her tiny body. A giant, happy expression overwhelmed her face as she jumped and twirled in the air.

“Benjamin's in love!” she said as she fell onto her back and smiled into the clouds above.

Barnaby and Benjamin listened to her hum a love song and sigh over and over.

“Well,” Barnaby said very slowly and awkwardly. “I'm very sorry to hear that.”

Myrna jumped to her feet and looked Barnaby straight in the eyes.

“Sorry! How could someone be sorry about something so wonderful! Her name is Selma!”

“Oh yes, love is wonderful. I meant sorry that Myrna knows that you're in love. So who is the lucky lady?”

“There is no lucky lady,” Benjamin said in a very shy tone.

“Oh, that's totally fine,” Barnaby said. “Modern times and all. I'm cool with that.”

“There is no one,” Benjamin changed his answer.

“You love no one?” Barnaby asked.

Myrna started to parade around and sing another love song to herself.

“He keeps saying that but I know the truth. Benjamin's in love! And, I'm going to tell the whole world! We're going to rescue his girlfriend,” Myrna said again as she skipped around Barnaby.

“Again, I'm sorry,” Barnaby said with a serious tone.

“She keeps saying I'm in love but I don't even know what love is,” Benjamin said.

“Oh my gosh this is the most precious thing!” Myrna said with joy. “Benjamin's in love and he's got to find her so that they can live together and be happy forever!”

“So, where is this lucky lady that you're, ahem, not in love with, Benjamin?” Barnaby said with a steady face. “I might be able to help you get there.”

“Do you know how to get to Aloysius Trenhaile's castle?” Benjamin said quickly. He said it so quickly that Myrna did not have a chance to put her hands over Benjamin's mouth. He knew from her expression that he had said a bad thing. But, he needed help getting to Aloysius Trenhaile's castle and this squirrel had probably run everywhere. If anyone knew how to get there, Barnaby would.

“Aloysius Trenhaile's castle? Wow, you really are in love with her,” Barnaby said as he scratched at his mustache and tapped his tail on the ground. “That takes a lot of guts to go to that castle. Why would your girlfriend happen to be there?”

“I don't have a girlfriend.”

“Selma!” Myrna whispered loudly.

“Why do you want to go to Aloysius Trenhaile's castle, Benjamin? This friend of yours, Selma, can't be so bad if you're willing to risk your life to go save her.”

“I need to rescue a king,” he said. “If I rescue a king, everyone at Castle Ehtahl will realize that I didn't do anything bad. And, the king is the only person who can send me home. And, Selma, my friend, has also been kidnapped and she's probably there too. She's OK but she's not really nice to me.”

“Women will do that. She probably likes you. Where are you from?” Barnaby asked with curiosity.

Benjamin looked at Myrna and he knew better than to answer this question honestly. He did not need to give Barnaby any more curious information than he already had.

“I'm from Castle Ehtahl. They're blaming me for destroying the dream machine.”

“You're the one who has ended all the dreams?” Barnaby asked with confusion.

“No!” Benjamin said quickly. “The person who kidnapped King Bernard Zwirn and Selma is the person who is ending all of our dreams.”

“I haven't dreamed in a while,” Barnaby said as he tilted his head to look to the sky. “But then again, it's tough to dream when you're running around all the time.”

“Me neither,” Myrna said. “My last dream involved an apple the size of the sun. It was all mine. I loved it.”

“I bet you did, Myrna,” Barnaby said with a smirk. “Listen, Benjamin. I'll be honest with you. I know where Aloysius Trenhaile's castle is and I don't want to go anywhere near it. It's where nightmares come from. You're from Castle Ehtahl. You know that. You make dreams. Aloysius makes nightmares. I hope Aloysius didn't kidnap your friends. Because if they were, well, Benjamin, I hope they weren't.”

“Can you show me the way? You don't need to come with me. I can go on my own,” Benjamin said quickly. He said it too quickly. Once again, he spoke words before he thought about the damage those words could cause to someone else. Myrna looked hurt and he realized she wanted to go wherever Benjamin was going to go. “Myrna and I will find it.”

“I can introduce you to someone who can help you,” Barnaby said. “But, that's as much as I can do.”

“That would be great!”

“But you must know,” Barnaby said seriously. “He will only help you if you do a favor for him.”

Chapter 20
Deception

“Do you know how different the world looks when you're not seeing it at a hundred miles an hour?” Barnaby said as he walked next to Benjamin with Myrna on his shoulder.

They had been walking for the better part of the afternoon and the sun was beginning to set over a meadow of daffodils that stretched to the horizon. Benjamin knew that Myrna was not too excited about trusting Barnaby. But, Benjamin was willing to take a chance. If Barnaby knew someone that could take him to Aloysius Trenhaile's castle, then he could get there more quickly than if he was to find it on his own. He did not know how he could survive outside Castle Ehtahl for a long time.

“How much further is it, Barnaby?” Benjamin asked because his feet were getting tired. If he had more to eat, he wouldn't be so tired. But outside Castle Ehtahl, he had to rely on his book to choose which berries and fruits to eat.

“You're tired already?” Barnaby asked without slowing his pace.

“I'm just hungry.”

“Me too,” Myrna said. “All this travel has me wishing that we're heading for a big feast.”

“That's not off, Myrna!” Barnaby said. Benjamin's eyes lit at the possibility of walking toward food. He thought how much he missed his mother's cooking and how he had taken it for granted.

“There's food ahead?” Benjamin asked, a little too eagerly.

“Well, you remember that favor I asked you? Well, you see my friend collect nuts. Walnuts, to be precise. And, you see he's got this problem where he can't chew very well anymore. So he's got all these walnuts but he can't eat them because he can't get the shells open. Do you think you could help him?”

“He needs someone to open the walnuts for them?”

“Yes, you see he can't do it himself. And there aren't just walnuts. There are all sorts of foods. I'm only interested in the walnuts but he's got more food than I ever knew existed.”

“Does he have tulips?” Myrna asked.

“I think he's got everything you could ever want. That's his home over there,” Barnaby said as he pointed to a tree standing alone in the middle of a meadow.

When they approached, Barnaby knocked on the outside of the trunk as hard as he could. The tree soared into the air like the dream machine inside Castle Ehtahl. It had thousands of branches, each branch with thousands of leaves. It looked almost as high as the mountains that towered in the distance.

Barnaby stood on his hind legs and knocked as loudly on the tree as he could.

“Chesterfield!” Barnaby said. “I found an answer to all of our, I mean your problems! It's time to eat, Chesterfield!”

The running inside the tree came to an abrupt stop. Barnaby took a couple steps back from the trunk and a door suddenly became visible in the tree.

“What do you want, Barnaby?” an unknown figure shouted from inside.

“Chesterfield, I've found our hero!”

“What did you do with your bird?”

“It flew away,” Barnaby said sadly.

“It flew away?” Chesterfield asked with disbelief.

“You had a bird?” Myrna asked.

“I had a bird,” Barnaby said with disbelief.

“Where did it go?” Myrna asked with curiosity. She ran from Benjamin's shoulder to the side of Barnaby. She leaned over and whispered loudly into his ear. “Was she your girlfriend?”

“No, she wasn't my girlfriend.”

“Oh, love is so hard!” Myrna said as she clutched her heart and fell on her back.

“She was my transportation.”

“Love exists! It exists!” Myrna said as she jumped to her feet.

“But, she had to fly away,” Barnaby said quickly as Myrna grabbed his hand with warm affection.

“Why? Why did she have to leave?”

“I'd rather not talk about that right now,” Barnaby said slowly. “I promised Benjamin that I would find a way for him to go to where he needs to go.”

The door opened, a three foot by three foot door within the frame of a tree ten times that width. And standing within this relatively large door was the largest chipmunk Benjamin had ever seen. It was as tall as Barnaby and as wide as Benjamin.

“Why that's wonderful!” Chesterfield exclaimed with his arms stretched to his sides. “Barnaby, you should have told me.”

“I did tell you. This child is going to be our hero.”

“Let me get my walnuts!”

Chesterfield slammed the door closed and ran throughout the tree, shaking branches and leaves loose. Benjamin heard the sounds of musical instruments, construction noises, and loud engines as Chesterfield moved about. It was quite a large home but Chesterfield was a gigantic chipmunk. When the door swung open minutes later, Chesterfield appeared with five walnuts in his mouth and hands. He scooted across the grass and placed them at Benjamin's feet.

Benjamin couldn't believe his luck. There were only five walnuts. This would take him no time at all. He would help a starving chipmunk and be on his way in a matter of minutes.

He picked up the walnuts and examined each to see that they were ordinary. He knew how to open these shells because he had seen his parents open them many times before. All he had to do was find something hard to slam them against. And having learned his lesson in the forest, he wasn't about to slam the walnuts into the side of the tree.

He placed a rock between Barnaby and Chesterfield. They watched Benjamin's every move with increasing interest. Myrna kept looking at Barnaby and was hardly paying any attention to Benjamin. She seemed like she was interested in something else.

“Here we go,” Benjamin said as he prepared to smash the rock into the walnut.

Chesterfield put his hand against the rock before Benjamin could pick it up.

“Wait! Wait! Wait! Do you know how long it took us to move that rock from here to where you just picked it up?” Chesterfield said with annoyance.

“What do you mean?” Benjamin asked.

“That rock was over here last month,” Barnaby explained. “It took us all of the past four weeks to move it to where you picked it up.”

“And now!” Chesterfield stamped his feet into the ground with frustration. “You've brought it back!”

“Don't worry! I'll put it back,” Benjamin said. He couldn't believe a squirrel and a chipmunk could get so upset about a rock.

Chesterfield and Barnaby stood to the side. Benjamin picked up the rock and slammed it against a walnut, creating a quick cracking noise with a sudden burst of shell in the air. Barnaby, Myrna, and Chesterfield covered their heads as it began to rain shell fragments.

Benjamin picked up the rock and slammed it into the second walnut. Crack!

The third. Crack!

The fourth. Crack!

And, the fifth. Crack!

He had opened all of the walnuts in less than five minutes. It had happened exactly as he had imagined it would. He was happy to have done something that he had only seen his parents do. And now having done it, he knew he could do it as well.

Both Chesterfield and Barnaby were shocked. They nodded their heads and then applauded as an audience would applaud a golfer's drive. Myrna joined the applause only after seeing that Chesterfield started clapping loudly.

“That was,” Chesterfield said, taking a slow step forward, “extremely impressive.”

“Thanks,” Benjamin said, happy to receive the compliment. “And, now you can eat!”

“Yes,” Barnaby said, taking a quick step forward. “Now, he can eat!”

“So, I should get going and I would really love to know how I can get to the, ahem, castle,” Benjamin said.

Benjamin grabbed his backpack and examined the long grass stain along his shirt. As he started to gather Myrna onto his shoulder, Chesterfield ran in front of Benjamin and put his hands out to stop him from moving any further.

“Actually,” Chesterfield said. “We didn't realize you would be so good at opening walnuts. Five walnuts are great. Don't get me wrong. I am very grateful for your help. But if we had a few more walnuts open, then I could eat all month without having to find someone else to open them.”

“Barnaby, I must be going. Why don't you try opening the walnuts for Chesterfield?”

Barnaby held his fingers forward and Benjamin saw that they had all been worn out, presumably from opening many walnuts and from running all around.

“How many more walnuts?” Benjamin asked with a long sigh. He couldn't stay for a while but he could open a couple more. And also, Benjamin had a lot of fun smashing the rock into the walnuts.

“Not many. As many as you want to do,” Chesterfield said from inside the tree.

“OK, bring out the walnuts.”

Benjamin returned to the rock and waited for Barnaby to stop whispering to Chesterfield so that he could begin opening the nuts.

“Actually,” Chesterfield said. “Would you mind coming inside my tree house to open the rest?”

“Inside the tree house? Why?”

“Well, I thought I could offer you a spot of tea and some biscuits.”

Benjamin only thought briefly about what biscuits and tea a chipmunk was capable of making. But then he realized what Barnaby had mentioned to him earlier. Chesterfield supposedly had lots of food to eat.

“I am hungry,” Benjamin said. “I would love something to eat!”

“Me too!” Myrna chimed in.

Benjamin was also curious to see the inside of the tree. After he watched Chesterfield walk inside, he stuck his own head in to look. The space was as high as the tree was tall. It looked like a cylindrical room was a spiral staircase that spun around shelves and shelves of walnuts and various other foods.

“Come on in!” Barnaby said.

“Yes, come in,” Chesterfield said as he pulled out some biscuits and tea. Barnaby and Chesterfield looked at the size of the biscuits and then compared them to the size of Benjamin. They were not nearly as large as they should be to satisfy the child's appetite. “Come in! Come in!”

Benjamin squeezed through the door until he was completely inside the tree. Barnaby shut the door and Chesterfield handed Benjamin biscuit after biscuit. As Benjamin ate the delicious treats, he began to wonder why there were so many walnuts on the shelves. There were a lot of other foods but there were more walnuts than anything else.

“So you really like walnuts?” Benjamin said.

“I don't know if like is the right word, but we've gotten used to them,” Chesterfield said.

“It looks like there are thousands here,” Benjamin replied as he sipped tea and ate another biscuit. Benjamin had eaten nearly a dozen so far while Myrna was halfway through her first biscuit. She was looking at all of the walnuts with skepticism.

“Can you tell me why you two were kicked out of the dream castles? Which ones were you kicked out of?” Myrna started peppering Barnaby and Chesterfield with questions.

“Now, now,” Barnaby said. “I'd be happy to explain why I'm no longer in a castle but not while we're eating.”

“I'm sure we got kicked out of the castles in much the same way you and Benjamin got kicked out of the castle,” Chesterfield said as he tilted his hat to the side of his face. “I didn't listen when I should have listened.”

“Let's just say, Myrna, that sometimes we don't always get to choose the lives we'd like to live. We're just getting by, Myrna. I think we should leave well enough alone,” Barnaby said.

Benjamin sensed that there was tension between Myrna and Barnaby. And, he did not want this tension to continue. He wanted to open the walnuts that Chesterfield needed so that he could get on his way to Aloysius Trenhaile's castle soon.

“Do you want to show me which walnuts you want me to open?” Benjamin said quickly. “I can open them for you and then you can show me how to get to Aloysius Trenhaile's castle.”

Chesterfield's jaw dropped to the floor again. But, he didn't say anything. He looked at Barnaby and Barnaby simply nodded his head in agreement. Benjamin watched this silent conversation and wondered what they were thinking. Myrna, also, seemed worried that the squirrel and the chipmunk were not as friendly as they said they were.

“Right. Yes. Well, I will certainly provide you with directions. So, before then, we were hoping you could help us open a few more. You opened the five walnuts so quickly that it will take you such a short amount of time than it would take us.”

“How many is a few?” Benjamin asked with caution.

Barnaby and Chesterfield started to climb the wall vertically to get to the top of the tree.

“Excuse me,” Benjamin said as he noticed that they were leaving. “How many is a few?”

“You are not being very polite, Barnaby!” Myrna yelled from Benjamin's shoulder.

They kept climbing faster and faster until they were completely out of Benjamin's reach.

“Forty-two thousand,” Chesterfield said.

“Forty-two thousand walnuts!” Benjamin shouted as he stood on his feet. “I am not going to open forty-two thousand walnuts!”

“It'll take you such a short amount of time compared to how long it will take us!” Barnaby protested.

“But, I'm not concerned with how long it would take you. It's going to take me longer than I want.”

“But we gave you biscuits.”

“I'll open a dozen and then that's it,” Benjamin decided. He grabbed twelve walnuts from the shelf and then smashed them individually on the ground inside the tree. Twelve open walnuts appeared on the ground below and as before, Chesterfield and Barnaby clapped like people at the opera. “Now, I must be leaving.”

Benjamin gathered his backpack, looked to make sure Myrna was ready to leave, and then tried to open the door from which he entered. But, it was locked. He pushed on it as hard as he could but it would not open. There wasn't anything that would allow him to unlock the door.

“Hey!” Benjamin yelled up the tree trunk. “The door is locked.”

“Yes,” Chesterfield said. “It is.”

“I would like you to open it for me.”

“I don't think we can do that.”

“Why not?”

“Because we have a lot of walnuts that need to be opened.”

“You open this door right now!”

“If you open all of the walnuts, we will open it. If you don't open all of the walnuts, well, the door stays closed.”

Benjamin was upset. He shook the door violently which caused the tree to vibrate ever so slightly. Walnuts fell from the tallest of shelves. He grumbled and his voiced echoed throughout the tree. Barnaby and Chesterfield climbed higher and higher.

“Once you open all the walnuts,” Chesterfield said. “We will unlock the door.”

It would take days, weeks, months, and maybe a year to open forty-two thousand walnuts. There was no chance he could do this within a reasonable amount of time. He had been tricked. He assumed he would only have to open a few more walnuts, not thousand. And now that he was locked inside the tree trunk, he was being held prisoner by a chipmunk and a squirrel.

“I'm not opening any!” Benjamin yelled.

“Fine, fine,” Chesterfield as if he had said this a hundred times.

Barnaby and Chesterfield climbed to the top of the tree to a loft that was away from Benjamin's sight.

“I have a bad feeling about this,” Myrna said.

“Now you have a bad feeling about this?” Benjamin asked with surprise.

“Yes,” Myrna said. “These two work for Aloysius Trenhaile.”

Chapter 21
Bird

Benjamin couldn't open the door and he wasn't going to open all the walnuts. He paced back and forth at the bottom of the tree trunk thinking about all the ways that one might be able to leave. He could dig a tunnel. But, he did not have a shovel and the trunk was too tough for his hands. He could punch a hole in the tree trunk. But, the tree trunk was more than a foot thick and he didn't have anything that strong. He could explode the entire tree with dynamite. But, he didn't have any dynamite.

“I am not very happy right now,” Myrna said as she shook her head from side to side.

“I'm not happy either, Myrna,” Benjamin said as he examined the walls for an opening.

“I mean, I don't get it. Barnaby seemed like a gentleman. He seemed like the kind of person we could trust. He seemed like he would be above treating us like this. Something is very wrong here, Benjamin.”

“Yes, I know, Myrna. I'm trying to find a way for us to escape.”

“No, Benjamin, you don't understand. I think something is really wrong with Barnaby. Maybe Chesterfield, too. I don't know him well. But, something makes me feel like Aloysius Trenhaile has something to do with all of these walnuts.”

“There's no way Barnaby and Chesterfield could eat all of the food in this tree alone.”

“What are they doing all the way up there?”

“I don't know. But, we need to leave.”

“No, we need to find out where all this food is going. We have to talk to Barnaby.”

Benjamin turned to face Myrna so that she could see his confused expression.

“Myrna, we're trapped here because of him. We can't trust him any longer. We have to leave.”

Myrna didn't make eye contact with Benjamin. She kept looking at her tail as it tapped up and down on the ground.

“No, we have to talk to Barnaby. He's the only person that can get us out of here.”

“You must be kidding.”

Myrna looked to the top of the tall room and pointed so that Benjamin could see where she was looking.

“How well can you climb?”

Benjamin sighed. He looked at Myrna and realized that she was not going to change her mind. So, he decided to climb. Hand over hand and foot over foot he climbed and climbed. Walnuts fell everywhere as he shook the shelves and moved his feet and hands in different spots. It was difficult but Benjamin was beginning to get comfortable with what he was doing. Benjamin climbed and climbed. After a half hour of progress, he looked to see how far he had moved. He was a foot off the ground, at best.

“Perhaps you have other talents besides climbing?” Myrna tried to be polite.

Benjamin didn't understand. He had been trying to climb for a while but had made no progress. He jumped at the wall again and climbed and climbed. But after another half hour had passed, he looked to see his progress and found that he had only climbed another foot into the air.

“Maybe we should read a book about climbing? That could help! If only there were books here,” Myrna said as she trailed off.

Benjamin sat down and stared at the wall. It was insurmountable. There was no way he could climb the side of it. Myrna might be able to climb it but it would take her a month until she reached the top. Benjamin wondered if he should just begin opening walnuts. There didn't seem to be any other way out of this predicament. He was caged in with nowhere to go. But then, Benjamin began to imagine that he could climb the wall and that he did make progress. He imagined moving hand over hand while holding himself up on larger steps. He positioned his feet onto these steps and then lifted his body further and further. As he looked down, he saw that he was hundreds of feet in the air. And so, he imagined that he continued to climb at a faster rate, each arm movement faster than the last. Walnuts and various other foods fell at his side. The tree swayed with Benjamin's movement. And after only a minute, Benjamin imagined that he reached the top. And there, at the top of the tree, was Chesterfield and Barnaby. He imagined that they were probably sleeping or watching television or doing something else while Benjamin and Myrna were trapped below. So, he hid behind them while they weren't paying attention and grabbed one with each of his hands. It would be impossible to catch a chipmunk or a squirrel in real life, Benjamin thought. But as he imagined it, he grabbed both of the animals and then climbed higher to the top of the tree until he reached the very top. From there, he exited a window and—

“Benjamin! Benjamin!” Benjamin heard Myrna yelling into his ear. “Benjamin, stop!”

Benjamin stopped. He stopped imagining. And when he stopped imagining, he found himself at the top of the tree with Myrna on his shoulder, Barnaby on his left, and Chesterfield on his right. All three of them were silent with eyes as large as their faces. Benjamin, too, was surprised. He didn't know how he got up here. He had simply imagined having climbed up the tree. He didn't actually climb up the tree. He already tried that and failed.

“Benjamin!” Myrna repeated again.

“I hear you. I hear you,” Benjamin said.

“Please don't drop us,” Chesterfield said.

“He's not going to drop you, you dumb chipmunk,” Myrna said. “Benjamin, let's go back inside.”

Benjamin climbed back inside and continued to wonder what had just happened.

“What! Woah!” Barnaby yelled. “What was that all about?”

Myrna saw that Benjamin was still trying to piece things together. And so, she took the opportunity to scold the two animals.

“That was not very nice!” Myrna yelled.

“We're sorry! We're sorry!” Chesterfield said.

“We should throw you off this tree for having trapped us like that. That is no way to treat someone,” Myrna shouted.

“Yes, we're terribly sorry!” Chesterfield said. Both he and Barnaby were suddenly more worried and concerned than they were before.

“What is the meaning of treating people like that?” Myrna yelled.

“We have to!” Barnaby said.

“You don't have to!”

“We do! Or else, I won't ever be freed,” Chesterfield said.

“You can leave whenever you want. You're not trapped here.”

“I am!” Chesterfield said. “If I don't have a shipment of food ready for the nightmares every week, then I can't leave the tree. One day, I hope to leave this tree for good like Barnaby here. He did this for years and finally, he's free.”

“That is still no reason to treat us that way.”

“I know,” Chesterfield said softly. And then, they both started shivering and burst into tears.

“We're sorry!”

“We know we're awful!”

“Don't kill us!”

“So sorry!”

“Take all the walnuts you want. Have them all,” Barnaby said in tears.

“Yes, you can have them all. Whatever you want. We're really sorry.”

Benjamin gathered himself together and released his grasp of the two animals.

“I don't want any walnuts. I just want to go to Aloysius Trenhaile's castle,” Benjamin said.

“Fine, fine, we'll let you go. Don't kill us! Please don't kill us.”

“I'm not going to kill you!” Benjamin said.

“You're not?” Barnaby asked.

“No, I would never do that.”

“But,” Chesterfield said slowly. “You have powers.”

“What powers?”

“Are you kidding? You climbed to the top of the tree. No one could climb to the top of the tree.”

“No one could climb up the top of the tree unless...” Barnaby stopped and then both he and Chesterfield looked at Benjamin.

Benjamin had no idea that he was now in increasingly more danger. Chesterfield and Barnaby had discovered what Miss Lindenmeyer and Rodney Cohen had discovered. They knew, too, that Benjamin had a creative imagination.

“Benjamin, what do you say about hanging out with us for a while?” Chesterfield said. “We could tour you around. We could introduce you to some people.”

Myrna had an idea what the squirrel and chipmunk were thinking so she quickly put a stop to it. She climbed down from Benjamin's shoulder and with her little arms waved at Chesterfield and Barnaby as quickly as she could.

“Now, listen here. I know what you're up to. You two are selfish brats and you want to use Benjamin for your own gain. That's not going to happen on my watch. I'm going to make sure Benjamin finds the king who can set him free. Is that clear?”

“Yes, ma'am,” they said in unison while Myrna continued to hold onto their noses.

“Good! So, first thing is first. You are to tell no one that Benjamin is capable of dreaming on his own. No one will know that he is creative and has a vivid imagination. OK?”

“Yes, ma'am,” they repeated again in a nasally voice.

“And secondly, you are going to tell us how to get to the nightmare castle.”

Both Barnaby and Chesterfield pointed to a large basket on a branch outside the tree. It was a gigantic basket made of steel and wire that looked like it had been used a thousand times. The basket was nearly ten times the size of Benjamin and looked like it weighed twenty times as much. Inside, Benjamin could see many opened walnuts as well as various fruits.

Benjamin looked at all of the walnuts and then looked at the basket.

“Where does that basket go?” Benjamin asked the two of them.

“It goes to the castle,” Chesterfield said. “It's going to be picked up today.”

“A hawk comes to pick it up,” Barnaby qualified.

“OK,” Benjamin said. “I'm going to hide underneath a blanket in that basket and the hawk will take me to that castle.”

Myrna didn't like the sound of going to Aloysius Trenhaile's castle but Benjamin knew this was a smarter way to find King Bernard Zwirn. He would be delivered to wherever the food was taken and then he could search for the king. He was proud he had stumbled upon a quite logical plan. But, there was one more detail.

“And, you two are coming with me,” he said as he pointed to Chesterfield and Barnaby. The squirrel and the chipmunk swallowed hard and then let out a long sigh. Their faces turned white and their limbs went numb. They knew that Benjamin was not giving them an option. They had to go along with him.

Benjamin had a feeling that these two animals weren't that bad. He felt like they would be nicer to others if Aloysius didn't enslave them. If they were free, they could be friendlier, he thought.

For a few hours, Benjamin, Myrna, Chesterfield, and Barnaby waited in the basket together. They were all hidden under a blanket that Chesterfield kept in a closet whenever he needed to cover the basket when it rained. Every time someone made a noise, Myrna stuck her finger to her mouth and shushed as loudly as she could. Each time, Benjamin laughed because Myrna was making more noise than everyone else but she didn't realize it. And when they all heard a hawk call in the distance, they stayed quiet. The hawk arrived and Benjamin realized it was nearly twenty times bigger than he. He wanted to see it. Just a glance, he thought. As he tried to peel the blanket down, Myrna grabbed his nose. Chesterfield did, too. And, Barnaby did as well. None of these animals wanted the hawk to see them. And so, Benjamin had to be satisfied with what he heard and smelled.

The hawk was far from graceful and Benjamin feared for his safety. He wondered if this was a good idea. The hawk moved in the air like Benjamin jumped on the ground. Everything tumbled around in the basket.

“So, this is what it's going to be like to fly,” Myrna said to Benjamin.

“How much longer do you think it will be?” Benjamin asked.

“Well, it's the same one that always comes to pick up the basket,” Barnaby said as he held onto a watermelon for dear life. “And since he comes every two weeks, I'd have to imagine it would take us a week to get to Aloysius Trenhaile's castle.”

“A week!” Benjamin asked with confusion.

“If Aloysius treats the hawk like he treats us, he won't be giving the hawk any resting time,” Chesterfield said.

“But, we won't starve!” Barnaby said as he watched all of the food bounce up and down.

“We won't survive up here for a week,” Benjamin said to himself. There was no way that they could sleep and there was no way that they could keep food in their stomachs. This bird needed to land, Benjamin thought. This was too dangerous.

Without thinking, Benjamin peeked around the blanket to see the large hawk flopping its wings above. He felt Myrna, Chesterfield, and Barnaby grabbing his legs to prevent him from leaving. Benjamin was not going to leave but he wanted to know if he could see a castle in the distance. He saw that he was much higher above the ground than he expected. The ground was thousands of feet below him and he was miles away from Chesterfield's tree. Benjamin had never been this high above the ground in his life. He watched with amazement as a river carved its way between rolling green hills into a mountain range capped with white tops. A volcano in the distance puffed smoke into the air next to a lake, which glistened under the beaming sun. He could see meadows stretch for distances he could not imagine walking and canyons that he could not imagine traversing. He didn't know where he was but he did see a castle in the distance.

“I see it!” Benjamin said to his fellow passengers.

“Already?” Chesterfield said.

“That doesn't sound right,” Barnaby offered.

Myrna looked at Benjamin with unease. She knew that he did not want to be in the basket thousands of feet above the ground any longer. She knew he wanted to go down to the ground.

“I definitely saw a castle,” Benjamin repeated.

“You saw a castle but how do you know it's Aloysius Trenhaile's castle?” Chesterfield asked.

“I don't know. Has anyone been there?”

“Only the hawk has been there!” Barnaby said. “I suggest we wait until the hawk has landed. When the hawk has landed, we'll know that we're in Aloysius Trenhaile's castle.”

Benjamin couldn't disagree with Barnaby's logic. He knew that the squirrel was wise, despite also being selfish. But, Benjamin definitely saw a castle. It looked like a set of crystal buildings sitting upon a hill. It didn't feel like the castle for an evil villain but Benjamin had never met an evil villain to know where they lived. He was convinced that the crystal castle was indeed where Aloysius Trenhaile lived.

“Benjamin, when did you first realize you could control your dreams?” Chesterfield asked from seemingly nowhere.

“What do you mean?”

“You can control what happens in reality by dreaming. I read a lot about this and I used to be able to do it. I can't any longer but I know that you have this gift. I saw you do it. You just don't know how to control it. For example, if you dream that this walnut in my hand grew to be double in size, it would be double its size after your dream ended.”

“I can control my dreams?”

“It's not an easy thing to understand. But, yes. You can control your dreams. I saw how you climbed up the side of the tree trunk. You couldn't have done that if you didn't dream you were doing it.”

“But I just go to sleep and dream. Or, my mind wanders during the day and I dream.”

“So, you never knew you were special?”

“I don't think I'm special.”

“That's very humble of you but you are special.”

“I guess, when I think about it, I first realized I could control my dreams when I flew in the castle.”

“You flew?” Myrna asked with surprise.

“Only for a moment and I wasn't able to do it again,” Benjamin said.

“I think with a little training, you could fly more often,” Chesterfield said.

“Really? How?”

“You can control those dreams. Let me help you. We can start with something very basic. Can you imagine that this walnut turned purple?”

“Purple?”

“Yes, purple. Imagine it's purple.”

“It's obviously not purple.”

“That's right. It's your job to imagine it turning purple. Close your eyes. Imagine this walnut turned purple. Don't think about anything else. Only think about your dream. Focus on dreaming. Dream about changing this walnut's color.”

Benjamin closed his eyes and squeezed them tightly. He tried to dream about the walnut changing colors. He thought so hard about it but then he felt a hand on his head.

“Relax!” Chesterfield said.

Benjamin open his eyes and stared at Chesterfield.

“This is hard,” Benjamin said softly.

“You can do it. You can dream. You just have to relax and believe in yourself. Relax and let your mind gently fall into your control.”

Benjamin closed his eyes again and relaxed his body. He started to think about changing the walnut's color. But then, he stopped. He noticed that he was not relaxing his mind.

“It's not easy,” Chesterfield said. “But you know you can control your dreams when you're comfortable letting yourself relax. Guide your dreams. Don't force them.”

Benjamin took a deep breath and then dropped his shoulders. He thought about Jupiter running around his family home. There were tennis balls outside and Jupiter ran from one to another, barking at each of them. Benjamin picked one of them up and threw it as far as he could. Jupiter chased after it and returned it. When Benjamin looked at the tennis ball, he noticed that Jupiter also brought a walnut back from the tree at the end of the yard. It was the tree that Benjamin loved to climb. He frequently read books at the top of it. The tree was his escape from the world. It was one of his favorite places. Benjamin then imagined that all of the walnuts in the tree were no longer a boring brown color but every color imaginable. There were blues and reds and greens and oranges. There were blacks and whites and yellows and grays. And in his hand, the walnut was purple. And then, Benjamin imagined that the walnut in Chesterfield's hand was also purple. He imagined that it transitioned color from brown to purple instantly.

“That's it!” Chesterfield shouted. “You did it!”

Benjamin opened his eyes and saw that Chesterfield holding a purple walnut in his hand. He did it. He still wasn't sure how he did it. But, Chesterfield taught him how to control his dreams.

“That was amazing, Benjamin,” Myrna said.

“Well done,” Barnaby added.

“Now you can do anything. You can dream, Benjamin,” Chesterfield said. “All you have to do is close your eyes and imagine. Let your mind drift away and gently guide it however you'd like. Follow your dreams.”

“Thanks, Chesterfield,” Benjamin said with a newfound respect for his friend the squirrel.

Suddenly, the hawk shook the basket from side to side. And then, it did it again. And, again. It was a violent shaking that caused all of the contents in the basket to trade places with each other.

“We must be getting ready to land,” Benjamin said with enthusiasm.

“That's impossible,” Barnaby said. “We've only been flying for a number of hours.”

Chesterfield and Barnaby shared a confused expression as the hawk shook the basket even more. As Benjamin gripped the walls, Barnaby poked his nose from the basket to look outside. He quickly pulled his head back in.

“We're under attack!” Barnaby said.

“Under attack?” Myrna responded. “Under attack by who?”

“There are people on the ground who are firing rocks at the hawk. They are trying to knock it down.”

The hawk shook the basket from side to side again. Benjamin started to worry that his assumption was incorrect. The bird was not going to land safely. The bird was going to crash to the ground with the basket in tow. The basket bounced up and down and the animals held on for their lives.

Benjamin looked outside and saw objects being fired passed the hawk at amazing speeds. One flew by and then another. And then, another. He looked in the direction from which they were coming and was able to see a group of people near a river. They were trying to shoot the hawk.

The bird swung left and barely escaped getting hit. Then, it banked to the right and avoided several more shots. Benjamin held onto the basket as tightly as he could, fearful that either the hawk was going to drop them or that it would be hit.

The hawk jerked to the right and several walnuts flew from the basket to the ground below. Benjamin gripped the side as tightly as he could. The hawk began to spiral to avoid the shots being fired at it.

“Benjamin!” Barnaby yelled. “Please save us!”

Something hit the hawk square in the head. The bird, the basket, and the animals were in free fall headed straight for land. Feathers flew everywhere and the hawk screamed in panic. Benjamin screamed too. He was crashing into the earth and this was not part of his plan. The air moved so fast that Benjamin could not tell how close he was to disaster. He didn't know what he could do. But something about what Chesterfield said made sense to him.

He closed his eyes and tried to ignore the sounds of the basket crashing to the earth. If only, he thought, the basket would land on something soft. He didn't know what it could be. But if the basket could land on something soft, they would be fine. But he couldn't imagine what that would be. Whenever he dreamed before, he was comfortable. At that moment, he was as far away from comfort as he could be. He opened his eyes and saw the three animals looking at him and he realized then how much he was needed. They depended on him and that made him confident. And as he started to feel confident, he also realized that despite the dire situation in which he found himself, he felt a little more comfort.

Benjamin shut his eyes again and imagined how a basket could land on earth. It could be a pillow, he thought. But, there was no pillow big enough. It could be a big cotton ball, but that didn't feel right either. It could be a gigantic mattress. But that, too, didn't feel normal. Neither did a sofa or a chair or a silk hammock. But then something did feel comfortable. The basket could land in a big pile of feathers. The feathers absorbed the basket and Benjamin imagined them falling all around as the animals and fruit slowed to a gentle landing on the ground. It was a beautiful dream, he thought. He opened his eyes and saw what he had done.

“Well done, Benjamin!” Chesterfield said. “I'm very proud of you!”

Benjamin was proud of himself. He felt like he had controlled his dreams. He was able to guide his imagination.

“Are you sure we didn't just land on the bird?” Myrna said as she pointed to all of the feathers.

Benjamin didn't see the bird but he did see a gigantic pile of feathers. And so, it may have been that the basket landed on the bird. Or, maybe, he thought, he did dream that the basket landed on a pile of feathers from his imagination. He wanted to know whether the hawk was there but he heard footsteps and shouting from a few hundred feet away.

“We have to hide,” Barnaby said.

“Who is that?” Benjamin asked.

“They shot down the bird,” Chesterfield said. “I don't want to find out. If they're trying to destroy Aloysius Trenhaile's hawk, they might be worse than he is.”

“We should hide, Benjamin. Hurry!” Myrna said.

Benjamin didn't know how many people were running toward him but he guessed it was a dozen. He ran to a boulder against the side of a mountain cliff and stayed as still as he could. After a minute, they saw a shadow cast near the feathers. And then, another. And, another. There were more than a dozen people together.

“There's our food,” said a voice.

“Pick it all up,” said another.

“Let's take the basket as well,” said another.

“Don't leave a trace here. We don't want anyone to track us down,” said another.

Benjamin couldn't see the people but he heard them gather the basket and pick up the walnuts and all of the other foods. The shadows moved quickly and Benjamin's curiosity grew. He leaned against the boulder and slowly started to move to its edge. He peeked around the side and saw lots of people dressed completely in blue. They were all wearing sunglasses. Barnaby yanked Benjamin back before he was seen.

“Is that the bird?” said one of the people dressed in blue. “Where did all those feathers come from?”

“Nope. That's not the bird. These feathers are a different color.”

Chapter 22
Return

Benjamin waited until the hunting party had left before he moved from behind the boulder. They were all quiet. They did not know whether those people could rescue them or hurt them. But, Benjamin was not going to take a chance. He needed to make sure that they all were safe.

“Are we ready to move on?” Barnaby asked.

“I think so,” Benjamin said. “I'd sure like to know what that was all about.”

“I've never seen anything like that before. They must not work for nightmares,” Chesterfield said.

“Who could they work for?” Myrna asked.

“The dream castles,” Selma said from the other side of the rock.

Benjamin paused and turned his head quickly to see where the sound had come from. He saw familiar shoes, familiar clothes, and a familiar grin. She looked like she had fared better than he had imagined.

“Selma!” he yelled.

“Hi, Benjamin,” Selma said with a light laugh. She twisted her right foot into the ground and looked from side to side quickly. For a moment, Benjamin thought that she was happy to see him.

“You're alive!” Benjamin said.

“Of course, I'm alive,” Selma laughed. “Why would I not be alive?”

“I thought you had been kidnapped. I thought you were with King Bernard Zwirn.”

“No, I wasn't kidnapped. I left.”

“You left? What do you mean you left?”

“I decided that I was going to find King Bernard Zwirn and bring him back. So, I left the castle and here I am.”

“That's crazy. We were really worried about you.”

“You were?”

“I didn't know what to think but I thought something awful happened to you.”

“Were you going to be my hero?”

“I don't know about that but I was going to find you. And, here you are.”

“Here I am. But, what are you doing here?”

“That's a long story. But, most recently, I was shot down from the sky.”

“Oh, I saw that. Lucky landing, right?”

“I guess so. Thalia Nachamie kicked me out of the castle. He blamed me for everything that had gone wrong but I know he's responsible. I heard him talking to Russell Fox and I think Russell Fox is actually—”

Selma reached forward and put her hand over his mouth. Benjamin looked into her eyes and felt surprised by her sudden touch. He was shocked by how smoothly and gently she stopped him from talking.

“I know what you're going to say and you're right. We can't talk about that, however.”

Benjamin heard coughing several feet behind him. He turned to see Myrna standing with her arms at her side suggesting that she was waiting for Benjamin to introduce her to Selma. Chesterfield and Barnaby stood on either side with light grins.

“Oh, Selma these are my friends.”

“You made friends out here? How long have you been out here?”

“Hi, I'm Myrna,” Myrna said as she ran up to Selma to shake her hand. Selma bent down and shook Myrna's hand. “I've heard a lot about you! I think that—”

“I'm Barnaby,” Barnaby said as he walked past Myrna. “You seem like a very nice person.”

“Thanks, Barnaby. It's nice to meet you as well.”

“My name is Chesterfield,” Chesterfield said as he shook her hand.

“Nice to meet you as well, Chesterfield,” Selma said with a smile.

“Barnaby and Chesterfield, I was having a woman to woman talk with Selma,” Myrna said with her hands on her hips. “If you two wouldn't mind, I have quite a few questions I've been meaning to ask.”

“Myrna, I think you should let Benjamin and Selma catch up,” Barnaby said.

“Let's go find some berries to eat,” Chesterfield said to her.

“Fine, I guess girl time can wait,” Myrna said. “Besides, she's probably allergic to the berries as well. We'll have to eat them all.”

Benjamin watched his three friends walk to a some plants and search for berries. He smiled as he watched Myrna continue to look back at Selma. Barnaby guided her further and further away.

“So, you were kicked out of the castle,” Selma said as she walked slowly away, her eyes focused on something in the distance.

“Thalia Nachamie is an evil person and Russell Fox, well, I guess you know,” Benjamin said. “But, you really shouldn't have left without telling anyone. There were a lot of people who were worried about you. Your brother didn't know where you were.”

“Rodney worries too much,” Selma said as she paused her stroll.

“He didn't know any differently. You suddenly disappeared and we thought you were kidnapped. I thought you were going to be with King Bernard Zwirn.”

“If I told people what I was going to do, I wouldn't have been allowed to leave. I had to leave. I had to go find King Bernard Zwirn. There's no one else who can stop Thalia Nachamie and save the castle. He's the only one.”

“Do you know where he is?”

“I think I know who kidnapped him but I don't exactly know where the castle is. If I did, I'd probably be there by now. It wasn't as easy being outside the castle as I thought it might be.”

“Tell me about it,” Benjamin said. “I've seen some things I didn't expect to see.”

“A huge, talking squirrel? A tiny caterpillar?”

“Talking trees, too.”

“It's not paradise out here, Benjamin.”

“Rodney's going to be so happy that you're safe.”

“Rodney will be fine. He and I are different. Rodney will sit and hope that things better. I can't do that. I have to stand up and make things better.”

“I can see that.”

“See what?”

“Well, you're here. You're in the middle of nowhere trying to make something better. But, why go about it all alone? Why not find other people to help you?”

Selma sat on a rock and stared back into the distance. A cloud was beginning to cover the sun and the sounds of Myrna, Barnaby, and Chesterfield searching for berries filled the air.

“There wasn't anyone to ask, Benjamin. No one was going to help me.”

“Rodney would help you.”

“Rodney wouldn't help me.”

“Why not?”

“Rodney and I are very different. He gets over pain quickly, somehow. I don't know how he does it. He can somehow forget pain and suffering as if it never happened. I can't do that. I never forget pain. I have to do something about it. I have to make sure it never happens again.”

“Who caused the pain?”

“We don't talk about it.”

“So at this point, I know who we're talking about. What did he do?”

“It started before I was born. My parents were two of the most creative people in Castle Ehtahl. They had dreams beyond what I could imagine. They dreamed of far away places where every day was better than the day before. They dreamed of parties and celebrations where everyone left with a state of happiness that lasted for days. And, they dreamed of worlds where people treated each other well and fairly and honestly.”

“That all sounds great.”

“It was great. It was their dreams. They had the creative minds to imagine how to make these dreams. But, that was when problems started.”

“What was the problem?”

“Not everyone wanted these dreams. They didn't like my parents for their creativity. They could imagine things that no one else could imagine. And, that made a lot of people jealous and upset. They didn't understand why my parents should say what the dreams should be. They didn't want to see these dreams. They wanted their own dreams and they feared people who had a bigger imagination than they did. My parents' imaginations were unmatched. You're the only person I've heard of who has as close a creative mind.”

“Me?”

“Don't act so surprised. You know you have a great imagination. We all know it. They could dream better than you could dream.”

“So where are they now?”

“They created the dream machine as a way to broadcast dreams to other places. When it was finished, people like you could have better dreams. But as soon as it was done, my parents were kidnapped and taken away by a nightmare. I haven't seen them since. That was a long time ago. No one knows where they are. I had nightmares for years afterwards. Every night I had one. And, it was always the same nightmare. I saw this boy our age at the end of a city block. There was no one else around. As I approached him, he didn't move. He just scratched his head. As I got closer, I noticed that he wasn't looking at me. He was looking at something behind me. Whenever I looked behind me, I couldn't see anything. And then when I turned around again, the boy was gone. Instead, there was a monster.”

“A monster! Did it have huge teeth and sharp claws? Was it really tall and strong?”

“I think most monsters are like that,” Selma said with a smile. “But, I think we probably saw the same monster.”

“You saw it too?”

“Yes, I saw it every day for years.”

“Did it try to attack you, too?”

“No,” Selma said slowly. “It didn't. It just stared at me. And, I just stared back at it. I wasn't going to run away from it. It did scare me the first couple times I saw it. My hands sweat and my heart raced. But, I learned over time to stare at it. It would stare back. It would never harm me. I don't know why it didn't. It just stared at me. Eventually, it would laugh, loudly. And then, I'd wake up.”

“Why did it laugh?”

“I don't know. I don't even know why I didn't run away.”

“You didn't run away because you're brave.”

“Maybe. I think I didn't run away because I couldn't. I didn't have anywhere to run to. I wanted to find my parents. I knew that it knew where they were. I wasn't going to run away from the possibility of finding them again.”

“Are you trying to find them now? Is that why you're outside the castle?”

“No, I'm trying to find King Bernard Zwirn. He can find my parents. I can't find them.”

“I hope you find them.”

“Thanks. I hope I find them, too. But first, we have to find King Bernard Zwirn.”

“We?” Benjamin asked with surprise. He did not expect Selma to include him in her adventure.

“Yes, we,” she said. “I don't think either one of us can do this alone. Can you find King Bernard Zwirn by yourself? I'm impressed you're out here searching for him. You're pretty brave, Benjamin.”

Benjamin paused for a moment and looked in the direction of Myrna, Barnaby, and Chesterfield. He didn't realize he had as much in common with Selma as he did. And, he was flattered that Selma wanted his help. He needed her help, too. He wanted to be as brave as she was. She stood up to the monster. She didn't run away.

“Yes, I'd love to find King Bernard Zwirn together.”

“Great,” Selma said with a smile. “Where were you thinking about going next?”

“Well, I saw a castle while we were in the air. I'd like to go there to see if they know where the nightmare castle is. What do you think?”

“I think that's a good idea,” she said as she twisted her feet in the dirt. “Should we go find your friends?”

“Yes, let's go find them,” he said as they walked side by side to Myrna, Barnaby, and Chesterfield.

“So,” Selma said quietly. “What's it like outside here?”

“You mean in Pennsylvania?”

“Benjamin!” Myrna scolded Benjamin from the distance.

“Yes, there,” Selma said with a light chuckle at hearing Myrna yelling at Benjamin.

“There are a lot of people. Sometimes it feels like there are more people than animals. For the most part, everyone is fine. We all do the same thing. We wake up in the morning. We drive to school or work. We eat lunch. We drive home. We eat dinner. And then we go to bed and do it all again the next day.”

“That sounds awful.”

“Well, it's really not bad. I'm probably not doing a good job describing it.”

“I don't think you are. Life outside here has to be fun, no?”

Benjamin couldn't respond quickly enough. Selma noticed that he was hesitant. It wasn't so fun, Benjamin thought.

“I'm curious, Benjamin, why you get nightmares? I told you why I got my nightmares. Why do you get yours?” Selma asked.

“Benjamin, what's so awful about your life that you've got all these nightmares?” Myrna asked as Benjamin and Selma had now reached the three others.

“My life's good!” Benjamin responded quickly.

“Good family?” Barnaby asked.

“Yep.”

“You eat well?” Chesterfield asked.

“Sure.”

“And you exercise?” Barnaby asked.

“Yeah.”

“And you get enough sleep?” Chesterfield asked.

“Yep.”

“And you're healthy?” Barnaby asked.

“I get sick once in awhile.”

“But not all the time?” Chesterfield asked.

“No, not all the time.”

“And you've got a bunch of friends?” Myrna asked

“I don't think we need to ask Benjamin questions if he doesn't want to answer them,” Selma said calmly.

Benjamin looked at her and smiled widely. He liked that she was standing up for him. He liked that he now felt closer to her.

“Yes, but,” Myrna said slowly. “Why don't you have friends, Benjamin?”

“I do have friends.”

“Do you have any friends your own age?” Chesterfield asked.

“I know people my age.”

“You have friends at school?” Barnaby asked.

“I don't know,” he said slowly as he looked at Selma. “I get teased a lot at school.”

“You get teased?”

“Yes, I get teased.”

“That's awful,” Myrna said.

“It's OK. I get teased too,” Selma said.

“You do?”

“Yes, they tease me at school.”

“Why do you two get teased?” Barnaby asked.

“I guess we're different than everyone else in our classes,” Benjamin said.

“Oh, please!” Myrna, Chesterfield, and Barnaby said at once. They all stopped walking and looked at Benjamin.

“Do you realize you're talking to a talking squirrel that runs with his eyes closed?” Barnaby asked.

“Do you realize you're talking to a talking caterpillar who creates maps of places she's never been to?” Myrna asked.

“Do you realize you're talking to a talking chipmunk who tries to get other people to do his work?” Chesterfield asked.

“Benjamin, no one is more different than the three of us,” Myrna said as she pointed a finger in the direction of Selma and Benjamin.

“In our eyes, you two are normal,” Barnaby said.

“You're so normal you're almost boring,” Chesterfield added.

“So, I think you should stop whining about being different because you're not as different as we are. And, we love how different we are,” Barnaby said. “I wish I ran with my eyes open.”

“I wish I made maps for places I've actually been,” Myrna said.

“I wish I wasn't lazy and did all my work,” Chesterfield added.

“If you think everyone else thinks they've got it great, you just don't have perspective,” Barnaby said.

“Perspective!” Myrna added.

“So, we're in agreement. There's no reason Benjamin shouldn't have friends and there's no reason that Selma should be teased,” Chesterfield said.

“Agreed!” Myrna and Barnaby said at once.

“It sounds like you two just need to be more confident,” Barnaby added.

“You've got a gift, Benjamin. You can dream! Not everyone can dream, you know,” Chesterfield said.

“And, Selma. You were out here all my yourself. You're incredibly brave,” Myrna said.

“You've got to be thankful for what you have and not worry about what you don't have,” Barnaby said.

Benjamin thought for a moment and knew that they were right. He had been dwelling on what he thought were his shortcomings that he never allowed time to think about his gifts. He was capable of making friends. He just needed to find the right friends. And with Selma at his side, he finally felt like he was heading in the right direction.

“I think your friends are right,” Selma said.

Chapter 23
Glass Castle

They walked for several hours before they saw the glass castle in the distance. Barnaby still didn't think it was Aloysius Trenhaile's castle but Benjamin was hopeful that someone there would be able to tell them where Aloysius Trenhaile lived. He knew he was close. He just didn't know how much further he needed to go. And with Selma at his side, he began to feel more confident that he would get there. He knew Selma wanted the same thing that he wanted. They wanted to stop their nightmares. They wanted to dream again. And in order to do so, they had to conquer their own fears. They needed to defeat Aloysius Trenhaile and rescue King Bernard Zwirn.

“Are you ready to see another castle?” Selma asked Benjamin quietly.

“Of course,” Benjamin said. “I'm always up for adventure.”

Ahead of them, a large glass drawbridge much thicker and taller than the one at Castle Ehtahl stretched across a moat of chipped red glass. The walls, too, were a blue glass that offered a view into what was hidden behind them. Through the wall, Benjamin saw that everything else was made of glass of varying colors. This was the castle he had seen from the distance. It was a castle made entirely of glass.

“This isn't Aloysius Trenhaile's castle,” Benjamin said.

“No. If this were Aloysius Trenhaile's castle, all of the glass would be broken,” Chesterfield added.

“I've heard about this,” Myrna said. “This is Castle Ehtsetra. This is where daydreams come from.”

“How do you know?” Benjamin asked.

“I met someone from here once. I gave her some maps,” Myrna said. “It turns out those maps I gave her were not accurate. I hope she's OK right now.”

A figure moved back and forth on the other side of the drawbridge, pacing like a guard and looking through the glass at Benjamin. He did not seem thrilled to see visitors. Benjamin, however, was excited to see him.

On their side of the moat, Benjamin saw a blue button that looked like a doorbell. He moved his hand to press it because that's what he did whenever he saw a button. But as soon as he moved close to it, Myrna jumped in front of him and gave him an unsatisfied look.

“There's a certain way that you push a doorbell,” Myrna said. “Each way you push the doorbell tells the guard on the other side where you come from. And if you don't push the doorbell in any kind of recognizable way, he'll assume you're a nightmare or some other evil thing.”

“How do you push the doorbell?” Selma asked curiously.

“Well, we are going to act as delivery people. We don't want to raise any suspicions about what we're doing here. We'll be delivery, um, news,” Myrna said. “So, it'll be tap, tap, long, tap, long, tap.”

“So these are secret passwords?”

“Not really,” Myrna said as she approached the doorbell. “It's just that evil villains can't be bothered to slow down and think about anything for a little bit. They know the patterns. Evil is just always in a hurry for whatever reason. They never stop and take their time.”

Benjamin watched Myrna tap the button, tap it again, press it for a long time, and then tap, long, and tap. The guard on the other side of the glass stopped marching back and forth and appeared to put his hands on the glass drawbridge to try to see who was on the other side. A muffled noise came out of the blue button that seemed unintelligible at first.

“Who goes there?” said the guard from the other side.

“Delivery!” Myrna said.

“Delivery? There are no deliveries on Saturdays.”

“It's a special delivery.”

“What are you delivering?”

“We are delivering news.”

“We have plenty of news, thank you. What kind of news?”

“New news!”

“I'm sure we've heard it already.”

“You couldn't have. It's new news.”

“There is no news on the weekends.”

“We're a few days late. It should have been Thursday but we had to make sure we had our facts right.”

“So this is late news?”

“It's late news for us but it's still new news for you.”

“What is this news?”

“We can't tell you.”

“Why not?”

“Because then it would no longer be new news. It would be old news and no one wants old news. That's history.”

“To whom are you delivering the new news?”

Myrna paused and thought for a moment. Benjamin wanted to help her but he didn't know what her plan was. He had no idea who should receive the news. It seemed like it could be anyone, he thought.

“The news is for the queen!” Myrna shouted.

The drawbridge jolted and then slowly leaned forward as smoothly and gracefully as a massive sheet of glass could move. It glimmered in the sun, reflecting different shades of blue and orange. It was the most beautiful bridge Benjamin had ever seen. And as it lowered further, he saw that Selma was grinning. She must be excited to go inside as well, he thought. But just as the drawbridge was about to come to a stop, it jolted two inches. It hit the base and shattered into a thousand pieces. The sound reminded Benjamin of when he broke a light bulb in the basement while throwing tennis balls to Jupiter. Everyone's eyes stared as all of the pieces of the bridge fell into the moat below. The guard on the other side, too, was shocked by what had just happened. He stood with his hands in the air in disbelief.

“You must be kidding!” he shouted.

“Do you have another bridge?” Selma shouted back.

“No, this is the only one. It makes sense that it would break. We've never had to lower the bridge before. No one ever comes here except for the nightmares. I don't think we ever tested it. A glass bridge? Who were we kidding? That was going to shatter the moment we tried to use it. Like now. It shattered. There's a million pieces in the moat!”

“Is there any other way to get into the castle?” Benjamin shouted.

“Nope, there's no other way. You're going to have to come back. Or, you can wait there. But, it'll probably take months so I don't think you want to wait there for months.”

“We are not waiting here for months,” Myrna said with disgust.

“What are we going to do? Should we just leave?” Benjamin asked his friends.

“Well, Benjamin, there is a way to get to the door,” Chesterfield said. “It's like I told you last time. You can imagine that we cross this moat and if your imagination is strong enough, we'll surely make it.”

Chesterfield pushed Benjamin toward the edge of the cliff where the bridge was to begin. Benjamin saw that the moat was much deeper than he had imagined. He could barely see the remains of the glass bridge below.

“Close your eyes,” Chesterfield said.

“I don't know, Chesterfield. That's a long way down,” Benjamin said.

“Trust me. Do you trust me?”

“Yes, I guess I trust you.”

“I'm not going to let you fall. I'm going to teach you how to walk across air.”

“Yes, I guess I trust you.”

“You have to trust me. If you don't trust me, you're going to fall into the abyss.”

“I'm not sure I like this,” Myrna said softly.

“I know I wasn't nice to you before, Myrna. But, I promise I'm better than that. I'm really not that bad. I was just in a bad situation. I was only thinking of myself. But now, I'm trying not to think of myself. I'm trying to help Benjamin. I want to help him find the king,” Chesterfield said to Myrna.

“Fine,” Myrna said with an almost visible smile in her eyes.

“OK, I trust you, Chesterfield,” Benjamin said.

“Close your eyes and take a deep breath,” Chesterfield said. Instinctively, everyone else closed their eyes and took a deep breath. The guard on the other side of the moat stared at them with his arms crossed. “Imagine there's a bridge in front of you. It's a wooden bridge. It's older and many people have crossed it before. Light brown wooden beams stretch all the way along its floor from where we're standing to the edge of the castle. A breeze blows leaves into the air and you watch them tumble across the ground. Now, Benjamin, what else do you see?”

Benjamin paused for a moment and thought about what Chesterfield described. He saw the covered red bridge before him and thought that it might be real. It was always at this moment that Benjamin recognized that he was imagining something. And, he knew, he needed to stop thinking about imagining. He needed to let himself go. He took another deep breath and let his mind fall further into the bridge.

“There's a bird's nest in the ceiling of the bridge, about halfway down. It's been there for a while and isn't used any more. The wind tries to blow it away but it stays strong. It doesn't fall over. There are several windows in the bridge that are framed in white against the red walls. As I walk forward, the wood creaks very lightly below me,” Benjamin said.

“Benjamin,” Chesterfield said very gently and slowly. “Can we come with you?”

“Yes, everyone steps forward and the bridge moans a little bit. We take another step and the wood creaks again. And after another step, the bridge has given up moaning. It lets us walk across it. Barnaby stares at all of the wooden beams in the ceiling while Chesterfield runs ahead to see the bird's nest. Selma skips across the bridge to the other side and Myrna runs ahead and follows behind her. I'm about halfway across the bridge when I look at the ground to see all the lines in the wooden floor. Everyone else walks to the end of the bridge and then I slowly walk there, too. We're on the other side. We crossed the red wooden bridge,” Benjamin said.

Benjamin felt arms grab him from all sides. He opened his eyes and saw that all his friends were jumping around him with excitement. He didn't see a wooden bridge. He saw the moat below. But, he was on the other side of it. He was standing next to the guard who had his arms on his side and his head twisted to his left.

“What in all that is good was that?” the guard yelled.

“That was amazing, Benjamin,” Selma said.

“Benjamin, you're getting much better at this,” Chesterfield said. “Soon, you'll be able to imagine whatever you'd like.”

“I still don't understand how I was able to do that,” Benjamin said.

“I don't understand either!” the guard yelled.

“You imagined it,” Chesterfield said. “Everyone is creative. Everyone has the ability to dream. You've got such a great imagination that you can make it real!”

“That was really amazing, Benjamin,” Selma said. “You do have a pretty good imagination.”

“So,” the guard said abruptly. “You have new news?”

“Yes, sir!” Myrna said. “Hope you don't have to be the one to clean up all the broken glass.”

They walked inside the castle. There were glass roads and glass trees and glass chairs and glass sidewalks. There were glass trains and glass skyscrapers and glass cars driven by otherwise normal looking people. It was nearly ten times as populous as Castle Ehtahl and one skyscraper in particular appeared to soar so high into the blue sky so as to touch the sun.

“That's where we're headed,” Myrna said as she watched Benjamin and Selma's eyes look higher and higher.

Barnaby and Chesterfield nudged Benjamin forward. They walked among the hundreds of people moving to and fro. Each of the citizens had expressionless faces, their eyes hidden by dark sunglasses. Many people carried glass briefcases and just about everyone was wearing white clothing except for an occasional person wearing blue.

“Where are we going?” Benjamin asked.

“The queen is the only person who knows where the nightmare castle is,” Myrna said.

“Why is she the only one?” Selma asked.

“The fewer people who know anything about nightmares, the better,” Barnaby added.

They walked to an elevated tram station and joined the lines of people waiting for the next train. When it arrived, it was made of nothing but bright green glass and it slid across an orange glass railway. They rode the train for a half an hour, moving throughout the city and stopping at various elevated train stations along the way. The glass structures allowed Benjamin to see into buildings that would have been impossible when they were made of steel or brick. He saw people on different floors interacting with their surroundings as if they were walking on air. And for all of the transparency throughout the buildings and structures and benches and cars, the people were as quiet and still as possible. No one uttered a word to anyone else and no one seemed capable of a smile. They all looked like cloned models of each other, walking around a pristine glass environment as quietly as possible.

“How—” Benjamin began to ask in the train car. As soon as he opened his mouth, he saw every face in the train turn in his direction. Selma looked at him and put her finger to her lips.

They exited at the next station that led them to the skyscraper at the center of the town. Hundreds of other people were entering the building as well.

“No one says anything here,” he whispered to Myrna. “How do people communicate if they cannot speak to one another?”

“Did you hear that echo when you said one word?” she responded. “Imagine if everyone were to talk at once. Our ears would explode with the noise. There would be so much sound it would be painful to hear.”

“So no one talks?”

“They do. But, they're very careful with what they say because sounds bounce off the glass loudly. They choose their words wisely.”

“Seems like a difficult way to live,” Benjamin said as they walked to the front desk.

“Or it's as difficult as living in a place where everyone says whatever they want but no one hears it.”

“I guess that's the same thing,” Benjamin said as he looked upwards and wondered how many floors he could see. It seemed that the people here had to be smart about what they said. He had not been in an environment before that required such behavior.

At the front desk, a woman wearing a white jacket had long, bushy red hair on her head which she moved from side to side in a jerky motion. Benjamin wondered how she did not hurt her neck. She was moving her head so quickly. It almost seem unnatural.

“Hello, may I help you?” the lady asked with a gentle, bouncy tone.

“Yes,” Myrna responded. “What floor is the queen's office?”

Every person in the lobby stopped and looked in Myrna's direction. The lady at the front desk stopped moving her head from side to side and stared at Myrna with a surprised expression. Benjamin could hear his heart beat among the silence of everything around him. No one moved. No one said anything. Everyone waited.

“My dear,” the lady asked as she signaled to everyone else in the lobby to carry along. “Why do you want to go to see the queen?”

“We have news!” Myrna said as she pointed to Benjamin, Selma, Chesterfield, and Barnaby.

“Oh!” the lady responded. “That's great! I thought for a second that you wanted to leave!”

The lady laughed with a sound Benjamin thought was much louder than the woman was capable of making. She heaved her head back and forth as she pounded her fist into the glass table. Others in the lobby began to laugh and then more people began to pound their fists into tables. At that moment, Benjamin heard what it was for everyone in a glass room to make a loud noise at once. It was both deafening and painful. He and Selma had their hands to their ears until it stopped.

“Yes,” she said. “Please! You must deliver your news! I hope it's new news because if it's old news, you know the queen won't be happy.”

“Our news is new,” Benjamin said quickly.

“Well, then,” the lady answered. “I suppose you had better be on your way. It's floor two hundred and eighty-eight on your right. And, please be quiet along the way. We're busy here and we can't have noise for the sake of noise.”

Benjamin felt out of place. He did not know how people could live in an environment that had such strict rules around noise and dress. It felt stifling. It felt unnatural. It felt like he was in a glass container. When they stepped into the glass elevator, he saw that the two hundred and eighty-eighth floor was the highest floor.

“I hope the queen doesn't kill us,” Barnaby said.

“Our news is new,” Myrna said. “Hopefully.”

Chapter 24
Request

The elevator stopped quickly after having ascended at a high speed and Benjamin felt his stomach touch his shoulders. A bell chimed loudly and the doors slowly parted to reveal a small hallway on the two hundred and eighty-eighth floor. They stepped from the elevator into a room shaped like a glass ball perched at the top of the glass tower. He could see nothing but blue skies, clouds, and the sun. There were no birds flying around and no planes in sight.

In the middle of the globe was a square room that had one door but no windows. A man wearing a bright white suit stood at attention in front of it and he waved his hand for Benjamin and everyone else to come near. He held a silver cane and wore a white top hat slightly tilted to the side.

“Hello there,” he said in a long drawn out voice. His voice moved up and down like the cane that he waved around in circles. “How may I help you?”

“We're here to see the queen,” Benjamin said.

“Yes, I hope so,” he said as he waved his cane in the air. “I hope you wouldn't travel all the way up here to not see the queen. But what, exactly, are you here for?”

“We have news,” Selma said.

“You have news?” the man said.

“Indeed. We have news,” Barnaby said.

“What is this news?”

“I'm afraid we must tell the queen,” Benjamin said.

“Well, I work for the queen. You can tell me anything that you'd tell her.”

“It's just that we'd tell you and then you'd have some questions and then we'd answer those questions. And then, we have to do the same thing all over again with the queen. It would be like telling the same story twice,” Myrna said as she watched the man's cane wave around.

“That does seem quite inefficient. But, I can't let just anyone see the queen. We've got security measures, you see. I have to make sure you are not a nightmare.”

“How can we convince you that we aren't nightmares?” Benjamin asked.

“That's quite easy. You would behave unlike a nightmare if, indeed, you were not a nightmare.”

“How does a nightmare behave?”

“Oh certainly you know! They largely mess everything up and turn everything upside down and cause a big chaotic scare for everyone. It's incredibly loud and annoying.”

“So, we haven't done that. We've been quite civilized.”

“You have indeed. So, I can reasonably guess that you aren't a nightmare and that our dreams are not in danger. But nonetheless, I cannot waste the queen's time. You have to give me some information about what this news may be.”

Benjamin thought for a second about what news he could possibly give someone he did not know. He needed to say something that sounded honest and that also would guarantee that he would be able to ask questions about where King Bernard Zwirn was. And then, it came to him. There was no need to overthink it. He knew a topic that would give him an audience with anyone in the kingdom.

“Aloysius Trenhaile.”

“Right,” the man said as he stopped twirling the cane. “One second.”

He ran into the white cubed room faster than Barnaby ran across the dessert.

“You know you're not supposed to say that name!” Selma said.

“But, it's true. We're not lying. We have news. And the news is about—”

“Don't say it again!” Barnaby and Chesterfield yelled at once.

Before Benjamin could utter another word, the guard reappeared with as much energy and enthusiasm as he had when he left. He shook his head from side to side and then pounded the silver cane into the glass.

“What did you say you wanted to talk about again?” he asked very calmly.

“Aloysius—” Benjamin started until the man put a finger out in front of him.

“That's what I thought. One second please,” he bowed and then slung his body around and back into the white room.

“How do we know they aren't working for nightmares?” Barnaby said. “I'm wondering if we'd be better off finding the castle on our own. We could be in a lot of trouble very soon.”

“This is a friendly castle,” Myrna said. “They're just as afraid of nightmares as we are. We'll be fine.”

The door burst open and the man slid across the floor once again. He slammed the silver cane into the ground and then regained his composure.

“Please,” he said. “Follow me. Quickly, now. Quickly.”

Seated at a small desk in the room, Benjamin saw a woman who looked like a peacock. Her hair was every color imaginable and her clothing extended as wide as the room. She wore white makeup with red splotches on her cheeks. Her earrings were made of as many pieces of glass as there were pieces in Castle Ehtahl's dream machine. They hung from her ears like stars hang in the midnight sky. As she moved from side to side, Benjamin noticed that there was more color on her than there was in the entirety of the castle.

“My name is Queen Lizette Gohara,” the queen said. “And who might you all be?”

“My name is Benjamin and this is Selma. The caterpillar is Myrna. The squirrel over there is Barnaby and the chipmunk's name is Chesterfield. We're here because I need your help.”

“It's a pleasure to meet you all. Thank you for coming here. What can I do for you?”

“I need directions to a nightmare castle.”

Benjamin looked to Myrna and Myrna gave a thumbs up in approval.

“I'm sorry. I don't quite know what you mean,” Queen Lizette Gohara replied.

“You know, we don't talk about it.”

“We don't talk about it?”

“Yes, we don't talk about it.”

“Then how can I talk about it?”

“You can talk about it.”

“About what?”

“We don't talk about it.”

“I know.”

“Can you talk about it?”

“But, we don't talk about it.”

“That's right.”

“I'm confused.”

“He means Aloysius—,” Selma started to say because she could not stand to hear this conversation continue.

“Oh! Oh, I know,” Queen Lizette Gohara responded. And then, she paused for a moment and inspected Benjamin carefully. Benjamin felt like she was looking at him in a quest to figure out why he wanted to know about Aloysius Trenhaile. “What exactly do you want from, um, well, we don't talk about it. I spend hours of my day making sure he doesn't come to my castle. I spend nights awake wondering if he'll destroy my dreams if I fall asleep. I spend a lot of energy thinking about how I can make sure he stays outside my castle walls and away from my daydreams. I've never once thought about going to his castle. That would be ridiculous. It would be crazy. It would be nuts. No one would want to do such a thing. Why do you want to do such a thing?”

“I need to rescue someone.”

“You know someone in his castle?”

“Yes, a nightmare took him hostage and he is holding him in the castle. I need to know where the castle is so I can get him back.”

“I just don't feel right about this, Benjamin. I know that we've just met and I don't have any attachment to you at all but I'm concerned for you. It's one thing to be brave but it's another thing to be blinded by the idea of being brave that one ends up making bad decisions. I think this is a bad decision. I don't know how you could survive a moment in a nightmare castle. You must understand that I want the best for you and if there was a way that I could help you, I would help you find your friend.”

“But, you can help. You can show us where the castle is. That is, of course, if you know where it is?”

Queen Lizette Gohara stood upright and quietly walked to the wall furthest away from Benjamin. She sighed and raised her hand softly to a white button on the white wall. When she tapped it, the walls disappeared and Benjamin could see all of the castle and all of the land around it. He felt like a bird perched on the top of a tree observing everything below him.

“I'm conflicted, Benjamin. Do you know what nightmares are capable of?”

“I do! He kidnapped King Bernard Zwirn.”

“Oh,” she said slowly. “King Bernard Zwirn has been kidnapped.”

“Yes.”

“That is indeed not good. I have no doubt that you witnessed an awful thing. But Benjamin, have you ever had nightmares?”

Benjamin gulped as memories of recent nightmares drifted into his head. These were memories that he hoped would vanish to never be found again.

“I've had a lot of nightmares.”

“Everyone has nightmares. We need nightmares because they help us define our dreams. But when we have too many nightmares, we lose the ability to dream. And that's what has happened to this castle and others. We're under constant attack by nightmares that fear dreamers. They enter this castle and they destroy dream after dream. There's nothing left. The only defense we have against nightmares is to make our dreams even stronger. But, we're losing the battle. Every day, there is another nightmare. They're more frequent and they're more powerful. I don't think we'll be able to dream much longer.”

“Can't you stop them?”

“I've tried every way I know how. I don't know how else to stop them. I wish I knew how but I can only continue trying to keep my dreams alive for another day.”

“Has a nightmare come today?”

“Not yet.”

“Can you show me the nightmare when it arrives?” Benjamin said confidently.

Queen Lizette Gohara lifted her head and looked at Benjamin without blinking. Selma took one step closer to Benjamin and stood next to him. He could hear the heavy breathing of Barnaby to his left and the sniffles of Chesterfield to his right. He wondered what Queen Lizette Gohara was thinking. She just stood there and stared at him.

“OK, Benjamin. I'll show you the nightmare.”

Benjamin took a deep breath as he watched Queen Lizette Gohara manage her conflicted feelings. He knew he was going to be in danger. But, he needed to see the nightmare. He needed to know what he was dealing with. He needed to convince Queen Lizette Gohara that she should show them the way to Aloysius Trenhaile's castle.

Queen Lizette Gohara led Benjamin to the control tower where she oversaw all of the daydreams. It was not too dissimilar to the room in Castle Ehtahl. There were many screens and many people making comments about what they saw. Benjamin saw thousands of daydreams and he noticed that daydreams were significantly shorter than nighttime dreams. Whereas the dreams in Castle Ehtahl would sometimes last for hours, the daydreams would sometimes last for seconds or a minute. And yet, they were just as intricate and detailed.

“A nightmare should arrive at any moment,” Queen Lizette Gohara said. “I can never tell exactly which daydream will be invaded by the nightmare. But, I'm getting very good at telling when.”

“How do you know when?” Benjamin asked.

“Well, it's like I told you, Benjamin. They've been coming more and more frequently. They don't come less frequently. And so, it's just about every hour that we have a nightmare invade,” she said as her eyes scanned the screens in front of her. “I just can't predict where.”

Benjamin looked at the screens with the same focus that he had given to his favorite television shows. He saw an old man winning an award for swimming. He saw a woman sitting on a beach. There was a young girl holding hands with a boy. And then there was a young boy playing tennis. Everything seemed normal to Benjamin because everyone was having happy dreams.

“I sense it,” Queen Lizette Gohara said.

“Sense what?” Selma asked quickly.

“Where?” Barnaby added.

“How?” Chesterfield continued.

“A nightmare,” Benjamin said softly. He kept his attention on the screens as he scanned each one for something bad.

“It's here,” Queen Lizette Gohara said as if she had repeated the same words dozens of times a day. She pointed to a screen on the opposite side of the wall. “It's attacking the dream.”

Benjamin ran to the screen that Queen Lizette Gohara pointed to. He didn't see anything unusual. It seemed like a normal daydream. There was a young boy holding a leash that led a golden retriever puppy. The dog was only a few months old and it jumped up and down as if it was the happiest it could possibly be. The boy ran with the puppy through a grass field in the middle of a park surrounded by apartment buildings. The young boy kept running and running and the puppy never left his side.

“Please stop the daydream,” Queen Lizette Gohara said to one of the operators behind her. People were scrambling to press buttons to turn the dream off.

“We can't,” one of the operators said.

“What do you mean by we can't,” Queen Lizette Gohara responded with concern.

“We can't,” the operators repeated. “We've lost full control. I think the nightmare has prevented us from shutting down the dream. We can't stop it.”

“This is not acceptable,” Queen Lizette Gohara said sternly. “These are our dream studios. We know them better than anyone else. We need to get control of them.”

“We're losing control,” the operator said. “We haven't seen anything like this before. We're losing control over the other dreams.”

“How is this possible?”

“The nightmare is taking control. We have to do something. We're going to lose control of everything.”

“Shut it down,” Queen Lizette Gohara shouted. “Shut down all the dreams.”

“All of them?” the operators echoed together.

Queen Lizette Gohara didn't hesitate. She looked at Benjamin with concern and gave him a slow, steady nod.

“Shut down everything. We need the nightmare to leave.”

“But what about the dreams?” Benjamin asked.

“We have to stop the nightmares even if it means that no one can dream,” Queen Lizette Gohara said. “This is the first time we've lost control of some of our dreams and—”

“We don't have control of any of our dreams,” the operator said.

“What?” Queen Lizette Gohara asked with concern.

“We can't shut down the dreams. The nightmare has complete control.”

Queen Lizette Gohara said nothing. She took a slow step and looked closer at the screen with the young boy running with his puppy. She lowered her head.

“I fear this is the end, Benjamin,” Queen Lizette Gohara said sullenly. “If the nightmare has control, there's nothing we can do.”

Queen Lizette Gohara closed her eyes and turned away from the screen. At that moment, the puppy transformed. It doubled in size and then it doubled in size again. As it grew, its hair grew longer and it's paws became larger. Its teeth grew ten times in size. Its face contorted and it looked vicious. Benjamin knew what it had become. It was no longer a puppy. It was now a werewolf.

The young boy screamed and threw the leash on the ground. He ran as fast as he could away from the werewolf. When the animal's transformation was complete, it roared loudly and stretched its arms as wide as it could. It looked from side to side like a rabid animal seeking a prey. Benjamin knew what the prey was. The werewolf snapped its jaw and then ran as fast as it could after the little boy.

Benjamin didn't know what to do. He didn't understand how strong nightmares were and he didn't understand how they could take control of dreams. All that he knew was that a boy was having a nightmare somewhere back home.

“You need to do something!” Selma whispered to him.

“Do something? What could I do?” Benjamin replied.

“Yes! Benjamin, you have to do something. You're the only one who can,” Chesterfield said.

“Wait, wait. Slow down everyone,” Benjamin interjected. “There's no way I can help. I don't know what to do here.”

“No, you can, Benjamin,” Barnaby said slowly. “You can stop the nightmare.”

“Fine. Let's say I could do something. What exactly could I do? That's a werewolf. How would you stop a werewolf?”

“I don't know,” Myrna said. “But, I bet you could imagine how you could stop a werewolf.”

Selma, Myrna, Chesterfield, and Barnaby stared at Benjamin with their arms crossed. Benjamin didn't know what to do because he didn't know how he could stop a werewolf. He knew that his friends wanted him to save the boy from the nightmare. But, he didn't know how. He thought about all of the ways he could stop a werewolf. He couldn't tackle it. He couldn't negotiate with it. He couldn't intimidate it. He didn't have a clue. All he knew was that the werewolf was going to create nightmares for everyone. And, according to his friends, he could stop it. But, he could imagine a red wooden bridge. He couldn't imagine stopping something alive.

“You really want me to stop the werewolf?”

Selma, Myrna, Chesterfield, and Barnaby nodded enthusiastically.

“And, you really think I can do this?”

Selma, Myrna, Chesterfield, and Barnaby nodded again.

“And, you really think I won't get hurt?”

Selma, Myrna, Chesterfield, and Barnaby shrugged their shoulders and let out long sighs.

“Fine,” Benjamin said. He had no choice. He couldn't stay here and face their four faces. He took a deep breath and then he left for the dream studio where the werewolf was terrorizing the boy.

As he walked to the studio, he wondered what he was doing. He had no business fighting a nightmare. He had no idea what he was going to do. All he knew was that his friends were convinced that he could stop it. That, he thought, was crazy. And yet, he walked towards the glass building that everyone else in the castle was running away from. It was impossible to mistake which studio had the nightmare. The roof had been torn off and smoke billowed in the air. Loud bangs and roars echoed from its orange walls. People ran past Benjamin in droves. As Benjamin watched the chaos grow in the studio, he thought about the boy that was having the daydream. He wondered what he was going through. He wondered why he deserved to have such a nightmare. He wondered how this would affect him. And only at that moment did Benjamin realize that he wasn't worrying about himself. He was worried about the boy who was having the nightmare. He would fight the nightmare, he decided. He had to help the boy. He had to protect him.

Benjamin ran to the front of the studio and threw open the large orange glass doors. He realized that by not thinking about himself, he had suddenly gained a level of courage that he had never experienced before. People screamed as they ran passed him. Benjamin pushed his way through them and looked for the nightmare. There was broken glass all over the ground from the shattered walls and ceilings. A yellow chandelier lay broken in one corner of the studio and a dozen glass statues lay in ruins. Behind them, Benjamin saw the young boy of no more than four years. He was cowering in fear. Sweat dripped from his face and his blond hair was disheveled. He looked worn and he breathed very heavily.

“Don't move!” Benjamin yelled to him. “I'm going to save you!”

Benjamin didn't know how he was going to save him. But when he said the words, he actually convinced himself that he would save the boy. He just needed to find the werewolf. The boy made eye contact with Benjamin and he pointed his small arm to the other side of the studio. Benjamin saw a large hole in a purple wall of glass that could fit a werewolf. He ran toward it and found himself in a gigantic green studio. In the center, the werewolf growled loudly.

It was nearly ten times larger than what Benjamin had seen with Queen Lizette Gohara. It soared over twenty feet tall and its huge muscles made it look like a ferocious beast capable of crushing Benjamin quickly. It was looking in the opposite direction of Benjamin. Benjamin thought that he had an opportunity to attack the werewolf by taking a broken shard of glass and hitting the beast with it. He picked up a sharp blue glass piece and began to tiptoe toward the nightmare. He took one step forward and then he took another. He was doing it. He was going to destroy the werewolf. He took another step forward and found himself only ten feet behind his enemy. The werewolf snorted and roared. Benjamin took another step forward. He was only three steps away.

Benjamin took another step and when his foot came down to the ground, he landed on an orange piece of glass no bigger than his shoe. The glass cracked in half and the werewolf stopped moving. The noise awoke the beast. It turned around violently and its eyes stared deep into Benjamin. It took a deep breath and roared more loudly than it had roared before. Benjamin's hair and shirt blew backwards. It stretched its arms wide and extended his claws that were sharper than any piece of glass on the ground. It took one swipe and knocked the glass shard from Benjamin's hand. It happened so fast that Benjamin didn't have time to react. All he knew was that he was in trouble.

He ran through the broken glass and the werewolf chased after him. Benjamin picked up a piece from the ground and threw it at the beast but the werewolf simply smacked it away. Benjamin picked up another piece of glass and threw it but the werewolf hit it away again. The werewolf then picked up a thousand pieces of glass and threw them all at Benjamin. Benjamin ducked under a table and when the last glass hit the ground, he ran as fast as he could outside the studio. The werewolf followed and Benjamin realized that he led the werewolf into the center of the castle. Somewhere, Selma, Chesterfield, Myrna, and Barnaby were watching him. They were probably as panicked as he was, Benjamin thought.

The werewolf picked up a tall glass statue and swung at Benjamin with it. Benjamin ducked out of the way at the last moment. The beast swung at Benjamin again. Benjamin jumped away again but he was losing energy. The werewolf was a lot stronger and more powerful than he was. There was no way that he could destroy the beast with muscle, he thought. He had a hard time concentrating. He wasn't relaxed like he had been when he had imagined walking across the wooden bridge. This was stressful. He was getting anxious.

Benjamin stumbled to the ground and rolled to the side as the werewolf smashed the glass statue on the ground. Benjamin thought about how he could destroy the werewolf. He couldn't tackle it. That much he had decided. He couldn't trap it. It was too quick. He was running out of time and out of breath. The werewolf had Benjamin pinned on the ground and Benjamin began to fear that this was the end. There was no way that he could destroy a nightmare. It had been a silly hope. It was not reality. In reality, he was a tiny boy who did not have the muscle to hurt a violent animal. He closed his eyes as the werewolf held a thick glass pillar over its head. It was going to pound it directly into Benjamin. If only, Benjamin thought with his eyes closed, he could knock down one of the walls of the studios near the werewolf so that it fell on top of the beast. It could come crashing down on the werewolf's back. Another wall could crash into the nightmare. And then, an entire studio could slam into it. And after that, two castle walls could slam into the beast from both sides. The nightmare would be so injured it wouldn't be able to attack. If only, Benjamin thought. If only.

After a few seconds, Benjamin realized that he had not yet been destroyed. He was still alive. He slowly opened his left eye and upon not seeing the werewolf, he opened his right eye. It was nowhere to be seen. The castle was quiet. Benjamin could feel people staring at him. He could sense something was near.

And then, the werewolf's claw appeared. It was under nearly fifty feet of glass. Its other arm appeared in the heavy glass pieces. It was under a pile of glass higher than any of the studios near it. And to Benjamin's happiness, the animal was injured. It slowly crawled out of the mess of glass pieces and knelt in front of Benjamin. Benjamin didn't know what to do. He didn't know who did this to the animal. He didn't know how it became so injured.

With the last of its energy, the werewolf stood on both legs and headed for the castle walls. Benjamin watched the beast stepping on broken glass as it exited the castle. It didn't turn around or try to attack Benjamin. It had simply left. It limped its way outside.

“You did it! You saved our castle!” Queen Lizette Gohara said as she approached Benjamin with Selma, Myrna, Chesterfield, and Barnaby at her side.

“What did I do?” Benjamin asked with confusion.

“You did that. You injured the nightmare. You forced it to leave,” Queen Lizette Gohara added with amazement.

“That was unbelievable, kid,” Barnaby said.

“I've never seen anyone as powerful as you,” Chesterfield said.

“I'm so proud of you,” Myrna said with a twirl.

“You defeated the nightmare,” Selma said. “You threw so much glass at it that it could not possibly have escaped unharmed. It was an impossible amount of glass. You stopped it!”

“I imagined that,” Benjamin said. “I didn't actually do that. I didn't move any of that glass. I didn't throw anything at him. How could I? I'm not that strong and I wasn't relaxed. I couldn't dream like I imagined the bridge.”

“You may not have the muscle but you do have the mind. You've got a very powerful imagination, Benjamin. Even if you were not relaxed, you did imagine defeating the beast,” Queen Lizette Gohara said. “And I hate to say this but I think you might be the one who can save King Bernard Zwirn.”

Benjamin paused for a moment to try to understand what had happened. Everything that he had imagined happened. But, it was different. He was learning to use his imagination and creativity but he realized he still did not have complete control of it. All he knew was that Queen Lizette Gohara was now encouraging him to go find King Bernard Zwirn. He didn't want to think about anything for too long. He wanted to go. He wanted to go save him.

“Where is the castle?” Benjamin asked eagerly.

Chapter 25
Nightmare Castle

Benjamin walked further than he had ever walked in a day. He was determined to get to Aloysius Trenhaile's castle and he was walking so fast that his friends could barely keep pace with him. He had his eyes set on an object in the distance ever since Queen Lizette Gohara pointed him in the direction. Far away, a volcano spewed lava thousands of feet into the air. Dark clouds billowed around it. The ground growled louder as he got closer. And on the side of the volcano, there was a castle so dark and treacherous that no living being could get there alive.

“That's it?” Chesterfield said with concern. “That's so much more frightening than I thought it would be.”

“That's it,” Benjamin said with a determined stride.

“I wish it was more welcoming,” Myrna said. “It would be so much nicer if there were flowers and gardens and birds and trees. I doubt there are any bunnies or deer in that castle. I doubt it smells good either. I'm not sure why anything would want to live there.”

“It sounds like the perfect environment for nightmares,” Selma said as a large ball of lava fell behind them.

“Maybe it'll just fall into the volcano,” Barnaby said as he huddled by Benjamin. “It looks worse than I ever imagined. I'm getting shakier the closer we get to it. Maybe we can turn around soon?”

“Maybe,” Benjamin said. “But, only after we save King Bernard Zwirn.”

“I don't know if I can do this,” Chesterfield said. “I really want to help you Benjamin but I'm having serious doubts here. I'm not brave enough for this.”

“It's OK, Chesterfield. I never asked you to do something you weren't comfortable doing. You don't have to come in the castle if you don't want to.”

“Chesterfield, no!” Myrna said. “You have to help. We're doing this together.”

“He doesn't have to, Myrna, if he's uncomfortable. He's already done a lot to help me. He's been teaching me how to dream,” Benjamin said.

“But Chesterfield, you have to stand up to the nightmares. You have to stand up to what scares you. You can't stop because you're uncomfortable. You've got to keep going.”

“That's so easy to say, Myrna. But in reality, there's a huge volcano with a dark, dreadful castle on the side of it,” Chesterfield pleaded.

“Myrna's right, Chesterfield. Would you rather sit back and continue to be forever in fear of nightmares? Or, would you rather stand up to them and let them know that you are to be feared?” Selma said.

Benjamin thought about Selma's words and realized that he needed to be the thing that the nightmare's feared. He needed to be the nightmare's nightmare if he was going to destroy them. If he was any less frightening, he would not be able to stop evil from continuing to frighten people.

“OK. I'll go,” Chesterfield said slowly. “But, I'm only doing it so that Benjamin can save the king.”

“Thanks, Chesterfield,” Benjamin said.

They continued marching forward and the volcano began to tower into the sky like a skyscraper standing alone on barren ground. They climbed a short incline until the incline turned into a steep hill. Lava started to fall from the sky all around them. Rocks tumbled down the hill and the ground trembled as the volcano furiously heated everything around it. The castle was only a short distance away and Benjamin got his first glance of its awful exterior. Its walls were nearly ten times as high as the walls of any of the castles he had seen. Lava dripped down their sides and what was not covered in lava was a deep black color. The only building that stretched higher than the walls was a tall dark tower with a flame at the very top. Everything was dark and dirty and covered with dust and debris. There was no clean part of the castle. And, Benjamin realized, there also was no door.

“OK, so do you have any recommendations for how we can get inside?” Benjamin asked as the volcano erupted suddenly.

“There's no door,” Myrna said. “I guess they don't want people going in.”

“Or, they don't want what's inside to come out,” Selma said.

“Either way, we have to go inside so we'll have to go over or under that wall,” Benjamin said.

They walked further up the volcano, dodging lava and ash as it fell from the sky around them. It started to get louder and noisier the closer they got to the walls, a sound that was similar to a raging cauldron of water. And as Benjamin stood behind a large boulder, he heard sounds of screaming and yelling from inside. He shivered at the sound.

“Get back!” Myrna yelled. “Get back!”

“What?” Benjamin yelled as he ducked to the ground.

At that moment, three screeching dragons the size of school buses flew overhead. Benjamin could see fire in their eyes. Their talons looked like they could break anything with ease. They flew around in a formation like they were searching for something inside the castle. The screams grew louder as the dragons hissed and snarled at something that Benjamin could not see.

“We have to climb the wall,” Benjamin said. “There's no way we can dig underneath it.”

“After the dragons leave, please,” Chesterfield said.

“I don't know how we're going to get over it,” Barnaby said. “That's steeper than anything I've ever climbed.”

“We're going to have to try,” Benjamin said.

Benjamin saw that Chesterfield was beside himself. He was looking from side to side very quickly and Benjamin realized that the chipmunk was quite nervous. Without thinking, Benjamin put his hand on his back to try to comfort him.

“I'll help you,” Chesterfield said. “I can't carry anything but I can climb walls very well. I'm so low to the ground that no one will see me. I can go to the top of the wall.”

“But once you're up there, how will you get us to the other side?” Selma asked.

“I don't know,” Chesterfield said. “I haven't thought that far. But, I'll have a look around and maybe there's a hole in the wall or something. I don't know. I'm nervous. I'll just do this to help. Someone needs to look around.”

“Thanks, Chesterfield. I appreciate it,” Benjamin said with a warmness for his friend.

As more dragons soared around the castle, everyone waited a few minutes until the beasts were out of sight. And then, Chesterfield dashed for the wall. He climbed quickly as rocks slipped underneath him and fell by his side. Lava dripped down the wall as ash poured from the volcano. Benjamin felt his heart stop as he watched Chesterfield with nervous anticipation. He was only halfway up the wall when one of the dragons flew within sight. They couldn't warn Chesterfield at this point. He was on his own. The chipmunk kept climbing and climbing as fast as he could.

“We have to distract the dragons,” Benjamin said.

“I don't know what you're proposing, but I don't want to volunteer for that,” Barnaby said.

“No, I don't want us to distract them,” Benjamin said. “We have to knock something over.”

“Like what?” Barnaby said casually as he put his hand on the boulder that they were standing behind.

Barnaby fell forward. He had accidentally pushed the boulder forward. And then, it started to roll. Benjamin, Myrna, Selma, and Barnaby hid behind another smaller boulder as they watched the huge rock tumbled down the hill. It was large enough that the dragons noticed it. They flew in its direction and hovered around it. Chesterfield had a break from the dragons to reach the top of the wall. And after he reached the top, he disappeared into the castle. Benjamin's breathing became heavy with nervousness for Chesterfield's fate. Selma noticed that Benjamin was nervous so she stood at his side. He couldn't believe she was so calm.

It was the longest minute Benjamin had experienced. They were helpless waiting on the other side of the wall. The dragons grew tired of the boulder and flew back into the castle. As time wore on, Benjamin feared that something awful had happened to Chesterfield. He worried that he would never be able to scale the wall.

But then, a long, thick rope was thrown over the side. Benjamin saw Chesterfield at the top waving his hands. And without thinking, Benjamin grabbed Myrna and Barnaby and ran for the rope. Selma ran in front of them. Hand over hand, Benjamin climbed with a strength he never knew he had. He was not worried about the dragons and he was not worried about falling. He was concentrating on getting inside the castle because once inside, he could figure things out.

He reached the top and hugged Chesterfield. He was so grateful for the chipmunk's courage. Selma pulled the rope up. Benjamin couldn't celebrate for long. As he turned around to look inside the castle, he saw the worst sight he had ever seen. On the other side of the wall was a large army of nightmarish beasts. Aloysius Trenhaile was preparing for war. He was going to destroy all the dreams.

They used the rope to climb down the other side and hid behind more rocks that had fallen from a dilapidated building. There was no safe place in the castle, Benjamin knew. They needed to be careful that they weren't seen.

Aloysius Trenhaile's castle was littered with broken houses. They lined a long lava river that flowed from the top of the volcano through the castle. There were rusty military vehicles that looked like porcupines, spikes coming out of every side. There were weapons that seemed large enough to destroy any castle Benjamin had seen. And throughout, there were trolls who grunted and growled at each other. There were skeletons that jostled back and forth. There were ghosts scattered throughout and awful spiders that Benjamin had never seen before. They looked like the horrifying creatures that could only exist in nightmares. It was worse than Benjamin imagined.

“Now what?” Myrna asked.

“We stay alive,” Benjamin said calmly. “We have to find King Bernard Zwirn. We have to find where they keep their prisoners.”

“That has to be easy,” Selma said. “All of the buildings here are broken to pieces except for that tower in the middle. He has to be up there.”

In the center of the castle was a tower that even lava could not destroy. It had a staircase that wrapped around its exterior dozens of times. Its black exterior made it almost invisible against the night sky. If it wasn't for the large fire at the top, it would be invisible among the falling ash.

“We have to go there, somehow,” Benjamin said.

He scanned the castle for an easy path to the tower but it was difficult to see given the darkness. The stairs were the most obvious choice, he thought. But, he would probably be seen by all of the beasts gathered below. If there was a way he could disguise himself, this might work. But, he didn't know how.

“I'm not sure how we'll get there,” Benjamin said.

“I guess we couldn't just take the stairs,” Myrna said.

“No, not the stairs,” Selma said. “They'll see us.”

“I think it's my turn to help us,” Barnaby said.

Benjamin was surprised that Barnaby wanted to help. He didn't expect that Barnaby would be so eager to assist. But, he was certainly happy that everyone was eager to find the king.

“What exactly are you proposing?” Chesterfield said.

“Everyone get in that cart over there,” Barnaby said.

Benjamin turned around and saw an old rickety cart ten feet away. It looked like it had fallen from the top of the tower to the ground below. It had four wheels but one of them was at an unusual angle. And, Benjamin thought, there was no motor. That was a cart that needed to be pulled.

“And then what?” Benjamin asked.

“I'll pull you up the tower,” Barnaby said with seriousness.

“You are going to pull that cart?” Selma asked.

“Up stairs?” Benjamin asked.

“By yourself?” Myrna asked.

“Yes. Yes. And, yes,” Barnaby answered. “I'm quite strong and when I get running, I can get going at a very fast pace. And, I have a gift that no one else here has.”

“What is that?” Benjamin inquired.

“I won't be scared because I keep my eyes closed when I run. I won't be frightened because I won't see anything that'll scare me.”

“Well, that makes one of us. I'm certainly scared. I'd prefer if you kept your eyes open,” Myrna said.

Benjamin thought for a moment and realized that this might work. If there was a squirrel pulling a cart through the nightmares, they might never notice. He was so fast it would be as if the cart was flying across the ground.

“This is perfect!” Benjamin yelled with excitement.

“I don't share your enthusiasm,” Myrna said.

“No, this will be great. Barnaby doesn't need to see where he's going. He keeps his eyes closed. So, we'll cover him with the tarp in the cart. It'll be like a ghost is pulling the cart. No one will notice!”

Myrna was not convinced. Chesterfield wasn't either. But, Selma was. She nodded in Benjamin's direction and that was all the confidence Benjamin needed. He grabbed Myrna and Chesterfield and jumped into the cart. Barnaby stood at the front with a large, ugly cloth on top of him and prepared to run.

The cart jolted forward and Benjamin and Selma hid as best as they could. Barnaby was running as fast as he could. He dodged between demons and flew by snakes. He sprinted by angry goblins and frightening rodents. Benjamin looked ahead to see that they were only a short distance away from the staircase. Nothing had noticed them. The dragons swarming above didn't seem to pay any attention.

But when Barnaby hit the stairs, he did not slow his speed. Benjamin and Selma were jostled back and forth with every step along the way. Benjamin did not like being thrown about in such a violent way. Barnaby pulled the cart up another step and Benjamin hit his head against the iron wall of the cart. And then another step and Benjamin hit his back against pieces of coal. Myrna and Chesterfield were being tossed around like socks in a dryer. But, Barnaby continued blindfolded. With each step, the cart bumped and bounced and flew into the air. They had only been moving for a couple minutes when Benjamin peered outside the cart to see that they were hundreds of feet above the ground. The sight baffled him. Although the tower looked high from the ground, it felt much taller. He could see the full violence and size of the volcano. He could see the frightening scale of the nightmares. He could see awful, scary things everywhere. And, he could see the top of the tower only a few feet away. The fire that he saw from the ground raged on the top floor.

When they reached the top, Barnaby fell on his side. His body inhaled and exhaled deeply. He was so exhausted that he could not hide himself from the danger that awaited them on the top floor. Benjamin did not forget that they were in Aloysius Trenhaile's castle. And, they had reached Aloysius Trenhaile's lair. Benjamin grabbed his friend and hid behind a wall.

“That was amazing!” Benjamin said to Barnaby.

“Did I do it?” Barnaby asked with one eye open.

“You did really great! Now come with me. We have to find King Bernard Zwirn,” Benjamin said.

The wind blew violently at this height. The volcano continued to spit lava into the air and ash poured down everywhere. It was difficult to see and to walk straight. They stayed along the side of the wall until they reached a room as large as a dream studio. The wind slowed and the lava stopped. The ash calmed and the air became clear. Inside this room at the top of the tower, Benjamin saw someone he had hoped to see.

“Benjamin?” King Bernard Zwirn asked.

The king was seated in an iron cage stuck in the air. Although it hadn't been a long time since Benjamin had last seen him, he looked remarkably older and weaker. Benjamin knew the king was in trouble. There was no one else in the room. There was no Aloysius Trenhaile. It was only King Bernard Zwirn and a loud, noisy machine.

“Benjamin! What are you doing here?” he asked again.

“We came to save you,” Benjamin said.

“I'm sorry this all happened, Benjamin. I didn't expect things to go this direction. But, you can't stay here. I don't know how you got in here but you're in a lot of trouble. You and your friends need to leave immediately. I don't think you know what you're doing. This is all my fault. Please, Benjamin. Please, leave. Save yourself! If my brother finds you, you're going to be in a lot of trouble and I won't be able to save you. Please, Benjamin. Please leave!”

“Your brother?”

“Yes, my brother,” King Bernard Zwirn sighed.

“Your brother is Aloysius Trenhaile?”

The fire roared and lightning struck the tower. The demons, ghosts, and horrid creatures all screamed in unison at the base of the castle.

“Benjamin, you cannot say that name!” Myrna yelled

“Where is he?” Benjamin asked quickly.

“He's coming back. He's making nightmares. Benjamin, you should leave now!”

“I'm not going anywhere,” Benjamin said. “I was kicked out of Castle Ehtahl. I am going to bring you back with me.”

“I thought Thalia Nachamie might have taken control. It isn't a good time for dreaming, Benjamin. Dreams may soon come to an end. So, you must leave. If my brother finds you, he's going to hurt you.”

There was another roar in the distance. The creatures at the base of the castle were becoming agitated. Benjamin looked outside the room and saw that they were stirring. Some were walking in circles but others were starting to climb the staircase. They were preparing to attack.

“King Zwirn, how can we destroy the nightmares?”

“We've never been able to figure it out, Benjamin. If we can stop this machine here, we'll be able to temporarily stop their production. But so long as there are dreams, there are bound to be nightmares. There's no way to stop them. They just exist. We've had to live with them.”

“But if I stop your brother?”

The beasts and demons at the bottom of the castle screamed again. They ran around and around. And then, they all started to run up the staircase.

“You're in trouble,” King Bernard Zwirn said slowly.

“He's coming,” Selma whispered to Benjamin.

Chapter 26
We Don't Talk About It

He was much taller than Benjamin expected. His body was thin like a crane. He stood like a young tree with branched arms that stretched outward like crooked sticks. His fingers pointed like long, narrow daggers. His elbows, knees, and shoulders were sharp, not smooth like a normal person's. His feet were unusually big while his ears were wide and short. His nose arched forward like a parrot's nose and his eyes sunk into his face like coals on a beach. And as he walked toward Benjamin, he moved like a sly fox stalking his prey.

“So, this is the one?” Aloysius Trenhaile asked King Bernard Zwirn amid lightning and thunder. “You told me I'd never come upon him. You said that he'd come upon me. And with what luck, here he is. What is your name, child?”

Benjamin hadn't moved. He didn't know how to interact with this man that had been so feared by so many. This man was responsible for destroying dreams in the castles and he had an army ready to destroy dreams forever. He was the reason dreams were disappearing.

“Leave the boy alone!” King Bernard Zwirn yelled from the cage. “He causes you no harm. Let him be.”

Aloysius Trenhaile walked around Benjamin several times, his legs taking long strides. His hands were behind his back. Benjamin felt like the man was going to grab him if he tried to flee.

“Bernard, that can't happen,” Aloysius Trenhaile said calmly. “Any child that comes to my castle surely is not worthy of letting free. Why is he here, Bernard?”

“He was just leaving, Aloysius! Let him be.”

“But why leave now? Don't you want to see the release of my greatest creation yet? I was just about to create a nightmare's nightmare. Stick around, boy. Don't you want to see what happens when nightmares win? Don't you want to see when dreams disappear forever?”

Chains burst from the ground and wrapped themselves around Benjamin's arms and legs so quickly that Benjamin didn't have any time to react. They tied down Selma as well. Barnaby was restrained and so was Chesterfield. Myrna was stuck in a cage that had fallen from the ceiling. They were all imprisoned.

“You can stay there,” Aloysius Trenhaile said with an annoyed, calm voice. “You'll be witness to something that will change human history. This will revolutionize the way people live. This will change the way people think. For too long, there has been a divide between the people who can dream and those who cannot. But, nightmares do not discriminate. Nightmares affect everyone. And tonight, this machine will make sure that no one dreams. The dreamers will stop dreaming and be just like the people who are unable to dream. Everyone will have nightmares and everyone will realize how much better a world that will be.”

“I don't understand,” Benjamin said meekly.

“What don't you understand? Nightmares are fair. Dreams are unfair. Not everyone can dream, boy.”

“Why don't you make dreams for the people who cannot dream?”

Aloysius Trenhaile let out a long, loud laugh that caused the fire at the top of the room to roar. Benjamin tried to avert his eyes as lava fell throughout the room.

“You assume that everyone wants to dream!” Aloysius Trenhaile screamed.

“Everyone wants a dream,” Benjamin replied.

“No!” Aloysius Trenhaile exclaimed. “Everyone does not want a dream! Lots of people want to live life without a dream! The dreamers always think that everyone should have a dream. But, they're wrong! Dreamers are unrealistic. Dreamers don't understand truths. And for that, boy, the dreamers will be punished! The dreamers will have nightmares!”

“Why?”

“They will no longer have dreams. They will only have nightmares!”

Benjamin didn't understand what had led Aloysius Trenhaile to come to this conclusion. If there were no dreamers, the world would be a sadder place, he thought. It would be filled with people who just did what they were told, people who did not think beyond what they saw, people who did not care about creativity, people who did not try to stretch their minds, people who were insecure, people who were afraid of being different, people who were exactly the same as everyone else. It seemed to be an awful place. And, it was certainly a place Benjamin did not want to live. He wanted dreams.

“Bring in the catalyst!” Aloysius Trenhaile yelled as he inspected the complicated nightmare machine in the center of the room.

A machine was wheeled in that was made of many electrical parts Benjamin could not identify. It looked so much more complicated than the dream machine in Castle Ehtahl. From four doors on all sides of the room, demons entered with various pieces of equipment. They began to plug cords into the nightmare machine and pull levers that sent sparks flying into the air. The nightmare machine was slowly coming to life.

“Oh, one more thing, Bernard,” Aloysius Trenhaile said amid the chaos of the awful creatures running around. “No one leaves here alive.”

“Aloysius, you let them go! They do no harm!” King Bernard Zwirn yelled back.

“I don't know why they're here. I assume they're here to save you. But, we both know you can't be saved,” Aloysius replied.

Trolls entered and began putting the finishing touches on the nightmare machine, which started to make lots of noise and generate more sparks. To Benjamin, the nightmare machine looked like it was going to explode. Even the demons and trolls and other disgusting beasts on the floor began to look at it with fear. Some slowly backed away and ran down the exterior staircase while others admired the lights and noises with amazement. Benjamin and King Bernard Zwirn continued to avert their eyes. It was too bright to look directly at and too loud to hear.

“Benjamin, you have to save yourself,” King Bernard Zwirn said.

Benjamin looked at the chains that held him in the air. He jostled his body back and forth but could not free himself.

“I'm stuck. I can't get myself free,” he said as he watched Selma struggle as well. “We're here to save you.”

“How did you get to this castle? How did you get up this tower? How did you find this place? How did you have the courage to find me? You can free yourself, Benjamin. You're the only one who can. You just have to imagine yourself being freed,” King Bernard Zwirn whispered. “I believe you can do it.”

Benjamin's mind started to wander as he watched pieces of lava fly into the room through the open roof above. He wondered how it was possible that he hadn't been hit by lava yet. He was glad he hadn't been hit by lava because that surely would have hurt. But with all of the pieces falling into the room, it was surprising that nothing hit him, Selma, King Bernard Zwirn, or the nightmare machine that Aloysius Trenhaile continued to work on. If only a piece of lava would fall through the ceiling and hit the iron chains, Benjamin would be free. He imagined a small piece of lava moving so fast that it would melt the chains instantly and let him free.

And the next thing he realized, the chains that had restrained him had set him free.

Aloysius Trenhaile turned to face Benjamin, his face as angry and upset as a face could look. He started to march toward Benjamin but Benjamin closed his eyes and imagined that lava was hailing down on the nightmare machine. Aloysius Trenhaile screamed and roared loudly. Benjamin opened his eyes to find that the machine had been hit by lava several times. Trolls and demons ran back into the room. They desperately tried to control the melting structure.

“You are going to die!” Aloysius Trenhaile screamed at Benjamin.

Benjamin turned but he didn't stop.

“No!” Benjamin yelled. “This stops now!”

All around him, the awful creatures of Aloysius Trenhaile's castle began to stir with confusion as to what was happening at the top of the tower. And then, the fire at the top of the castle exploded into a large fireball that forced both Benjamin and Selma to turn away. He saw demons and ghosts and skeletons falling off the staircase that surrounded the tower. Benjamin needed to save his friends, quickly. Benjamin could see that the nightmare machine had melted enough to render it unusable. But, parts of it were still functioning and it looked like it was going to explode. Aloysius Trenhaile was giving orders to all of the beasts around him to save the machine.

“Don't turn it off!” he screamed. “Keep it running and save every part!”

“Aloysius!” Benjamin heard King Bernard Zwirn yell. “You have to stop this immediately. This is no way to behave, brother.”

“Quiet!” Aloysius yelled. “If this doesn't work tonight, it'll work tomorrow. And, you'll witness it then! And you, Benjamin! How dumb must you be to stay here?” Aloysius Trenhaile asked. “You have to be so stupid to not run away. And now, what? What do you want? You want to die?”

Benjamin paused and twisted his foot into the ground. He let out a long sigh and thought really hard about why he had not left.

“Oh you must be kidding me,” Aloysius Trenhaile said with a chuckle. “You're here because you want to stop me?”

Benjamin continued to twist his foot in the ground and then he began stretching his arms. He wasn't sure what was going to happen next. He had never fought anyone in his life. He never wanted to fight anyone. It was not in his character. Through his entire life to date, he had always received the insults and punches. He never delivered them. And so, he didn't quite know what to do.

“Aloysius Trenhaile!” Benjamin yelled. “Stop the nightmares now!”

Aloysius Trenhaile laughed. There was a long silence and then, all of the beasts around him laughed. All of the beasts and nightmares throughout the castle laughed. But there were people other than Benjamin who were not laughing. King Bernard Zwirn looked scared but Myrna, Chesterfield, and Barnaby all had their hands clenched.

“I said stop the nightmares,” Benjamin said. “I don't know what I'm getting myself into. But, I know that I want you to stop what your doing.”

“And what if I don't?” Aloysius screamed.

“Then I'm going to have to stop you.”

The roars of laughter spread throughout the castle. Benjamin did not look like a threat. He knew this. He knew this his entire life. But all of that perception was going to change. If Aloysius Trenhaile was not going to stop, Benjamin wanted to stop him.

“Alright everyone,” Aloysius Trenhaile said to all the beasts. “Let's get back to saving this nightmare machine. Cool the rest of the melting sections and then—”

Aloysius Trenhaile continued to give instructions to his followers as Benjamin continued to stand there. Benjamin turned to King Bernard Zwirn and saw that he did not look as scared as he did moments before. Instead, the king clenched his fist and held it in front of him to give Benjamin his sign of support. And so, Benjamin decided that it was time for him to take things into his own hands. If he was going to get hurt, he was willing to get hurt knowing that he could save dreamers like himself everywhere.

He closed his eyes, took a deep breath, and upon opening them watched a gigantic lava ball smash into the nightmare machine destroying everything that Aloysius Trenhaile was trying to preserve. Unlike before, the beasts and creatures did not respond with panic or confusion. Everyone looked at Benjamin who was imagining another lava ball falling onto all of these demons.

With one quick motion, Aloysius Trenhaile pushed everyone away to the walls as a lava ball crashed into the room resulting in a fantastic explosion. Aloysius Trenhaile made a motion with his hands and froze the explosion as it occurred. Benjamin's jaw dropped as he watched Aloysius take the explosion and throw it thousands of feet in the air. They were fighting, Benjamin thought. He was battling evil.

Benjamin imagined destroying the walls on all sides of the room so that they stood on only a floor on top of the tower. Aloysius responded by creating a large crack in the ground that splintered through Benjamin's feet. Benjamin jumped to the side and watched a chunk of the tower fall to the ground. He picked up some of the boulders and threw them one after another at Aloysius. Aloysius collected them in midair and then threw them back at Benjamin who ducked to the ground to avoid them. Aloysius imagined snakes chasing after Benjamin. Benjamin imagined that each one of the snakes turned into doves and they flew away as quickly as they could. This was not going to be as easy as Benjamin thought. Aloysius could imagine things as well as Benjamin could.

And then, Aloysius did something that Benjamin did not expect. He transformed into a gigantic bull. Benjamin started to build a wall as quickly as he could. Aloysius breathed fire out of his snout and then proceeded to run forward. Benjamin built and built and built the wall until it was twenty feet high and twenty feet thick. And still, Aloysius charged through it like it was a stack of cards. Benjamin fell to the ground and slid to the edge of the floor. He held on tightly so as not to fall off the tower.

He imagined a lightning bolt shattering the sky and hitting Aloysius square in the back. The bull squealed in pain and Aloysius transformed back into a human body. The evil man gathered a fire and set the entire floor ablaze. Benjamin responded by freezing everything around him and then freezing the entire top half of the tower. Aloysius roared in response and then transformed into a cyclops a dozen times larger than Benjamin. He grabbed a section of the building and slammed it over Benjamin. But Benjamin imagined himself in a solid sphere and the tower broke all around him. Aloysius charged and then created a sound wave with his hands that blew Benjamin off the tower.

Benjamin was in a free fall and could feel that he was losing control. He spun every which direction and did not know how much further he had until he hit the ground. But then he imagined that like that day in the academy, he could fly. And so Benjamin returned to the top of the tower flying as high he could. He imagined a tornado headed directly for Aloysius. Aloysius responded with a hailstorm that absorbed the tornado and tried to suck Benjamin inside it.

Aloysius transformed into a dragon and began chasing Benjamin in the air while sending fireballs in his direction. Benjamin dodged each one and flew throughout the castle, trying to get away from the beast. He circled the tower again and again but Aloysius followed the entire way. Aloysius snapped at Benjamin with his teeth whenever he neared but Benjamin continued to avoid the monster. He imagined that Aloysius was stuck in an iron cage and when that cage appeared around the flying dragon, Aloysius fell to the ground with a thud loud enough to create another lava river running through the castle.

Benjamin looked down and saw that he did it. He had defeated Aloysius Trenhaile. Benjamin quickly flew to the top of the tower to find King Bernard Zwirn. He was a little shaken but he was fine. Benjamin opened the cage and let him free.

“Thank you, Benjamin,” he said.

“Are you OK?” Benjamin asked.

“Well,” the king said slowly. “I don't suppose anyone could say they felt OK after having survived what you and my brother just created. But, I'm fine. We have to leave, Benjamin.”

They turned to go and then Benjamin saw a sight that was familiar to him from long ago. When he was with the dinosaurs trying to stop Professor Undutois from destroying the planet, there was a terrifying monster. It was a monster so feared that the dinosaurs ran from it. A monster that ruined his dreams and turned them into nightmares. And at that moment, Benjamin saw that same monster jump up the side of the tower and land next to him.

The tower couldn't take the weight of this enormous beast. It swayed from side to side as another chunk of the building fell to the ground. A crack rippled through the ground to the top floor. The monster looked at Benjamin and let out a roar so loud it could be heard throughout the entire land Benjamin had traveled. Benjamin couldn't hear. The noise was so deafening. And the resulting ringing in his ears made him dizzy. He looked around and saw that King Bernard Zwirn was holding his ears and laying on the ground. He was alive but like Benjamin in a lot of danger. The monster roared again and then snapped at Benjamin.

It wants to cut off my head, Benjamin thought. But, Benjamin did not flinch. He would have to dream of something so massive that the beast couldn't stand a chance. And so, he transformed into a brilliant, large, white dragon.

Benjamin flew into the air and Aloysius gave chase. They flew around the castle several times as Aloysius continued to try to grab and thrash at the white dragon. He needed some help. He realized he could not do this alone. He could be as creative and as imaginative as Aloysius Trenhaile but he could not be so much more powerful to stop the evil man alone. Instead, he needed some assistance from his friends.

“Throw something at him!” Benjamin yelled to Selma and King Bernard Zwirn as he flew by the top of the tower.

“What?” Selma asked. “What should we throw?”

“The berries! Get the poisonous berries from my backpack.”

Selma ran to Benjamin's backpack and retrieved a bunch of the berries that Myrna had not yet eaten. She looked at them with confusion.

“They're delicious,” Myrna said quietly. “But apparently they're poisonous to humans.”

Selma threw them into the air and Benjamin imagined that they had doubled in size and quantity. He had hundreds of red berries suspended in the air. As Aloysius Trenhaile continued to chase him, Benjamin imagined that all of the berries collapsed on his nemesis at the same time. Aloysius Trenhaile was covered and he began to roar with anger. As he opened his mouth to scream, Benjamin imagined that dozens of berries flew inside. Aloysius grabbed his neck and Benjamin continued to imagine berries hitting the evil man.

Within seconds, Benjamin knew that he was right to trust everything he read in A Guide To Plants Outside The Castle Not That You'll Ever Need This Because Everyone Stays In The Castle But If You Do Here's A Book For That, I Guess. Aloysius Trenhaile had fallen asleep. And as he slept, he was finally no threat to anyone. He flew the villain to the top of the tower and King Bernard Zwirn quickly restrained his brother who at that point could no longer fight back.

The tower started to crumble around them. Benjamin knew he could save everyone. He imagined that the tower collapsed around he and his friends. He imagined that he flew his friends to safety on the other side of the castle walls. And he imagined that all of Aloysius Trenhaile's castle was destroyed beyond repair.

When he stopped dreaming, he saw that all of the monsters and nightmares were buried underneath rocks and walls of the former castle. There was nothing left but a gigantic mound of dust and lava flowing from the angry volcano.

“Well done, Benjamin,” Barnaby nodded with approval.

“That was amazing,” Selma said.

“He's also a great listener,” Myrna whispered to Selma.

“How did you and your brother grow so far apart?” Benjamin asked King Bernard Zwirn. “You make dreams and he makes nightmares.”

“He didn't always make nightmares,” King Bernard Zwirn said. “No one wants to be evil. Something happens that makes good people do evil things. My brother originally made dreams. He made some of the most beautiful, inspiring dreams you could ever imagine for people. But one day, everything changed for him. He wanted something he couldn't have. And when he realized he couldn't have it, he started getting angry.”

“What did he want?” Benjamin asked.

“He wanted to always live in a dream. It's one thing to have dreams and be a dreamer. But, we can't live in our dreams. We have to accept that reality is separate from them. He couldn't understand it and he believed that there were people who lived in dreams. And since he was unable to live this way, he decided that no one else should either. That's when he joined the castles that produce nightmares.”

“What are you going to do with him now?” Benjamin asked. “His castle's destroyed. He can't produce nightmares there anymore.”

“He can't but he could go somewhere else, if he wants. If I know my brother, he's as stubborn as I am. And so, I'd like to keep him in Castle Ehtahl for a while. I think if there's anyone who can convince him to change his ways, it'll be me. I can't send him back out into this land. The land will either kill him or he'll hurt others.”

Benjamin respected King Bernard Zwirn for not giving up on his brother. He thought it was commendable that he was going to try to change him to be good. At home, he didn't think most people behaved the same way.

“So now there are no more nightmares,” Benjamin said.

“Well,” King Bernard Zwirn said as the sun started to rise in the distance. “There are no more nightmares from Aloysius Trenhaile. It's impossible to get rid of all the nightmares, Benjamin. So long as there are dreamers, there are going to be people who want to destroy dreams. The victory today is that there will be more dreams than nightmares. And for your home, that means there will be dreams again.”

Benjamin watched the sun rise and felt that he was fine with this situation. He could dream again.

“Let's go home,” King Bernard Zwirn said. “I'm exhausted.”

Chapter 27
Guard

As they all journeyed back to Castle Ehtahl, they retold stories of how they came to be together. King Bernard Zwirn listened as Myrna explained how she found Benjamin and how they were tricked by Barnaby. Barnaby and Chesterfield talked about Benjamin forgiving them and encouraging them to stand up to Aloysius Trenhaile. They talked about the glass castle and Benjamin defeating the nightmare. But most of the time, Myrna asked Selma questions about Benjamin.

“You don't know if you had butterflies the first time you saw him?” Myrna repeated.

“Myrna, when are you going to be a butterfly?” Benjamin asked.

“Soon!” she said with excitement.

When they returned to Castle Ehtahl's walls, Benjamin felt relief knowing that he had finally made it back. Selma and he were exhausted. Aloysius Trenhaile was still unconscious. Barnaby, Chesterfield, and Myrna were tired. But, King Bernard Zwirn seemed as energetic as possible.

“Before we go inside,” Benjamin said. “You should probably know that Thalia Nachamie is in charge.”

“Don't worry, Benjamin,” the king said. “I will clear up everything in the castle. Thalia Nachamie is not welcome in my castle. I'll get the missing piece of the dream machine back and turn it on.”

“So,” Barnaby said slowly. Benjamin realized that the three animals didn't have anywhere to go. This was goodbye. They would continue to live outside the castle walls. “Should we....”

“Oh!” King Bernard Zwirn said. “Where are my manners? You three aren't going anywhere. You're going to live in Castle Ehtahl.”

“Really?” Myrna said with elation.

“Yes, really. You should not be alone. You should be with us. I don't want you three feeling lonely any longer. You deserve to be treated very well after all that you've done for Benjamin and me,” King Bernard said firmly.

“I don't know what to say but thank you!” Chesterfield said.

King Bernard Zwirn turned and pounded on the castle wall as loudly as he could.

“Who is it?” Noel Jaffin asked on the other end.

“Noel, this is King Zwirn. Let me in.”

“Ah, I've been hearing that all week. Everyone's pretending to be King Zwirn. I'm King Zwirn. You're King Zwirn. We're all King Zwirn.”

“What? Noel, this is King Zwirn. Let me in this instant.”

“Oh, right. And, I'm five feet tall and quite handsome.”

Benjamin stepped forward and pounded on the door.

“Noel, let us in!” Benjamin yelled as loudly as he could.

There was a pause on the other end. Benjamin could hear feet shuffling around and then a ladder being rested against the door.

“Benjamin? Is that you?” Noel Jaffin whispered quickly.

“Oh, so you recognize Benjamin's voice but you don't recognize mine,” King Bernard Zwirn said as he rolled his eyes.

“Sorry about that, King Zwirn,” Noel Jaffin said as the doors to the castle began to open. “We've been getting so many visitors who claim to be you. Some of them sounded nearly identical to you.”

“None of them did,” Cole said.

“Well, not exactly but they were certainly very close to how King Zwirn speaks,” Noel Jaffin defended himself.

“None of them were close,” Joel said with a long sigh.

“I didn't say exactly but I'm saying that they could have been mistaken for King Zwirn.”

“Noel, you need to get your ears checked,” King Bernard Zwirn said as he reentered his castle.

Benjamin followed behind and was so happy to be in a place that was closer to home. Selma walked at his side and Benjamin held her hand. He knew that she wanted to smile but that she was holding herself back. She was still trying to be tough.

Myrna, Barnaby, and Chesterfield entered the castle and King Bernard Zwirn stood with a hand gesturing for them to stop. He waved for them to come closer and slowly nodded his head.

“I can't let a huge chipmunk, a massive squirrel, and a tiny caterpillar roam my castle. Would you like to return to your original selves?” he asked with a smile.

“Yes!” Chesterfield screamed.

“It's been so long,” Barnaby said.

“Yes, please,” Myrna replied.

King Bernard Zwirn closed his eyes and waved his arms around the three animals. Dust swirled around them and tiny flashes of light burst into the air. Benjamin stared in disbelief, unsure what he was about to see. King Bernard Zwirn waved his hands again and then brought them to rest at his side. The lights stopped flashing and the dust settled to the ground. In front of Benjamin stood three children. Chesterfield was a boy two years younger than Benjamin wearing a brown coat and jeans. Myrna was a girl his age wearing a flowery dress and a big white hat. And, Barnaby was a boy four years older than Benjamin wearing a baseball hat, a white shirt, and khaki shorts. They all examined their new selves and hugged King Bernard Zwirn.

“What just happened?” Benjamin asked with confusion.

“What?” Myrna asked with the same amount of confusion.

“Is he OK?” Chesterfield whispered to Barnaby.

“I don't know. He looks like he's in shock,” Barnaby said.

“You're people!” Benjamin said.

All three of them laughed at once.

“Of course we're people!” Myrna said with a smile.

“You're not animals?”

“Hey now! That's not nice,” Myrna said with a chuckle.

“Myrna, you were a caterpillar!” Benjamin defended.

“Was I?” she said with a laugh.

“Barnaby, you were a squirrel!”

“A squirrel?” Barnaby asked.

“And, Chesterfield you were a chipmunk!”

“Wow, really?” Chesterfield said.

“Aloysius transformed them into animals,” King Bernard Zwirn said.

“Why?” Benjamin asked.

“It was a part of his nightmare scheme. Even I am not sure of his intentions,” King Bernard Zwirn answered.

Noel Jaffin stumbled his way to King Bernard Zwirn's side. He was breathless as he tried to speak to the king.

“Where have you been?” Noel blurted.

“I was kidnapped, Noel,” King Bernard Zwirn said without looking at the sweaty guard. “But, now I'm back. And, I need to see Thalia Nachamie immediately.”

“Why of course,” Noel said. “I'll go find him. But, what are we going to do with Benjamin?”

King Bernard Zwirn stopped walking and turned his head slightly to the side.

“What do you mean what are we going to do with Benjamin?”

Benjamin saw that Noel was trying to keep the conversation between the king and himself. Noel moved closer to King Bernard Zwirn and stood on his toes to speak closer to the king's ear. King Bernard Zwirn didn't move so Noel tried to speak as quietly as possible, while watching Benjamin in the corner of his eye.

“He's a convicted villain,” Noel whispered.

“A convicted villain?” King Bernard Zwirn blurted.

“Sh! He's right there,” Noel whispered in a panic.

“What has he been convicted of?”

“Stealing.”

“What has he stolen?”

“He stole the missing piece of the dream machine.”

“So, the dream machine now works?”

“Well, it could. It doesn't, though. After Benjamin left, Thalia Nachamie told us that since it had not been used in such a long period of time, it was impossible to figure out where the missing piece actually went.”

“And Thalia Nachamie is the one who convicted Benjamin of stealing?”

“Yes, of course.”

“But, Benjamin didn't steal it.”

“Well,” Noel said slowly as he looked away shyly from Benjamin. “If you say so.”

“Noel, did anyone see Benjamin steal anything?”

“No.”

“And don't you think it is odd that Thalia Nachamie didn't fix the machine? He kicked Benjamin from the castle and then did nothing with the missing piece.”

“Well, that's not exactly true.”

“What isn't true?”

“He fled the other day. He said something about nightmares being destroyed,” Noel started to speak more slowly.

“They were,” King Bernard Zwirn said. “Thanks to Benjamin. I'm back in charge, Noel.”

Noel Jaffin nodded his head and saluted Benjamin. He then ran back to Cole and Joel to help them close the castle door. Miss Lindenmeyer and Rodney Cohen came running from the castle's plaza. They hugged Benjamin and Selma as tightly as they could when they arrived.

“We were so worried about you two,” Miss Lindenmeyer said. “I couldn't find you when Thalia Nachamie banished you from the castle. I looked everywhere.”

“It's OK,” Benjamin said. “It all worked out.”

“I'm so glad,” Miss Lindenmeyer said as she hugged him again. “Selma, I'm so glad you're well. I was so worried about you.”

“I'm OK,” Selma said.

“It's that imagination, kid,” Rodney said as he shuffled Benjamin's hair. “You have an amazing sense of creativity.”

“Yes,” King Bernard Zwirn said as he knelt down to the young boy. “You've done an amazing thing, Benjamin. No one else would have been able to do what you've done. You've given us the chance to dream again. You've stayed here a lot longer than you would've expected. I'm sorry about that. But, I think you've learned some things about yourself along the way. And now that everything is restored, I can finally send you home, Benjamin.”

Benjamin observed the smiling faces staring at him. He felt so comfortable and so warm amongst these people. He especially felt at ease with Selma, Myrna, Barnaby, and Chesterfield. They were his friends, he realized.

“But,” Benjamin started to say. “I don't really want to leave anymore.”

“You don't want to leave?” King Bernard Zwirn asked.

“Benjamin,” Miss Lindenmeyer said. “You need to go back and take care of your parents. If we are going to continue to make dreams, we need people to dream. You have to dream.”

Benjamin looked at the ground and wondered how he could go back home now. He had been through so much that had made him happier and braver than he was before. He was an entirely different person. He had friends. He was unafraid. He was comfortable. But, he thought of his parents. He knew he'd have to go home. His mother and father and Jupiter were probably worried. And, he missed them as well.

“Benjamin, it has been a pleasure,” Barnaby said as he extended his hand. Benjamin shook it and then Barnaby walked further into the castle.

“Thank you for everything,” Chesterfield said as he shook Benjamin's hand and then walked behind Barnaby.

“Benjamin,” Myrna said and then she began to cry. “Benjamin, this is not supposed to be the way it ends. You're supposed to be in love forever. You're supposed to be my friend forever. You're supposed to talk to me about your love forever!”

“Goodbye, Myrna,” Benjamin said. “I'm going to miss you.”

Myrna cried again and then walked next to Barnaby and Chesterfield. She was a beautiful butterfly, Benjamin thought.

“I didn't like you initially,” Selma said frankly.

“I knew that.”

“I really, really didn't like you.”

“Yes, I know.”

“But, you're not so bad.”

“Thanks,” Benjamin said.

Benjamin hugged her as hard as he could. He was hugging her so hard that he worried he had squeezed all of the air from her little body. He released her a little bit but when he felt Selma hug him back, he squeezed her again.

“I'll miss you,” she said quietly.

“I'll miss you, too,” he said.

Chapter 28
School

Mrs. Buckingham drove quickly through the neighborhood, careful not to run into any chipmunks and squirrels walking across the street. Her eyes were focused on the road like a racecar driver searching for a finish line. The news reporter on the radio was going on and on about the same story.

“In a report issued last night, people everywhere are dreaming again,” the reporter said. “The dreams are back and people are more confident than ever. For more on this story, we're turning to field reporter Rebecca—”

“I don't understand why every morning has to be like this,” she said to Benjamin who sat silently in the passenger seat. Benjamin bounced his head against his seat.

“I didn't hear my alarm,” Benjamin said quickly.

“You say that every morning,” Mrs. Buckingham said as she swerved around a group of chipmunks fighting over a nut. “And every morning I have to race through the neighborhood giving all the little critters along the way heart attacks.”

“I can be late.”

“You cannot be late.”

“Sure, Billy comes in late almost every day.”

“You aren't Billy. I don't even know who Billy is. Who's Billy?”

Benjamin heard a pigeon scream as it narrowly missed being struck by their little car.

“I'll make it up. No big deal.”

“No big deal? Benjamin, we still have to talk about where you were. This is a big deal.”

Mrs. Buckingham slammed on the brakes and stopped at a red light. Benjamin flew forward and nearly hit his head on the dashboard.

“It's not like we learn anything at school anyways,” Benjamin said.

Mrs. Buckingham stared at him with accusing eyes for about a minute. Benjamin didn't know why she didn't agree. He learned more in Castle Ehtahl than he had in all of his days in Mr. Marchetta's classroom.

“Benjamin, I love you and sometimes you say the most ridiculous things. Where were you this morning, by the way? You were outside for almost an hour,” his mother said as she accelerated the car faster and faster.

Benjamin smiled and wondered how much easier it would have been to get to Aloysius Trenhaile's castle if he had a car. He then wondered how much sooner he would have gotten home had he had roads to follow like the roads in his neighborhood. And then, he wondered how much further he could have traveled each day if there were lights scattered to illuminate his path. There were things everywhere along this race to school that made Benjamin wonder whether he could have endured less in his voyage.

And at that moment when a squirrel jumped over the car to avoid Mrs. Buckingham's dash to the finish line, he knew that it would all be different. If he had things that could have made his journey easier, he would not have evolved from the boy who was scared of everything into the boy who was scared of a lot less. He gained a lot more of everything.

“Bye, mom,” Benjamin said as he exited the car in front of the school.

The school looked the same. Nothing had changed. It had a boring exterior. The grass was barely alive. Kids trampled over each other to get through the door before the bell rang. It was exactly as it was. There was nothing different.

And, Benjamin was OK with that.

Because for the first time in his life, he knew that he was different.

And he was fine with being different.

He sat in Mr. Marchetta's classroom as the teacher lectured about forests.

“Forests have lots of animals in them. There are deer, birds, raccoons, and all sorts of animals. The only animal you don't find in a forest is people. We don't live in forests. We live in cities. Forests don't have toilets or grocery stores or movie theaters. You think it's funny but if you ever decide to spend some time in a forest, you'll learn it's not an enjoyable place. You're going to want to leave. Forests are the worst. They are scary and ruthless and dangerous. There's nothing fun about a forest. But if you find yourself in a forest, make sure to mark trees with a rock as you walk. That way, you'll know how to exit. You just search for the trees that you marked. And then, you'll be on your way out unless...”

Benjamin stared out the window and watched a large billowing cloud move slowly along the blue canvas of the sky toward the golden sun resting above the buildings across the street. He saw Mr. Marchetta's fancy car parked outside the school. It was orange and looked like it would move much faster than his mother's car. He didn't like it. Part of the reason he didn't like it was because Mr. Marchetta owned it. But, the other part that he didn't like was that it looked out of place. He wanted to see a tree or a bush or a river or a volcano instead. Or, he wanted to see Myrna. Or King Bernard Zwirn. Or Miss Lindenmeyer. Or Barnaby. Or Chesterfield. Or Selma.

But then, the landscape changed. Benjamin saw Snark appear from seemingly out of nowhere. Benjamin's heart raced and his eyes widened as he stretched his neck to see what Snark was going to do.

The ground vibrated with each step Snark took, pounding the pavement and rattling the windows. Snark paused and turned his gigantic head. Benjamin knew Snark was looking directly at him. Snark's mouth opened slightly to reveal his teeth and Benjamin saw him pant lightly like a dog when it's happy.

Benjamin grinned as well.

Snark lifted his left leg high into the air and then slammed it down into Mr. Marchetta's car. It made the same sound as when Benjamin stepped on an empty soda can. And since Benjamin liked that sound so much, it was impossible for him to not stop laughing.

Snark left as quickly as he arrived but not without waving to Benjamin.

“Benjamin, why aren't you paying attention?” Mr. Marchetta asked with a stern, angry look.

“Because he's lost,” Howard Horne snickered from the back. “Benjamin's lost in the forest.”

The class, Howard Horne's audience, giggled in response. Mr. Marchetta started to laugh as well. Benjamin looked around and saw that he was the joke of everyone around him.

But unlike weeks ago when Benjamin was bullied and felt like there was nothing outside of that classroom for him, he knew that there was a big world ready to welcome him. He didn't need bullies. He didn't need mean people. He knew where he belonged.

“I'm not lost,” Benjamin said. “I know exactly who I am.”